<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<aiml version="1.0">
  <meta content="SimpleAIMLGenerator" name="author"/>
  <meta content="en" name="language"/>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SITE MAP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I wrote a dynamic sitemap class a while ago, and blogged about it here: <a href="http://harriyott.com/2007/03/adding-dynamic-nodes-to-aspnet-site.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://harriyott.com/2007/03/adding-dynamic-nodes-to-aspnet-site.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SYNC THE SVN REVIS NUMBER WITH MY ASP.NET WEB SITE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>Looks like Jeff is using <A href="http://confluence.public.thoughtworks.org/display/CCNET/What+is+CruiseControl.NET" rel="nofollow">CruiseControl.NET</A> based on some leafing through the podcast transcripts. This seems to have automated deployment capabilities from source control to production. Might this be where the insertion is happening?</P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      POINT NUMBER PARS IS THERE A CATCH ALL ALGORITHM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think the best you can do in this case is to take their input and then show them what you think they meant. If they disagree, show them the format you're expecting and get them to enter it again.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VISUAL STUDIO AND SUBVERS HOW TO INTEGR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Working with remote site is not possible with Subversion as far as I know.<br/>Other nuances of web development with VisualSVN are described <a href="http://www.visualsvn.com/support/topic/00002/" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LIST FOR II 6 ASP.NET WINDOW AUTHENT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>It sounds like you've covered all the server-side bases--maybe it's a client issue? I assume your users have integrated authentication enabled in IE7? (Tools -&gt; Internet Options -&gt; Advanced -&gt; Security). This is enabled by default.</P><br/><P>Also, is your site correctly recognized by IE7 as being in the Local Intranet zone? The IE7 default is to allow automatic logon only in that zone, so users would be prompted if IE thinks your site is on the internet. I believe using a hostname with a dot in it causes IE to place the site into the Internet zone.</P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DECENT SIMPL GIS MAP COMPON FOR ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>Here's one ASP.NET map implementation (of many):</P><br/><P><A href="http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/sharpmap1.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/sharpmap1.aspx</A></P><br/><P>You can also go all-out and <A href="http://www.reimers.dk/" rel="nofollow">hook up to the Google Maps API via an ASP.NET control</A>.</P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VALU OF BUILT ENCOD VIEWSTAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Rex, I suspect a good place to start looking is solutions that <strong>compress the ViewState</strong> -- they're grabbing ViewState on the server before it's sent down to the client and gzipping it. That's exactly where you want to be.</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/CommentView,guid,febce059-7e7c-439e-af3d-c53d250b3e9c.aspx" rel="nofollow">Scott Hanselman on ViewState Compression</a> (2005)</li><br/><li><a href="http://www.bloggingdeveloper.com/post/How-To-Compress-ViewState-in-ASPNET-20-ViewState-Compression-with-SystemIOCompression.aspx" rel="nofollow">ViewState Compression with System.IO.Compression</a> (2007)</li><br/></ul>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USTOM CLIENT SID VALID
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try changing the argument names to "sender" and "args".  And, after you have it working, switch the call over to ScriptManager.RegisterClientScriptBlock, regardless of AJAX use.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BANDWITH THROTTL IN II 6 BY IP ADDRESS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>My first thought is this. I don't know if it would work but it would only take a few minutes to try.</p><br/><br/><p>Create <strong>two</strong> IIS web sites on the same server. The first site is bound to the public IP, but the second site is bound to the private IP. Both point to the same folder on the file system.</p><br/><br/><p>Your VPN users will be accessing via the private IP, so you can setup a "site-wide" rule on that site that will only affect VPN users. This should work for almost any IIS6 setting, including bandwidth throttling.</p><br/><br/><p>Worth a try, at least.</p><br/><br/><p>-- <br/>Edit: Tried this and it worked flawlessly.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BUILT IN USER PROFIL VS. OLD STILE USER CLASS TABL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Ive only built 2 applications that used the profile provider. Since then I have stayed away from using it. For both of the apps I used it to store information about the user such as their company name, address and phone number. </p><br/><br/><p>This worked fine until our client wanted to be able to find a user by one of these fields.<br/>Searching involved looping through <strong>every</strong> users profile and comparing the information to the search criteria. As the user base grew the search time became unacceptable to our client. The only solution was to create a table to store the users information. Search speed was increased immensely.</p><br/><br/><p>I would recommend storing this type of information in its own table.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PL QUOT HOW DO I DELIMIT A DATABOUND JAVASCRIPT STRING PARAMET IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I had recently similar problem and the only way to solve it was to use plain old HTML codes for single (<code>&amp;#39;</code>) and double quotes (<code>&amp;#34;</code>).  </p><br/><br/><p>Source code was total mess of course but it worked.</p><br/><br/><p>Try</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;a id="aShowHide" onclick='ToggleDisplay(&amp;#34;&lt;%# DataBinder.Eval(Container.DataItem, "JobCode") %&gt;&amp;#34;);'&gt;Show/Hide&lt;/a&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>or</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;a id="aShowHide" onclick='ToggleDisplay(&amp;#39;&lt;%# DataBinder.Eval(Container.DataItem, "JobCode") %&gt;&amp;#39;);'&gt;Show/Hide&lt;/a&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TOACT IN ASP.NET MVC WITHOUT LOSE REQUEST DATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The solution is to use the TempData property to store the desired Request components.</p><br/><br/><p>For instance:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public ActionResult Send()<br>{<br>    TempData["form"] = Request.Form;<br>    return this.RedirectToAction(a =&gt; a.Form());<br>}<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Then in your "Form" action you can go:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public ActionResult Form()<br>{<br>    /* Declare viewData etc. */<br><br>    if (TempData["form"] != null)<br>    {<br>        /* Cast TempData["form"] to <br>        System.Collections.Specialized.NameValueCollection <br>        and use it */<br>     }<br>     return View("Form", viewData);<br> }<br></code></pre>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MULTIPL DATACONTEXT CLASS EVER APPROPRI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I disagree with John's answer. The DataContext (or Linq to Entities ObjectContext) is more of a "unit of work" than a connection. It manages change tracking, etc. See this blog post for a description:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/dinesh.kulkarni/archive/2008/04/27/lifetime-of-a-linq-to-sql-datacontext.aspx" rel="nofollow">Lifetime of a LINQ to SQL DataContext</a></p><br/><br/><p>The four main points of this blog post are that DataContext:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>Is ideally suited<br/>for a "unit of work" approach </li><br/><li>Is also designed for<br/>"stateless" server operation</li><br/><li>Is not designed for<br/>    Long-lived usage</li><br/><li><br/>    Should be used very carefully after<br/>    any SumbitChanges() operation.</li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>Considering that, I don't think using more than one DataContext would do any harm- in fact, creating different DataContexts for different types of work would help make your LinqToSql impelmentation more usuable and organized. The only downside is you wouldn't be able to use sqlmetal to auto-generate your dmbl. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CRUD DATABAS SAMPL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I just created a scaffolder that will generate this code for you in a nice testable way - my stab at "how it should be done" in a CRUD fashion. Have a look:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://blog.wekeroad.com/blog/subsonic-mvc-scaffold-addin/" rel="nofollow">http://blog.wekeroad.com/blog/subsonic-mvc-scaffold-addin/</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DEFIN CUSTOM WEB.CONFIG SECTION WITH POTENTI CHILD ELEMENT AND ATTRIBUT FOR THE PROPERTI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><strong>Using attributes, child config sections and constraints</strong></p><br/><br/><p>There is also the possibility to use attributes which automatically takes care of the plumbing, as well as providing the ability to easily add constraints.</p><br/><br/><p>I here present an example from code I use myself in one of my sites. With a constraint I dictate the maximum amount of disk space any one user is allowed to use.</p><br/><br/><p>MailCenterConfiguration.cs:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>namespace Ani {<br><br>public sealed class MailCenterConfiguration : ConfigurationSection<br>{<br>    [ConfigurationProperty("userDiskSpace", IsRequired = true)]<br>    [IntegerValidator(MinValue = 0, MaxValue = 1000000)]<br>    public int UserDiskSpace<br>    {<br>        get { return (int)base["userDiskSpace"]; }<br>        set { base["userDiskSpace"] = value; }<br>    }<br>}<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>}</p><br/><br/><p>This is set up in web.config like so</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;configSections&gt;<br>    &lt;!-- Mailcenter configuration file --&gt;<br>    &lt;section name="mailCenter" type="Ani.MailCenterConfiguration" requirePermission="false"/&gt;<br>&lt;/configSections&gt;<br>...<br>&lt;mailCenter userDiskSpace="25000"&gt;<br>    &lt;mail<br>     host="my.hostname.com"<br>     port="366" /&gt;<br>&lt;/mailCenter&gt;<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p><strong>Child elements</strong></p><br/><br/><p>The child xml element <em>mail</em> is created created in the same .cs file as the one above. Here I've added constraints on the port. If the port is assigned a value not in this range the runtime will complain when the config is loaded.</p><br/><br/><p>MailCenterConfiguration.cs:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public sealed class MailCenterConfiguration : ConfigurationSection<br>{<br>    [ConfigurationProperty("mail", IsRequired=true)]<br>    public MailElement Mail<br>    {<br>        get { return (MailElement)base["mail"]; }<br>        set { base["mail"] = value; }<br>    }<br><br>    public class MailElement : ConfigurationElement<br>    {<br>        [ConfigurationProperty("host", IsRequired = true)]<br>        public string Host<br>        {<br>            get { return (string)base["host"]; }<br>            set { base["host"] = value; }<br>        }<br><br>        [ConfigurationProperty("port", IsRequired = true)]<br>        [IntegerValidator(MinValue = 0, MaxValue = 65535)]<br>        public int Port<br>        {<br>            get { return (int)base["port"]; }<br>            set { base["port"] = value; }<br>        }<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p><strong>Use</strong></p><br/><br/><p>To then use it practically in code, all you have to do is instantiate the MailCenterConfigurationObject, this will <strong>automatically</strong> read the relevant sections from web.config.</p><br/><br/><p>MailCenterConfiguration.cs</p><br/><br/><pre><code>private static MailCenterConfiguration instance = null;<br>    public static MailCenterConfiguration Instance<br>    {<br>        get<br>        {<br>            if (instance == null)<br>            {<br>                instance = (MailCenterConfiguration)WebConfigurationManager<br>                     .GetSection("mailCenter");<br>            }<br>            return instance;<br>        }<br>    }<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>AnotherFile.cs</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public void SendMail()<br>{<br>    MailCenterConfiguration conf = MailCenterConfiguration.Instance;<br>    SmtpClient smtpClient = new SmtpClient(conf.Mail.Host, conf.Mail.Port);<br>}<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p><strong>Check for validity</strong></p><br/><br/><p>I previously mentioned that the runtime will complain when the configuration is loaded and some data does not comply to the rules you have set up (e.g. in MailCenterConfiguration.cs). I tend to want to know these things as soon as possible when my site fires up. One way to solve this is load the configuration in <em>Global.asax.cx.Application_Start</em> , if the configuration is invalid you will be notified of this with the means of an exception. Your site won't start and instead you will be presented detailed exception information in the <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/images/yellow-screen-of-death-large.png" rel="nofollow">Yellow screen of death</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>Global.asax.cs</p><br/><br/><pre><code>protected void Application_ Start(object sender, EventArgs e)<br>{<br>    MailCenterConfiguration.Instance;<br>}<br></code></pre>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AJAX WEBCONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Check out the <a href="http://www.telerik.com/products/aspnet-ajax/controls/ajax/overview.aspx" rel="nofollow">RadAjax</a> control from Telerik - it allows you to avoid using UpdatePanels, and limit the amount of info passed back and forth between server and client by declaring direct relationships between calling controls, and controls that should be "Ajaxified" when the calling controls submit postbacks. </p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BACKGROUND OF A MASTERPAG FROM THE CODE BEHIND OF A CONTENT PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>What I would do for the particular case is:</p><br/><br/><p>i. Define the body as a server side control</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;body runat="server" id="masterpageBody"&gt;<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>ii. In your content aspx page, register the MasterPage with the register:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;% MasterPageFile="..." %&gt;<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>iii. In the Content Page, you can now simply use </p><br/><br/><pre><code>Master.FindControl("masterpageBody")<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>and have access to the control. Now, you can change whatever properties/style that you like!</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      URL REWRIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try the Managed Fusion Url Rewriter and Reverse Proxy:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://urlrewriter.codeplex.com" rel="nofollow">http://urlrewriter.codeplex.com</a></p><br/><br/><p>The rule for rewriting this would be:</p><br/><br/><pre><code># clean up old rules and forward to new URL<br/>RewriteRule ^/?user=(.*)  /users/$1 [NC,R=301]<br/><br/># rewrite the rule internally<br/>RewriteRule ^/users/(.*)  /?user=$1 [NC,L]<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DISPLAY SVN REVIS NUMBER
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Make sure that the file has svn:keywords "Rev Id" and then put $Rev$ somewhere in there.</p><br/><br/><p>See <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/163/how-do-i-sync-the-svn-revision-number-with-my-aspnet-web-site" rel="nofollow">this question and the answers to it</a>.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      STATE USE ASP.NET AJAX ICALLBACKEVENTHANDL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you're already shuffling the ViewState around anyway, you might as well use an UpdatePanel.  Its partial postbacks <strong>will</strong> update the page's ViewState automatically.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      2008 DEBUGG ALREADI ATTACH WORK AROUND
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I find that this happens if I'm debugging with Firefox as my browser. When I exit Firefox the VS2005/8 debug session doesn't terminate. I have not found a solution for this (yet).</p><br/><br/><p>If this is what's happening with you then a quicker solution than running iisreset is to hit Shift-F5 when in Visual Studio and this will terminate the current debug session. You can then hit F5 and this will start a new debug session.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EFFECT OPTION FOR EMBED VIDEO IN AN ASP.NET WEB SITE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Flash is certainly the most ubiquitous and portable solution.  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash#Market_share" rel="nofollow">98% of browsers</a> have Flash installed.  Other alternatives are <a href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/" rel="nofollow">Quicktime</a>, <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windowsmedia/default.mspx" rel="nofollow">Windows Media Player</a>, or even <a href="http://silverlight.net/" rel="nofollow">Silverlight</a> (Microsoft's Flash competitor, which can be used to embed several video formats).</p><br/><br/><p>I would recommend using Flash (and it's FLV video file format) for embedding your video unless you have very specific requirements as far as video quality or DRM.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CREAT MODEL CLASS OR JUST STICK WITH GENER DATABAS UTIL CLASS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This question is loaded, data driven design vs domain driven design. For any application that has a good amount of behavior, then domain driven design should be preferred. Reporting, or utility applications tend to work better (or are quicker to developer) with data driven design.</p><br/><br/><p>What you're asking is "should my company make a fundamental shift in how we design our code". As a domain-freak, my gut reaction is to scream <strong>yes</strong>. However, by the simple nature of your question, I'm not sure you fully understand the scope of the change you are proposing. I think you should talk more to your team about it. </p><br/><br/><p>Get some literature, such as <a href="http://domaindrivendesign.org/books/index.html#DDD_apply" rel="nofollow">Evan's DDD</a> book, or the <a href="http://codebetter.com/blogs/karlseguin/archive/2008/06/24/foundations-of-programming-ebook.aspx" rel="nofollow">free foundations ebook</a>, and then you'll be in a better position to judge which direction you should go.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET DYNAM DATA LINQ TO SQL HOW DO YOU HAVE TWO TABL FIELD HAVE A RELATIONSHIP TO THE SAME FOREIGN KEY
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The solution is to delete and re-add BOTH tables to the LINQ to SQL diagram, not just the one you have added the second field and keys to.</p><br/><br/><p>Alternatively, it appears you can make two associations using the LINQ to SQL interface - just don't try and bundle them into a single association.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ABSOLUT PATH BACK TO WEB REL PATH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Perhaps this might work:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>String RelativePath = AbsolutePath.Replace(Request.ServerVariables["APPL_PHYSICAL_PATH"], String.Empty);<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p><em>(i'm using c# but could be adapted to vb)</em></p><br/><br/><p><em>(@Tags2k: I have editted the above answer)</em></p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET FUNCTION FROM JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well, if you don't want to do it using AJAX or any other way and just want a normal ASP.NET postback to happen, here is how you do it (without using any other libraries):</p><br/><br/><p><em>It is a little tricky though... :)</em></p><br/><br/><p>i. In your code file (assuming you are using C# and .NET 2.0 or later) add the following Interface to your Page Class to make it look like</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public partial class Default : System.Web.UI.Page, IPostBackEventHandler{}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>ii. This should add (using Tab-Tab) this function to your code file:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public void RaisePostBackEvent(string eventArgument) { }<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>iii. In your onclick event in Javascript write the following code:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>var pageId = '&lt;%=  Page.ClientID %&gt;';<br/>__doPostBack(pageId, argumentString);<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This will call the 'RaisePostBackEvent' method in your code file with the 'eventArgument' as the 'argumentString' you passed from the Javascript. Now, you can call any other event you like.</p><br/><br/><p>P.S: That is 'underscore-underscore-doPostBack' ... And, there should be no space in that sequence... Somehow the WMD does not allow me to write to underscores followed by a character!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET CODE TO RENDER A FORM THAT DISPLAY A VIEW OF AN OBJECT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.codeplex.com/PropertyGrid" rel="nofollow" title="CodePlex">ASP.Net PropertyGrid</a></p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DUAL VS. QUADCOR ON A WEBSERV
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>For something like a webserver, dividing up the tasks of handling each connection is (relatively) easy.  I say it's safe to say that web servers is one of the most common (and ironed out) uses of parallel code.  And since you are able to split up much of the processing into multiple discrete threads, more cores actually does benefit you.  This is one of the big reasons why shared hosting is even possible.  If server software like IIS and Apache couldn't run requests in parallel it would mean that every page request would have to be dished out in a queue fashion...likely making load times unbearably slow.</p><br/><br/><p>This also why high end server Operating Systems like Windows 2008 Server Enterprise support something like 64 cores and 2TB of RAM.  These are applications that can actually take advantage of that many cores.</p><br/><br/><p>Also, since each request is likely has low CPU load, you can probably (for some applications) get away with more slower cores.  But obviously having each core faster can mean being able to get each task done quicker and, in theory, handle more tasks and more server requests.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BEST DETECT AN ASP.NET EXPIR SESSION
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If Session("whatever") IsNot Nothing Then</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DIFFER BETWEEN A DATAGRID AND A GRIDVIEW IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>DataGrid was an ASP.NET 1.1 control, still supported. GridView arrived in 2.0, made certain tasks simpler added different databinding features:</P><br/><P>This link has a comparison of DataGrid and GridView features -</P><br/><P><A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-gb/magazine/cc163933.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-gb/magazine/cc163933.aspx</A></P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DO UNIT TEST FOR ASP.NET 2.0 WEB PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Boy, that's a pretty general question.  I'll do my best, but be prepared to see me miss by a mile.</p><br/><br/><p>Assumptions</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>You are using ASP.NET, not plain ASP</li><br/><li>You don't really want to test your web pages, but the <strong>logic</strong> behind them. Unit testing the actual .ASPX pages is rather painful, but there are frameworks out there to do it.  <a href="http://nunitasp.sourceforge.net/" rel="nofollow">NUnitAsp</a> is one.</li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>The first thing to do is to organize (or plan) your code so that it can be tested.  The two most popular design patterns for this at the time seem to be MVP and MVC.  Both separate the <strong>logic</strong> of the application away from the <strong>view</strong> so that you can test the logic without the view (web pages) getting in your way.</p><br/><br/><p>Either MVP or MVC will be effective.  MVC has the advantage of having a Microsoft framework <a href="http://www.asp.net/mvc/" rel="nofollow">almost ready to go</a>.  </p><br/><br/><p>Once you've selected a framework pattern that encourages testability, you need to use a unit testing tool.  <a href="http://www.nunit.org/" rel="nofollow">NUnit</a> is a good starting point.  Visual Studio Professional has a <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb385902.aspx" rel="nofollow">testing suite built it</a>, but NUnit + <a href="http://www.testdriven.net/" rel="nofollow">TestDrive.NET</a> also works in the IDE.</p><br/><br/><p>That's sort of a shotgun blast of information.  I hope some if it hits.  The Pragmatic Bookshelf has a <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0974514020" rel="nofollow">good book covering the topic</a>.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TO ASP.NET 3.X
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>if I install 3.5 and have IIS setup to use 2.0. I will be able to use 3.5 features?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Yes, that is correct. You have IIS set to 2.0 for both 2.0 and 3.5 sites, as they both run on the same CLR. 3.5 uses a different compile method than 2.0. This is declared in the web.config for the site. See <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vijaysk/archive/2008/03/20/running-asp-net-3-5-on-iis.aspx" rel="nofollow">this post</a> for more details on this. But the setup in IIS for both 3.5 and 2.0 ASP.net sites is identical.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CONFIGURATIONMANAG TO LOAD CONFIG FROM AN ARBITRARI LOCAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>System.Configuration.ConfigurationFileMap fileMap = new ConfigurationFileMap(strConfigPath); //Path to your config file<br>System.Configuration.Configuration configuration = System.Configuration.ConfigurationManager.OpenMappedMachineConfiguration(fileMap);<br></code></pre>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AUTHENT USER NAME VS USER ID
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I would suggest using the username as the primary key in the table if the username is going to be unique, there are a few good reasons to do this:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>The primary key will be a clustered index and thus search for a users details via their username will be very quick.</li><br/><li>It will stop duplicate usernames from appearing</li><br/><li>You don't have to worry about using two different peices of information (username or guid)</li><br/><li>It will make writing code much easier because of not having to lookup two bits of information.</li><br/></ol>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET MENU CONTROL SIZE ( WITHOUT 3RD PARTI LIBRARI )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>Take a look at: <A href="http://www.asp.net/CSSAdapters/Menu.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.asp.net/CSSAdapters/Menu.aspx</A></P><br/><P>The default Menu control is rendering far too much HTML.</P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VERSION OF JOOMLA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefreakparade.com/2008/07/16/content-management-systems-cms-for-the-net-platform/" rel="nofollow">Here is a list</a> of a dozen or so CMS systems for ASP.NET, with a little commentary about most of them. They are not all open source, but a number of them are.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A CSS SWITCHER IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>In Asp.net 3.5, you should be able to set up the Link tag in the header as a server tag. Then in the codebehind you can set the href property for the link element, based on a cookie value, querystring, date, etc.</P><br/><P>In your aspx file:</P><PRE><CODE>&lt;head&gt;<br/>  &lt;link id="linkStyles" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" runat="server" /&gt;<br/>&lt;/head&gt;<br/></CODE></PRE><br/><P>And in the Code behind:</P><PRE><CODE>protected void Page_Load(object sender, EventArgs e) {<br/>  string stylesheetAddress = // logic to determine stylesheet<br/>  linkStyles.Href = stylesheetAddress;<br/>}<br/></CODE></PRE>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      POST AND THEN REDIRECT TO AN EXTERN URL FROM ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's I solved this problem today.  I started from <a href="http://www.c-sharpcorner.com/UploadFile/desaijm/ASP.NetPostURL11282005005516AM/ASP.NetPostURL.aspx" rel="nofollow">this article</a> on C# Corner, but found the example - while technically sound - a little incomplete.  Everything he said was right, but I needed to hit a few external sites to piece this together to work exactly as I wanted.</p><br/><br/><p>It didn't help that the user was not technically submitting a form at all; they were clicking a link to go to our support center, but to log them in an http post had to be made to the support center's site.</p><br/><br/><p>This solution involves using HttpContext.Current.Response.Write() to write the data for the form, then using a bit of Javascript on the </p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;body onload=""&gt; <br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>method to submit the form to the proper URL.</p><br/><br/><p>When the user clicks on the Support Center link, the following method is called to write the response and redirect the user:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public static void PassthroughAuthentication()<br>{<br><br>    System.Web.HttpContext.Current.Response.Write("&lt;body <br>    onload=document.forms[0].submit();window.location=\"Home.aspx\";&gt;");<br><br>    System.Web.HttpContext.Current.Response.Write("&lt;form name=\"Form\" <br>    target=_blank method=post <br>    action=\"https://external-url.com/security.asp\"&gt;");<br><br>    System.Web.HttpContext.Current.Response.Write(string.Format("&lt;input <br>       type=hidden name=\"cFName\" value=\"{0}\"&gt;", "Username"));<br><br>    System.Web.HttpContext.Current.Response.Write("&lt;/form&gt;");<br>    System.Web.HttpContext.Current.Response.Write("&lt;/body&gt;");<br>}<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>The key to this method is in that onload bit of Javascript, which , when the body of the page loads, submits the form and then redirects the user back to my own Home page.  The reason for that bit of hoodoo is that I'm launching the external site in a new window, but don't want the user to resubmit the hidden form if they refresh the page.  Plus that hidden form pushed the page down a few pixels which got on my nerves.</p><br/><br/><p>I'd be very interested in any cleaner ideas anyone has on this one.</p><br/><br/><p>Eric Sipple</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      N ONLIN ORDER SYSTEM FOR A RESTAURANT CAF
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<P>@<A href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5397/implementing-online-ordering-for-a-small-cafe#5416" rel="nofollow">Justin</A>,</P><br/><P>OP asked about an ecommerce solution, as far as I recall WordPress and Drupal aren't shopping cart apps. Perhaps that's the reason your reply was modded down.</P><br/><P>@nuggs -</P><br/><P>1/ If you're building this app as a commercial concern, i.e. it pays the rent then be realistic and choose a shopping cart app that best suits the requirements. Don't go spending time rolling your own, find a good one and integrate it. Don't get hung up on open source and the hope that one day you might contribute back, be realistic.</P><br/><P>2/ Don't roll your own, get one off the shelf, your time is money. For a couple of hundred pounds you can pick up a commercial product like Cactushop. If you go down the F/OSS route then make sure the project has a decent predigree and ongoing development. Don't think that because the cart app is F/OSS you'll be able to maintain it should the project go tits up, the codebase could be a complete nightmare or utilise techniques and technology beyond your skills and capabilities. Trust me, I've been there with an open source Perl app that looked like line noise.</P><br/><P>3/ PayPal and Google are great for getting started because they provide a foot in the door to being able to accept online payments with very little entry cost. However at higher transaction volumes they aren't the best value for money. As your volume of transactions increase you may want to look at a dedicated payment processor such as HSBC, ProtX, SecPay etc. You'll get better support (i.e. people who answer phones) and better tech support when things go wrong. In addition to whoever you choose as a payment processor, make sure you have a fall back prepared. It's not unknown for any of the well know processors to have bad hair days. Be prepared for these scenarios. Your secondary processor may cost more per transaction but at least you can still take payments.</P><br/><P>And finally, be fair to your customer, estimate the app properly. If he's not happy to pay for your time, software or services that will help you bring the app in on time then walk away. Don't make a rod for your own back by giving your time and effort away free.</P>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAVASCRIPT TO RUN WHEN MODALPOPUPEXTEND IS SHOWN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>hmmm... I'm <em>pretty sure</em> that there's a shown event for the MPE... this is off the top of my head, but I think you can add an event handler to the shown event on page_load</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function pageLoad()<br>{<br>    var popup = $find('ModalPopupClientID');<br>    popup.add_shown(SetFocus);<br>}<br><br>function SetFocus()<br>{<br>    $get('TriggerClientId').focus();<br>}<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>i'm not sure tho if this will help you with calling it from the server side tho</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET MVC I ENCOUNT AN INCORRECT TYPE ERROR WHEN RENDER A USER CONTROL WITH THE CORRECT TYPE OBJECT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>What @Graphain said is probably the reason you're seeing this error.</p><br/><br/><p>If you want to know <em>why</em>; it is because when you pass null as the controlData parameter when using RenderUserControl(), the framework will try to pass the view data from the current view context onto the user control instead (see UserControlExtensions.DoRendering method in System.Web.Mvc).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      INCLUD A FRAGMENT IDENTIFI WHEN USE ASP.NET MVC ACTIONLINK REDIRECTTOACT ETC.
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>We're looking at including support for this in our next release.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PREVIEW 4 NO ROUT IN THE ROUT TABL MATCH THE SUPPLI VALU
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>What type is selectedYear? A DateTime? If so then you might need to convert to a string.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REQUEST.PARAM AND REQUEST.FORM DIFFER
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Request.Form only includes variables posted through a form, while Request.Params includes both posted form variables and get variables specified as URL parameters.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FORM BUTTON IN FIREFOX
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Ends up this resolved my issue:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>     SearchButton.UseSubmitBehavior = False<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PUT MY LOG FILE FOR AN ASP.NET APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>App_Data folder on the root of the project. It isn't served to web requests; so other people can't snoop for it.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SERVIC RESULT PROXI CLASS AND TYPE CONVERS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You are on the right track.  To get the data from the proxy object back into one of your own objects, you have to do left-hand-right-hand code.  i.e. copy property values.  I'll bet you that there is already a generic method out there that uses reflection.</p><br/><br/><p>Some people will use something other than a web service (.net remoting) if they just want to get a business object across the wire.  Or they'll use binary serialization.  I'm guessing you are using the web service for a reason, so you'll have to do property copying.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MASTER PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'm pretty sure I've only used master pages in the context of ASP.NET MVC so I'm not sure if it differs from web forms but in my experience they are not only excellent but I couldn't imagine not using them.  Master pages are code inheritance to web pages.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VISIBL OF ASP.NET LABEL WITH JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you need to manipulate it on the client side, you can't use the Visible property on the server side.  Instead, set its CSS display style to "none".  For example:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;asp:Label runat="server" id="Label1" style="display: none;" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Then, you could make it visible on the client side with:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>document.getElementById('Label1').style.display = 'inherit';<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>You could make it hidden again with:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>document.getElementById('Label1').style.display = 'none';<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Keep in mind that there may be issues with the ClientID being more complex than "Label1" in practice.  You'll need to use the ClientID with getElementById, not the server side ID, if they differ.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A CUSTOM ID TO RENDER USE HTMLHELPER IN MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try this: </p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%= Html.CheckBox("myCheckbox", "Click here", "True", false, new {_id ="test" })%&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>For any keyword you can use an underscore before the name of the attribute.  Instead of class you use _class.  Since class is a keyword in C#, and also the name of the attribute in HTML.  Now, "id" isn't a keyword in C#, but perhaps it is in another .NET language that they want to support.  From what I can tell, it's not a keyword in VB.NET, F#, or Ruby so maybe it is a mistake that they force you to use an underscore with it.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ROUT ENGIN FOR FORM SUBMISS IN ASP.NET MVC PREVIEW 4
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Solution:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public ActionResult TestAction(string paramName)<br/>{<br/>    if (!String.IsNullOrEmpty(Request["paramName"]))<br/>    {<br/>        return RedirectToAction("TestAction", new { paramName = Request["paramName"]});<br/>    }<br/>    /* ... */<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NAMESPAC SYSTEM.QUERI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>I have version 2 selected in IIS and I</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Well, surely that's your problem?  Select 3.5.</p><br/><br/><p>Actually, here's the real info:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToSetAnIISApplicationOrAppPoolToUseASPNET35RatherThan20.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToSetAnIISApplicationOrAppPoolToUseASPNET35RatherThan20.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SOME WAY OF RECYCL A CRYSTAL REPORT DATASET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Hmm... as nice as it is to call the stored proc from the report and have it all contained in one location, however we found (like you) that you eventually hit a point where you can't get crystal to do what you want even tho the data is right there.</p><br/><br/><p>We ended up introducing a business layer which sits under the report and rather than "pulling" data from the report we "push" the datasets to it and bind the data to the report. The advantage is that you can manipulate the data in code in datasets or objects before it reaches the report and then simply bind the data to the report.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.codeguru.com/csharp/.net/net_general/toolsand3rdparty/article.php/c13253" rel="nofollow" title="Unison Home Page">This article</a> has a nice intro on how to setup pushing data to the reports. I understand that your time/business constraints may not allow you to do this, but if it's at all possible, I'd highly recommend it as it's meant we can remove all "coding" out of our reports and into managed code which is always a good thing.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REFER FOR SECUR CODE PRACTIC IN ASP.NET AND CLASSIC ASP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>For ASP.NET, don't forget Mr Security himself, <a href="http://www.leastprivilege.com/" rel="nofollow" title="Unison Home Page">Dominick Baier</a> and his excellent book <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0735623317" rel="nofollow">Developing More-Secure Microsoft® ASP.NET 2.0 Applications</a>. I'd also recommend Stefan Schackow's <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0764596985" rel="nofollow">Professional ASP.NET 2.0 Security, Membership, and Role Management</a>, worth it just for the first five chapters. And finally, the other Mr Security, Keith Brown's <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0321228359" rel="nofollow">The .NET Developer's Guide to Windows Security</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>All of the above books are more practical and take an 'applied' approach rather than being about generic best practice.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ENTITI INSID ASP.NET PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The ASCII table is set of characters, arguable the first standardized set of characters back in the days when you could only spare 1 byte per character.  <a href="http://asciitable.com/" rel="nofollow" title="Unison Home Page"><a href="http://asciitable.com/" rel="nofollow">http://asciitable.com/</a></a>  But I did some looking around at the extended character set of ASCII and it appears that the character you are referencing is an ASCII character.  So there really isn't a problem which ever way you choose to display your title.  </p><br/><br/><p>My revised answer is go for less expensive one according to space (i.e. the first one)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SITEMAP ON THE FLI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Usually you'll use an <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=HTTPHandler+ASP.NET&amp;spell=1" rel="nofollow">HTTP Handler</a> for this. Given a request for...</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p><a href="http://www.yoursite.com/sitemap.axd" rel="nofollow">http://www.yoursite.com/sitemap.axd</a></p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>...your handler will respond with a formatted XML sitemap. Whether that sitemap is generated on the fly, from a database, or some other method is up to the HTTP Handler implementation.</p><br/><br/><p>Here's roughly what it would look like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>void IHttpHandler.ProcessRequest(HttpContext context)<br/>{<br/>    //<br/>    // Important to return qualified XML (text/xml) for sitemaps<br/>    //<br/>    context.Response.ClearHeaders();<br/>    context.Response.ClearContent();<br/>    context.Response.ContentType = "text/xml";<br/>    //<br/>    // Create an XML writer<br/>    //<br/>    XmlTextWriter writer = new XmlTextWriter(context.Response.Output);<br/>    writer.WriteStartDocument();<br/>    writer.WriteStartElement("urlset", "http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9");<br/>    //<br/>    // Now add entries for individual pages..<br/>    //<br/>    writer.WriteStartElement("url");<br/>    writer.WriteElementString("loc", "http://www.codingthewheel.com");<br/>    // use W3 date format..<br/>    writer.WriteElementString("lastmod", postDate.ToString("yyyy-MM-dd"));<br/>    writer.WriteElementString("changefreq", "daily");<br/>    writer.WriteElementString("priority", "1.0");<br/>    writer.WriteEndElement();<br/>    //<br/>    // Close everything out and go home.<br/>    //<br/>    result.WriteEndElement();<br/>    result.WriteEndDocument();<br/>    writer.Flush();<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This code can be improved but that's the basic idea.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAVASCRIPT AFTER CONTROL S SELECT VALU HA BEEN SET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<pre><code>&lt;%@ Page Language="C#" %&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd"&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;script runat="server"&gt;<br/>    protected void indexChanged(object sender, EventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        Label1.Text = " I did something! ";<br/>    }<br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;<br/>&lt;head runat="server"&gt;<br/>    &lt;title&gt;Test Page&lt;/title&gt;<br/>&lt;/head&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/>    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/>        function firstChanged() {<br/>            if(document.getElementById("firstSelect").selectedIndex != 0)<br/>                document.getElementById("secondSelect").disabled = false;<br/>            else<br/>                document.getElementById("secondSelect").disabled = true;<br/>        }<br/>    &lt;/script&gt;<br/>    &lt;form id="form1" runat="server"&gt;<br/>    &lt;div&gt;<br/>        &lt;select id="firstSelect" onchange="firstChanged()"&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="0"&gt;&lt;/option&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="1"&gt;One&lt;/option&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="2"&gt;Two&lt;/option&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="3"&gt;Three&lt;/option&gt;<br/>        &lt;/select&gt;<br/>        &lt;select id="secondSelect" disabled="disabled"&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="1"&gt;One&lt;/option&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="2"&gt;Two&lt;/option&gt;<br/>            &lt;option value="3"&gt;Three&lt;/option&gt;<br/>        &lt;/select&gt;<br/>        &lt;asp:DropDownList ID="DropDownList1" AutoPostBack="true" OnSelectedIndexChanged="indexChanged" runat="server"&gt;<br/>            &lt;asp:ListItem Text="One" Value="1"&gt;&lt;/asp:ListItem&gt;<br/>            &lt;asp:ListItem Text="Two" Value="2"&gt;&lt;/asp:ListItem&gt;    <br/>        &lt;/asp:DropDownList&gt;<br/>        &lt;asp:Label ID="Label1" runat="server"&gt;&lt;/asp:Label&gt;<br/>    &lt;/div&gt;<br/>    &lt;/form&gt;<br/>    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/>        window.onload = function() {firstChanged();}<br/>    &lt;/script&gt;<br/>&lt;/body&gt;<br/>&lt;/html&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Edit: Replaced the whole code. This should work even in your user control.<br/>I believe that Register.ClientScriptBlock is not working because the code you write in that block is executed <em>before</em> window.onload is called. And, I assume (I am not sure of this point) that the DOM objects do not have their values set at that time. And, this is why you are getting selectedIndex as always 0.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DATAGRID IN FOOTER CALCUL AVG OR SUM FOR COLUMN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't know if either are necessarily better, but two <em>alternate</em> ways would be:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>Manually run through the table once you hit the footer and calculate from the on-screen text</li><br/><li>Manually retrieve the data and do the calculation separately from the bind</li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>Of course, #2 sort of offsets the advantages of data binding (assuming that's what you're doing).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      N ADDIT WINDOW.ONLOAD EVENT IN JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Most of the "solutions" suggested are Microsoft-specific, or require bloated libraries. Here's one good way. This works with W3C-compliant browsers and with Microsoft IE.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>if (window.addEventListener) // W3C standard<br/>{<br/>  window.addEventListener('load', myFunction, false); // NB **not** 'onload'<br/>} <br/>else if (window.attachEvent) // Microsoft<br/>{<br/>  window.attachEvent('onload', myFunction);<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RAISEPOSTBACKEV NOT FIRE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There's a lot of ways this can fall apart.  Are you adding the control to the page dynamically in code behind?  If so alot of times your UniqueID can be off - even though the client id's are equal.  Do you have a code sample that might demonstrate what you're doing?</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WITHOUT LOOK LIKE SPAM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>A good answer for this question would<br/>  be a real gold mine for a motivated<br/>  spammer :)</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Not really -- as you'll see in that <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/371/how-do-you-make-sure-email-you-send-programmatically-is-not-automatically-marke" rel="nofollow">other thread</a>, answers center on showing that you are the authorative sender of the email, and various aspects that are useless to spammers and useful to non-spammers who send a lot of email.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DATETIM WEEK INTO ROW
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is the method that does it:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public int GetWeekRows(int year, int month)<br/>{<br/>    DateTime firstDayOfMonth = new DateTime(year, month, 1);<br/>    DateTime lastDayOfMonth = new DateTime(year, month, 1).AddMonths(1).AddDays(-1);<br/>    System.Globalization.Calendar calendar = System.Threading.Thread.CurrentThread.CurrentCulture.Calendar;<br/>    int lastWeek = calendar.GetWeekOfYear(lastDayOfMonth, System.Globalization.CalendarWeekRule.FirstFourDayWeek, DayOfWeek.Monday);<br/>    int firstWeek = calendar.GetWeekOfYear(firstDayOfMonth, System.Globalization.CalendarWeekRule.FirstFourDayWeek, DayOfWeek.Monday);<br/>    return lastWeek - firstWeek + 1;<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>You can customize the calendar week rule by modifying the System.Globalization.CalendarWeekRule.FirstFourDayWeek part. I hope the code is self explanatory.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MOCK FRAMEWORK THAT CAN DO BOTH WEBFORM AND MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Rhino's latest release includes much of the sweet sweet 3.5 love that MoQ has.  I'm a fan of MoQ, so that's what I'm using.  But I also have Rhino, in case it does something that MoQ doesn't do.</p><br/><br/><p>TL;DR:  MoQ it baby.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USE NEW ASP.NET FEATUR IN THE .NET FRAMEWORK 3.5
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>For ASP.NET, you have a lot of improvements:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>split view (code and design)</li><br/><li>faster switching between code and design view</li><br/><li>embedded master pages (one master page in another)</li><br/><li>javascript debugging</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>Anyway most of the useful stuff are really in the meat of the language, and for .NET 3.5 the new language features for C# 3.0 will be (and yes, I find ALL of them useful)</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>anonymous objects</li><br/><li>automatic properties</li><br/><li>object initializers</li><br/><li>collection initializers (inline initialization for collections)</li><br/><li>implicit typing (var keyword)</li><br/><li>lambda expressions</li><br/><li>LINQ</li><br/><li>Extension methods</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>I might have forgotten a few, but I think this is about most of the new cool <em>and</em> useful stuff.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      POST FORM DATA IN THE ASP.NET MVC FRAMEWORK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You might want to take a look at ScottGu's latest post for ASP.Net prev 5. It walks through a validation sample that is very interesting:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/09/02/asp-net-mvc-preview-5-and-form-posting-scenarios.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/09/02/asp-net-mvc-preview-5-and-form-posting-scenarios.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUTPUTCACHEFILT IN THE MICROSOFT MVC PREVIEW 4 ACTUAL SAVE ON ACTION INVOC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Internally, the OutputCacheAttribute (aka output cache filter) uses the same internal mechanism as <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hdxfb6cy.aspx" rel="nofollow" title="excanvas">page output caching</a> (aka the @OutputCache directive).</p><br/><br/><p>Therefore, it's not any faster than page output caching. However, with MVC, you really can't use page output caching via the @OutputCache directive in MVC because we render the view (aka page) <strong>after</strong> the action runs. So you would gain very little benefit.</p><br/><br/><p>With the output cache filter, it does the correct thing and does not execute the action code if the result is in the output cache. Hope that helps. :)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET APPLIC TO IIS7 INTEGR MODE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is a process:<br/><a href="http://www.west-wind.com/WebLog/posts/6075.aspx" rel="nofollow" title="pgpool-II">Rick Strahl's blog</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      UNHANDL EXCEPT IN ASP.NET USERCONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>mmilic, following on from <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10793/catching-unhandled-exceptions-in-aspnet-usercontrols#10910" rel="nofollow">your response</a> to my <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10793/catching-unhandled-exceptions-in-aspnet-usercontrols#10815" rel="nofollow">previous idea</a>..</p><br/><br/><p>No additional logic required! That's the point, your doing nothing to the classes in question, just wrapping them in some instantiation bubble-wrap! :)</p><br/><br/><p>OK, I was going to just bullet point but I wanted to see this work for myself, so I cobbled together some <em>very</em> rough code but the concept is there and it seems to work.</p><br/><br/><p><strong>APOLOGIES FOR THE LONG POST</strong></p><br/><br/><h2>The SafeLoader</h2><br/><br/><p>This will basically be the "bubble" I mentioned.. It will get the controls HTML, catching any errors that occur during Rendering.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public class SafeLoader<br/>{<br/>    public static string LoadControl(Control ctl)<br/>    {<br/>        // In terms of what we could do here, its down<br/>        // to you, I will just return some basic HTML saying<br/>        // I screwed up.<br/>        try<br/>        {<br/>            // Get the Controls HTML (which may throw)<br/>            // And store it in our own writer away from the<br/>            // actual Live page.<br/>            StringWriter writer = new StringWriter();<br/>            HtmlTextWriter htmlWriter = new HtmlTextWriter(writer);<br/>            ctl.RenderControl(htmlWriter);<br/><br/>            return writer.GetStringBuilder().ToString();<br/>        }<br/>        catch (Exception)<br/>        {<br/>            string ctlType = ctl.GetType().Name;<br/>            return "&lt;span style=\"color: red; font-weight:bold; font-size: smaller;\"&gt;" + <br/>                "Rob + Controls = FAIL (" + <br/>                ctlType + " rendering failed) Sad face :(&lt;/span&gt;";<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><h2>And Some Controls..</h2><br/><br/><p>Ok I just mocked together two controls here, one will throw the other will render junk. Point here, I don't give a crap. These will be replaced with your custom controls..</p><br/><br/><h3>BadControl</h3><br/><br/><pre><code>public class BadControl : WebControl<br/>{<br/>    protected override void Render(HtmlTextWriter writer)<br/>    {<br/>        throw new ApplicationException("Rob can't program controls");<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><h3>GoodControl</h3><br/><br/><pre><code>public class GoodControl : WebControl<br/>{<br/>    protected override void Render(HtmlTextWriter writer)<br/>    {<br/>        writer.Write("&lt;b&gt;Holy crap this control works&lt;/b&gt;");<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><h2>The Page</h2><br/><br/><p>OK, so lets look at the "test" page.. Here I simply instantiate the controls, grab their html and output it, I will follow with thoughts on designer support etc..</p><br/><br/><h3>Page Code-Behind</h3><br/><br/><pre><code>    protected void Page_Load(object sender, EventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        // Create some controls (BadControl will throw)<br/>        string goodHtml = SafeLoader.LoadControl(new BadControl());<br/>        Response.Write(goodHtml);<br/><br/>        string badHtml = SafeLoader.LoadControl(new GoodControl());<br/>        Response.Write(badHtml);<br/>    }<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><h3>Thoughts</h3><br/><br/><p>OK, I know what you are thinking, "these controls are instantiated programatically, what about designer support? I spent freaking hours getting these controls nice for the designer, now you're messing with my mojo".</p><br/><br/><p>OK, so I havent really tested this yet (probably will do in a min!) but the idea here is to override the CreateChildControls method for the page, and take the instance of each control added on the form and run it through the SafeLoader. If the code passes, you can add it to the Controls collection as normal, if not, then you can create erroneous literals or something, up to you my friend.</p><br/><br/><h2>Finally..</h2><br/><br/><p>Again, sorry for the long post, but I wanted to get the code here so we can discuss this :)<br/>I hope this helps demonstrate my idea :)</p><br/><br/><h2>Update</h2><br/><br/><p>Tested by chucking a control in on the designer and overriding the CreateChildControls method with this, works fine, may need some clean up to make things better looking, but I'll leave that to you ;)</p><br/><br/><pre><code>protected override void CreateChildControls()<br/>{<br/>    // Pass each control through the Loader to check<br/>    // its not lame<br/>    foreach (Control ctl in Controls)<br/>    {<br/>        string s = SafeLoader.LoadControl(ctl);<br/>        // If its bad, smack it downnnn!<br/>        if (s == string.Empty)<br/>        {<br/>            ctl.Visible = false; // Prevent Rendering<br/>            string ctlType = ctl.GetType().Name;<br/>            Response.Write("&lt;b&gt;Problem Occurred Rendering " + <br/>                ctlType + " '" + ctl.ID + "'.&lt;/b&gt;");<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Enjoy!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SITE OR WEB PROJECT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There's a <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa730880(VS.80).aspx#wapp_topic5" rel="nofollow" title="pgpool-II">pretty good comparison chart on MSDN</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>Website projects are simple, in that all files added to the project folders are automatically compiled and included, which was supposedly added to make it more palatable to classic ASP and PHP developers. Once benefit is that it includes build providers, which allow for certain actions to be associated with a filetype - that's how the first release of SubSonic would rebuild the data access layer when you added a .abp file to the site.</p><br/><br/><p>Web Application Projects are a lot more flexible, though. For instance, all class libraries in a Website Project need to be in the App_Code folder, which is frustrating in a complex application. There are a lot of scenarios which just don't work for a Website Project.</p><br/><br/><p>You can convert from one to another, although if you're unsure I'd recommend just starting with a Web Application.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ACH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think the maxim "let the computer do it; it's smarter than you" applies here. Just like memory management and other complicated things, the computer is a lot more informed about what it's doing than your are; consequently, able to get more performance than you are.</p><br/><br/><p>Microsoft has had a team of engineers working on it and they've probably managed to squeeze much more performance out of the system than would be possible for you to. It's also likely that ASP.NET's built-in caching operates at a different level (which is inaccessible to your application), making it much faster.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USERCONTROL S AND DEFAULTEV
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is a <em>possible</em> answer, without testing (like martin did). </p><br/><br/><p>In reflector, you will see that the DefaultEventAttribute allows itself to be inherited.<br/>In reflector, you see that the UserControl class has it's default event set to the Load event.</p><br/><br/><p>So the possible reason is that even though you are decorating your user control with the default event of OKClick, VS might still be thinking that the default event is load, as it's being inherited from UserControl whose default event is Load.</p><br/><br/><p>Just a high level guess at what might be happening.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PROXI APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Why won't any old proxy software work for this?  Why does it need to be an ASP.NET application?  There are TONS of tools out there (both Windows and *nix) that will get the job done quite easily.  Check <a href="http://www.squid-cache.org/" rel="nofollow" title="excanvas">Squid</a> or <a href="http://www.grok.co.uk/netproxy/" rel="nofollow">NetProxy</a> for starters.</p><br/><br/><p>If you need to integrate with IIS, <a href="http://www.iisproxy.net/" rel="nofollow">IISProxy</a> looks like it would do the trick too.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AN ASP.NET WEB SITE OR APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<ol><br/><li><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/05/12/visual-studio-2008-and-net-framework-3-5-service-pack-1-beta.aspx" rel="nofollow">Script Combining in .net 3.5 SP1</a></li><br/><li><a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html" rel="nofollow">Best Practices for fast websites</a></li><br/><li>HTTP Compression (gzip)</li><br/><li>Compress JS / CSS (different than http compression, minify javascript)<br/><ol><br/><li><a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/compressor/" rel="nofollow">YUI Compressor</a></li><br/><li><a href="http://www.codeplex.com/YUICompressor" rel="nofollow">.NET YUI Compressor</a></li><br/></ol></li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>My best advice is to check out the <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/YUI" rel="nofollow">YUI content</a>. They have some great articles that talk about things like <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/sprites/" rel="nofollow">CSS sprites</a> and have some <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/imageloader/" rel="nofollow">nice javascript libraries to help reduce the number of requests</a> the browser is making.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PAGE CACH IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've found the answer I was looking for:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>HttpResponse.RemoveOutputCacheItem("/caching/CacheForever.aspx");<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IMPERSON AN ACTIV DIRECTORI USER IN POWERSHEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Exchange 2007 doesn't allow you to impersonate a user for security reasons. This means that it is impossible (at the moment) to create mailboxes by impersonating a user. In order to get around this problem, I created a web service which runs under AD user which has permissions to create email acounts, etc. You can then access this webservice to get access to powershell. Please remember to add the necessary security because this could potentially be a huge security hole.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RSS FEED IN ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is what I recommend:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>Create a class called RssResult that<br/>inherits off the abstract base class<br/>ActionResult.</li><br/><li>Override the ExecuteResult method.</li><br/><li>ExecuteResult has the ControllerContext passed to it by the caller and with this you can get the data and content type.</li><br/><li><p>Once you change the content type to rss, you will want to serialize the data to RSS (using your own code or another library) and write to the response.</p></li><br/><li><p>Create an action on a controller that you want to return rss and set the return type as RssResult.  Grab the data from your model based on what you want to return.</p></li><br/><li><p>Then any request to this action will receive rss of whatever data you choose.</p></li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>That is probably the quickest and reusable way of returning rss has a response to a request in ASP.NET MVC.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ROUT MAP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>I just answered my own question. I had<br/>  the routes backwards (Default was<br/>  above page).</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Yeah, you have to put all custom routes above the Default route.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>So this brings up the next question...<br/>  how does the "Default" route match (I<br/>  assume they use regular expressions<br/>  here) the "Page" route?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>The Default route matches based on what we call Convention over Configuration.  Scott Guthrie explains it well in his first blog post on ASP.NET MVC.  I recommend that you read through it and also his other posts.  Keep in mind that these were posted based on the first CTP and the framework has changed.  You can also find web cast on ASP.NET MVC on the asp.net site by Scott Hanselman.</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/11/13/asp-net-mvc-framework-part-1.aspx" rel="nofollow" title="excanvas"><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/11/13/asp-net-mvc-framework-part-1.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/11/13/asp-net-mvc-framework-part-1.aspx</a></a></li><br/><li><a href="http://www.asp.net/MVC/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.asp.net/MVC/" rel="nofollow">http://www.asp.net/MVC/</a></a></li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LOG ERROR ( EXCEPT ) IN YOUR ASP.NET APP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I use <a href="http://code.google.com/p/elmah/" rel="nofollow" title="excanvas">elmah</a>.  It has some really nice features and here is a <a href="http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/ELMAHDemo.aspx" rel="nofollow">CodeProject</a> article on it.  I think the StackOverflow team uses elmah also!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DATABIND AN ASP.NET AJAX TOOLKIT MASKEDEDITEXTEND
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>We found out this morning why our code was mishandling the extender.  Since the db was handling the date as a date/time it was returning the date in this format 99/99/9999 99:99:99 but we had the extender mask looking for this format 99/99/9999 99:99 </p><br/><br/><pre><code>Mask="99/99/9999 99:99:99"</code></pre> <br/><br/><p>the above code fixed the problem.<br/>thanks to everyone for their help.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ONSID N2 CM BUT WORRI ABOUT PERFORMANCE. IS THI JUSTIFI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Maybe try this question at <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/n2/Thread/List.aspx" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.codeplex.com/n2/Thread/List.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.codeplex.com/n2/Thread/List.aspx</a></a></p><br/><br/><p>They might be able to tell you about performance limitations or bottlenecks.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NODE FROM A SITEMAPNODECOLLECT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Your shouldn't need CType</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Dim children = _<br/>    From n In SiteMap.CurrentNode.ChildNodes.Cast(Of SiteMapNode)() _<br/>    Where n.Url &lt;&gt; "/Registration.aspx" _<br/>    Select n<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VIRTUALPATHPROVID AND PRE COMPIL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Unfortunately that is not officially supported. See the following <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.hosting.virtualpathprovider.aspx" rel="nofollow">MSDN article</a>.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>If a Web site is precompiled for deployment, content provided by a VirtualPathProvider instance is not compiled, and no VirtualPathProvider instances are used by the precompiled site. </p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>The site you referred to is an unofficial workaround. I don't think it's been fixed in .NET 3.5 SP1</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FOSS ASP.NET SESSION REPLIC SOLUT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>BTW Windows Server AppFabric is out of beta. That's what i mentioned in my previous post.</p><br/><br/><p>here is the link on general availability;- <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/appfabric/archive/2010/06/07/windows-server-appfabric-now-generally-available.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://blogs.technet.com/b/appfabric/archive/2010/06/07/windows-server-appfabric-now-generally-available.aspx</a> </p><br/><br/><p>which specific features do you think one can get on NCache and not on AppFabric?</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET APPLIC THROW THREADABORTEXCEPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This is probably coming from a Response.Redirect call.  Check this link for an explanation:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://dotnet.org.za/armand/archive/2004/11/16/7088.aspx" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://dotnet.org.za/armand/archive/2004/11/16/7088.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://dotnet.org.za/armand/archive/2004/11/16/7088.aspx</a></a></p><br/><br/><p>(In most cases, calling Response.Redirect(url, false) fixes the problem)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WA THE PROFIL PROVID NOT BUILT INTO WEB APP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The profile provider uses the ASP.NET Build Provider system, which doesn't work with Web Application Projects.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>Adding a customized BuildProvider<br/>  class to the Web.config file works in<br/>  an ASP.NET Web site but does not work<br/>  in an ASP.NET Web application project.<br/>  In a Web application project, the code<br/>  that is generated by the BuildProvider<br/>  class cannot be included in the<br/>  application.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>source: <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.compilation.buildprovider.aspx" rel="nofollow">MSDN Build Provider documentation</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CREAT A LISTVIEW WITH DYNAM GROUPITEMCOUNT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I haven't used GroupItemCount, but I have taken this example written up by <a href="http://mattberseth.com/" rel="nofollow">Matt Berseth</a> titled <a href="http://mattberseth.com/blog/2008/01/building_a_grouping_grid_with.html" rel="nofollow">Building a Grouping Grid with the ASP.NET 3.5 LinqDataSource and ListView Controls</a> and have grouped items by a key just like you want.</p><br/><br/><p>It involves using an outer and inner ListView control.  Works great, give it a try.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DATA FROM AN ASPX PAGE TO AN ASCX MODAL POPUP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>All a usercontrol(.ascx) file is is a set of controls that you have grouped together to provide some reusable functionality.  The controls defined in it are still added to the page's control collection (.aspx) durring the page lifecylce.  The ModalPopupExtender uses javascript and dhtml to show and hide the controls in the usercontrol client-side.  What you are seeing is that the click event is being handled client-side by the ModalPoupExtender and it is canceling the post-back to the server.  This is the default behavior by design.  You certainly can access the page's control collection from the code-behind of your usercontrol though because it is all part of the same control tree.  Just use the FindControl(xxx) method of any control to search for the child of it you need.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RONPYTHON AND ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The current version of ASP.NET integration for IronPython is not very up-to-date and is more of a "proof-of-concept." I don't think I'd build a production website based on it.</p><br/><br/><p><strong>Edit:</strong>: I have a very high level of expectation for how things like this should work, and might setting the bar a little high.  Maybe you should take what's in "ASP.NET Futures", write a test application for it and see how it works for you.  If you're successful, I'd like to hear about it.  Otherwise, I think there should be a newer CTP of this in the next six months.</p><br/><br/><p>(I'm a developer on IronPython and IronRuby.)</p><br/><br/><p><strong>Edit 2:</strong> Since I originally posted this, a <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/aspnet/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Dynamic%20Language%20Support" rel="nofollow">newer version</a> has been released.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CUSTOM EDIT RECORD IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can REALLY cheat nowadays and take a peek at the new Dynamic Data that comes with .NET 3.5 SP1. Scott Guthrie has a blog entry demoing on how quick and easy it'll flow for you here:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/12/14/new-asp-net-dynamic-data-support.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/12/14/new-asp-net-dynamic-data-support.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>Without getting THAT cutting edge, I'd use the XSD generator to generate a strongly typed DataSet that coincides with the table in question. This will also generate the TableAdapter you can use to do all your CRUD statements. </p><br/><br/><p>From there, bind it to a DataGrid and leverage all the standard templates/events involved with that, such as EditIndex, SelectedIndex, RowEditing, RowUpdated, etc.</p><br/><br/><p>I've been doing this since the early 1.0 days of .NET and this kind of functionality has only gotten more and more streamlined with every update of the Framework.</p><br/><br/><p>EDIT: I want to give a quick nod to the Matt Berseth blog as well. I've been following a lot of his stuff for a while now and it is great!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SUPPORT ASP.NET 1.1
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Increasingly I think not.</p><br/><br/><p>The kind of large rigid organisation currently still clinging to 1.1 (probably because they're only just upgraded to it) is also the kind that's highly unlikely to look at open source solutions.</p><br/><br/><p>If I were starting a new ASP.Net project right now I'd stick with .Net 3.5 and probably the new MVC previews.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DEVIC IS DETECT AS NON MOBIL DEVIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Some are not recognized, because the UserAgent has been messed with or a new browser is being used. Such as Opera Mobile 9.5.  To fix this you need to create a Browser (*.browser) file specifically for defining this.  I had to do it for the new Mozilla based UserAgent that is being sent from Google.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MANIPUL IN ASP.NET C # WITHOUT SYSTEM.DRAWING GDI +
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't know of any fully-managed 2D drawing libraries that are either free or open-source  (there appears to be a few commercially available, but OSS is the way to go). However, you might look into <a href="http://www.go-mono.com/docs/index.aspx?tlink=0@N:Cairo" rel="nofollow">the Mono bindings to Cairo</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>Cairo is a platform independent 2D drawing API. You can find more information about it at <a href="http://cairographics.org" rel="nofollow">the Cairo homepage</a>. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cairo_(graphics)" rel="nofollow">Cairo Wikipedia page</a> also has some good info.</p><br/><br/><p>Cairo is also used fairly widely in the Open Source world, which to me says something about its robustness. Mozilla, Webkit, and Mono all use it, among others. Ironically, Mono actually uses it to back their System.Drawing implementation... go figure.</p><br/><br/><p>There might also be a way to use Mono's System.Drawing implementation as a drop-in replacement for the Microsoft implementation, though I'm not sure how or if that would even work. I would probably start by replacing the System.Drawing.dll reference with Mono's version, and then try to deal with any errors.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      3.5 SP1 AND ASPNET CLI CRYSTAL REPORT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>No it is a side effect of Crystal Reports.  If you don't need it, remove it from your computer it is nothing but a headache.  It is safe to delete the aspnet_client folder.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DRAG DROP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The Mootools sortables plugin does just that, and best of all, it's free ;)</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://demos.mootools.net/Sortables" rel="nofollow">http://demos.mootools.net/Sortables</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MIGRAT FROM ASP.NET WEBFORM TO ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>Any pointers, tips, tricks, or<br/>  gotchas to be aware of?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Well, I think you're probably a little ways away from thinking about tricks &amp; gotchas :) As I'm sure you're aware, ASP.NET MVC is not some new version of ASP.NET, but a totally different paradigm from ASP.NET, you won't be migrating, you'll be initiating a brand new development effort to replace an existing system. So maybe you can get a leg up on determining requirements for the app, but the rest will probably re-built from scratch.</p><br/><br/><p>Based on the (very common) problems you described in your existing code base you should consider taking this opportunity to learn some of the current best practices in designing loosely coupled systems. This is easy to do because modern "best practices" are easy to understand and easy to practice, and there is enormous community support, and high quality, open source tooling to help in the process.</p><br/><br/><p>We are moving an ASP/ASP.NET application to ASP.NET MVC at this time as well, and this is the conclusion my preparatory research has led me to, anyway.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.thefreakparade.com/2008/07/to-aspnetmvc-or-not-to-mvc-or-aspnet-mvc-hyperlink-acupuncture/" rel="nofollow" title="InfoQ">Here is a post to links on using ASP.NET MVC</a>, but I would start by <a href="http://www.thefreakparade.com/2008/07/so-you-want-to-learn-nhibernate-part-12-prerequisites-or-nhibernate-marijuananet/" rel="nofollow" title="JavaLobby">reading this post</a>. The post is about NHibernate (an ORM tool) on its surface but the discussion and the links are about getting the foundations right and is the result of preparing to port an ASP.NET site to MVC. Some of the reference architectures linked to in that post are based on ASP.NET MVC. <a href="http://www.thefreakparade.com/2008/07/so-you-want-to-learn-nhibernate-part-1-of-1-the-links/" rel="nofollow">Here is another post about NHibernate</a>, but in the "Best Practices &amp; Reference Applications" section most if not all of the reference applications listed are ASP.NET MVC applications also. Reference architectures can be extremely useful for quickly getting a feeling for how an optimal, maintainable ASP.NET MVC site might be designed.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SCHEDUL A BATCH PROCESS IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>Is there any known drawbacks with the<br/>  solution?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p><a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2008/07/easy-background-tasks-in-aspnet/" rel="nofollow" title="InfoQ">Here is the blog post</a> in which Jeff Atwood discusses this approach. As with most of Jeff's post, the meat is in the comments where the pros and cons have been discussed in extreme detail by a large number of opinionated folks, so that is an ideal place to have that particular part of your question answered.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ORGAN DATASET QUERI TO IMPROV PERFORM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>Should I just do it when I'm going to use it?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>I would recommend that you only retrieve the data when you are going to use it. If you are not going to need it, there is no reason to waste resources by retrieving it in Page_Load. If you are going to need it multiple times throughout the page load, consider saving the query results to a private variable or collection so that the same data can be reused multiple times throughout the page load.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>Am I opening a new connection when I create a new instance?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Asp.net handles <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/8xx3tyca(vs.71).aspx" rel="nofollow">connection pooling</a>, and opens and closes connections in an efficient way. You shouldn't have to worry about this.</p><br/><br/><p>One other thing to consider from a performance perspective is to avoid using Datasets and TableAdapters. In many cases, they add <a href="http://aspnet.4guysfromrolla.com/articles/050405-1.aspx" rel="nofollow">extra overhead</a> into data retrieval that does not exist when using Linq to Sql, Stored Procedures or DataReaders.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MODEL VIEW CONTROL ( MVC ) WHERE DO I START FROM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<ul><br/><li><a href="http://haacked.com/" rel="nofollow">Phil Haack's Blog</a> - PM on the MVC project at msft</li><br/><li><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/stephenwalther/" rel="nofollow">Stephen Walther's Blog</a> - he has<br/>a series dedicated to ASP.NET MVC</li><br/><li><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/" rel="nofollow">Scott Guthrie's Blog</a> - Scott Guuuuu</li><br/><li><a href="http://blog.wekeroad.com/" rel="nofollow">Rob Conery's Blog</a> - he has a<br/>whole series of screencasts about<br/>building an ecommerce site with<br/>ASP.NET MVC</li><br/><li><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/" rel="nofollow">Scott Hanselman's Blog</a> - the<br/>great scottha</li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      URL REWRIT DO YOU USE FOR ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>+1 UrlRewritingNET.URLRewrite -- used in several hundred services/portals/sites on a single box without issue for years! (@Jason -- that is the one you're talking about, right?)</p><br/><br/><p>and I've also used the URLRewriter.NET on a personal site, and found it, ah, interesting. @travis, you're right about the changed syntax, but once you get used to it, it's good.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GENER ASP.NET MVC ROUT FROM A SITEMAP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Zack, if I understand right you want unlimited depth of the subcategories. No biggie, since MVC Preview 3 (I think 3 or 4) this has been solved.</p><br/><br/><p>Just define a route like</p><br/><br/><p>"{controller}/{action}/{*categoryPath}"</p><br/><br/><p>for an url such as :</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://example.com/shop/products/household/kitchen/cookware/cooksets/nonstick" rel="nofollow">http://example.com/shop/products/household/kitchen/cookware/cooksets/nonstick</a></p><br/><br/><p>you should have a ShopController with a Products action :</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public class ShopController : Controller<br/>{<br/>...<br/>    public ActionResult Products(string categoryPath)<br/>    {<br/>        // the categoryPath value would be<br/>        // "household/kitchen/cookware/cooksets/nonstick". Process it (for ex. split it)<br/>        // and then decide what you do..<br/>        return View();<br/>    }<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ULTRAWEBGRID HOW TO USE A DROP DOWN LIST IN A COLUMN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've found what was wrong.</p><br/><br/><p>The column must allow updates.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>uwgMyGrid.Columns.FromKey("colTest").AllowUpdate = AllowUpdate.Yes;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      N ASP.NET MASTER PAGE AT RUNTIM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've done this once before, I did exactly what you described (Made all pages inherit from a custom page with an OnPreInit event). Also I had a custom Application_PreRequestHandlerExecute in my Global.asax.cs for setting Page.StyleSheetTheme for doing image/css changes that didn't require a different Master Page.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RID OF HOME IN ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Just change "Home" to an empty string.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>routes.MapRoute(<br/>    "Home",<br/>    "",<br/>    new { action = Index, controller = Home }<br/>);<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TRACK DOWN PERFORM PROBLEM WITH PAGE RENDER
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Download ANTS PROFILER, this will give you a perfect overview of the lines causing the slowdown.</p><br/><br/><p>Also when it's about rendering make sure you don't use to much string concats (like string += "value") but use StringBuilders to improve performance.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AUTOM REPETIT TASK POST BUILD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's an example of a Web Deployment Project scripting this sort of task in the .wdproj file:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>  &lt;Target Name="AfterBuild"&gt;<br/>    &lt;!-- ============================ Script Compression============================ --&gt;<br/>    &lt;MakeDir Directories="$(OutputPath)\compressed" /&gt;<br/>    &lt;Exec Command="java -jar c:\yuicompressor-2.2.5\build\yuicompressor-2.2.5.jar --charset UTF-8 styles.css -o compressed/styles.css" WorkingDirectory="$(OutputPath)" /&gt;<br/>    &lt;Exec Command="move /Y .\compressed\* .\" WorkingDirectory="$(OutputPath)" /&gt;<br/>    &lt;RemoveDir Directories="$(OutputPath)\sql" /&gt;<br/>    &lt;Exec Command="c:\7zip-4.4.2\7za.exe a $(ZipName).zip $(OutputPath)\*" /&gt;<br/>  &lt;/Target&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This would allow you to delete a folder.</p><br/><br/><p>(I suspect that if you wanted to not have the folder copy over <em>at all</em>, the solution file would be the place to specify that, though I haven't had to use that.)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MINIM JAVASCRIPT HTTP CALL FROM AJAXCONTROLTOOLKIT CONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I always preferred to write my Ajax calls in javascript using JQuery or Prototype. ASP.NET Ajax Toolkit does make things easier, but it never seems to do so elegantly.</p><br/><br/><p>I personally would make a new Calendar Controller. This way you can control the AJAX (using JQuery/Prototype) calls that are being made.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LOCATIONPROVID
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Why don't you create rights &amp; profiles to manage wich pages a user can see?<br/>I usually create a user class which implements the IPrincipal security interface. On every request to your application, you check the rights of a particular user and output the SiteMap's nodes allowed for this user.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FILE PATH TO A URL IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Afaik, there's no method to do what you want directly. I'd store the photosLocation as a path relative to the application; f.ex. "~/Images/". This way, you could use MapPath to get the physical location, and ResolveUrl to get the url (with a bit of help from System.IO.Path):</p><br/><br/><pre><code>string photosLocationPath = HttpContext.Current.Server.MapPath(photosLocation);<br/><br/>if (Directory.Exists(photosLocationPath))<br/>{<br/>    string[] files = Directory.GetFiles(photosLocationPath, "*.jpg");<br/>    if (files.Length &gt; 0)<br/>    {<br/>        string filenameRelative = photosLocation + <br/>                                  Path.GetFilename(files[0])     <br/><br/>        return HttpContext.Current.Request.ResolveUrl(filenameRelative);<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      APP DASHBOARD TYPE GUI INTERFAC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I have been looking at this kind of functionality myself recently and have decided on using jQuery with the help of <a href="http://ui.jquery.com/" rel="nofollow">jQuery UI</a>. I came across a large amount of information that also suggested <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/" rel="nofollow">Yahoo UI</a> (YUI), I had already started learning <a href="http://jQuery.com" rel="nofollow">jQuery</a> due to the AJAX support that it offers, so I stuck with it.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://ui.jquery.com/" rel="nofollow">jQuery UI Site</a><br/><br/><a href="http://docs.jquery.com/UI" rel="nofollow">jQuery UI Documentation</a><br/><br/><a href="http://ui.jquery.com/repository/real-world/layout/" rel="nofollow">Example of a drag and drop screen layout with jQuery UI</a><br/><br/><a href="http://www.learningjquery.com/2008/07/introduction-to-jquery-ui#" rel="nofollow">Introduction to jQuery UI</a></p><br/><br/><p>If you decide to use the YUI javascript library, here is a link to a vast amount of videos to help get you started.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/theater/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/theater/" rel="nofollow">http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/theater/</a></a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PAGE FLOW IN MVC ( PARTICULARLI ASP.NET )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Investigate the post-redirect-get pattern.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/mhawley/archive/tags/MVC/default.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/mhawley/archive/tags/MVC/default.aspx</a><br /><br/><a href="http://devlicio.us/blogs/tim_barcz/archive/2008/08/22/prg-pattern-in-the-asp-net-mvc-framework.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://devlicio.us/blogs/tim_barcz/archive/2008/08/22/prg-pattern-in-the-asp-net-mvc-framework.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>Use that along with a robust domain model (for tracking steps or form completion state or whatever you call it) and you're golden.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ID AUTHENT IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>See <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/TheWeeklySourceCode25OpenIDEdition.aspx" rel="nofollow">Scott Hanselman's post on using DotNetOpenID</a> in ASP.NET. <a href="http://blog.nerdbank.net/" rel="nofollow">Andrew Arnott's blog</a> is full of samples on using DotNetOpenID with ASP.NET, including ASP.NET MVC.</p><br/><br/><p>I recently hooked up DotNetOpenID for the Subtext 2.0 release. It went really smoothly - the code samples included with the DotNetOpenID download are pretty helpful. The one thing I'd recommend is that you just use the library and avoid the ASP.NET control. It uses table based layout (hardcoded) and is pretty difficult to restyle.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IMPLEMENT FIELD VALID USE ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Take a look at the <a href="http://bassistance.de/jquery-plugins/jquery-plugin-validation/" rel="nofollow">JQuery Validation plugin</a> this plugin is amazing,it's clean to implement and has all the features you could ever need, including remote validation via AJAX.</p><br/><br/><p>Also a sample MVC controller method can be found <a href="http://httpcode.com/blogs/PermaLink,guid,f8970f20-90d1-4af6-b2da-0285f1963b14.aspx" rel="nofollow">here</a> which basically uses the JsonResult action type like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public JsonResult CheckUserName(string username)<br/>{<br/>    return Json(CheckValidUsername(username));<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTMLSPECIALCHARACT EQUIVAL IN .NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try this.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>var encodedHtml = HttpContext.Current.Server.HtmlEncode(...);<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GZIP AND CACH STATIC IMAG IN ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Best solution is to let IIS do it.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/technet/prodtechnol/WindowsServer2003/Library/IIS/502ef631-3695-4616-b268-cbe7cf1351ce.mspx?mfr=true" rel="nofollow">IIS6 Compression</a> - most likely you need to <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/technet/prodtechnol/WindowsServer2003/Library/IIS/502ef631-3695-4616-b268-cbe7cf1351ce.mspx?mfr=true" rel="nofollow">specify file types to be compressed</a> like .jpg, .png, .gif types, etc.</p><br/><br/><p>Caching will come from making sure that the correct headers are being sent to the client from code, and i believe there is a setting you can set in IIS that enables it for static content, but i'm not sure on that one.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PRIVAT A BLOGENGINE.NET INSTAL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I use this extension. Just save the file as RequireLogin.cs in your App_Code\Extensions folder and make sure the extension is activated.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>using System;<br/><br/>using System.Data;<br/><br/>using System.Configuration;<br/><br/>using System.Web;<br/><br/>using System.Web.Security;<br/><br/>using System.Web.UI;<br/><br/>using System.Web.UI.HtmlControls;<br/><br/>using System.Web.UI.WebControls;<br/><br/>using System.Web.UI.WebControls.WebParts;<br/><br/>using BlogEngine.Core;<br/><br/>using BlogEngine.Core.Web.Controls;<br/><br/>using System.Collections.Generic;<br/><br/><br/><br/>/// &lt;summary&gt;<br/><br/>/// Summary description for PostSecurity<br/><br/>/// &lt;/summary&gt;<br/><br/>[Extension("Checks to see if a user can see this blog post.",<br/><br/>            "1.0", "&lt;a href=\"http://www.lavablast.com\"&gt;LavaBlast.com&lt;/a&gt;")]<br/><br/>public class RequireLogin<br/>{<br/><br/>    static protected ExtensionSettings settings = null;<br/><br/><br/><br/>    public RequireLogin()<br/>    {<br/><br/>        Post.Serving += new EventHandler&lt;ServingEventArgs&gt;(Post_Serving);<br/><br/><br/><br/>        ExtensionSettings s = new ExtensionSettings("RequireLogin");<br/><br/>        // describe specific rules for entering parameters<br/><br/>        s.Help = "Checks to see if the user has any of those roles before displaying the post. ";<br/><br/>        s.Help += "You can associate a role with a specific category. ";<br/><br/>        s.Help += "All posts having this category will require that the user have the role. ";<br/><br/>        s.Help += "A parameter with only a role without a category will enable to filter all posts to this role. ";<br/><br/>        ExtensionManager.ImportSettings(s);<br/><br/>        settings = ExtensionManager.GetSettings("PostSecurity");<br/><br/>    }<br/><br/><br/><br/>    protected void Post_Serving(object sender, ServingEventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        MembershipUser user = Membership.GetUser();<br/>        if(HttpContext.Current.Request.RawUrl.Contains("syndication.axd"))<br/>        {<br/>            return;<br/>        }<br/><br/>        if (user == null)<br/>        {<br/>            HttpContext.Current.Response.Redirect("~/Login.aspx");<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USTOM CONTROL COMPOSIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I say go ahead with the custom rendered control. I find that in most cases the composite can be easier done and used in a UserControl, but anything beyond that and you'd need to have a finer degree of control (pun unintended) to merit your own rendering strategy.</p><br/><br/><p>There maybe controls that are simple enough to merit a composite (e.g., a textbox combined with a javascript/dhtml based datepicker, for example) but beyond that one example, it looks like custom rendered controls are the way to go.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TREIV THE PC NAME OF A CLIENT ( WINDOW AUTH )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>No, that just returns the IP :-(</p><br/><br/><p>But I just found it:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>System.Net.Dns.GetHostEntry(Page.Request.UserHostAddress).HostName<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>That only works if there is actually a DNS Server to resolve the name, which is the case for my network.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      COMPLEX OBJECT AS A WEB SERVIC RESULT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The .Net XML (de)serialisation is pretty nicely implemented. At first thought, I don't think this is a bad idea at all.</p><br/><br/><p>If the two applications import the same C# class(es) definition(s), then this is a relatively nice way of getting copy-constructor behaviour for free. If the class structure changes, then everything will work when both sides get the new class definition, without needing to make any additional changes on the web-service consumption/construction side.</p><br/><br/><p>There's a slight overhead in marshalling and demarshalling the XML, but that is probably dwarved by the overhead of the remote web service call. .Net XML serialisation is well understood by most programmers and should produce an easy to maintain solution.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REMOT NAME ADDRESS ( NOT IP )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Edit of my previous answer. <br/>Try (in vb.net): </p><br/><br/><pre><code>    Dim sTmp As String<br/>    Dim ip As IPHostEntry<br/><br/>    sTmp = MaskedTextBox1.Text<br/>    Dim ipAddr As IPAddress = IPAddress.Parse(sTmp)<br/>    ip = Dns.GetHostEntry(ipAddr)<br/>    MaskedTextBox2.Text = ip.HostName<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Dns.resolve appears to be obsolete in later versions of .Net. As stated here before I believe the issue is caused by your IP address not having a fixed name or by it having multiple names. The example above works with Google addresses, but not with an address we use that has a couple of names associated with it. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BUILD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There are a number of way to do it.  A nant build script will do it but I think the most commonly accepted method now is to use msbuild.  <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/0k6kkbsd.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/0k6kkbsd.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PRACTIS TO AUTHOR ALL USER FOR JUST ONE PAGE IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've been using forms authentication and creating the necessary GenericIdentity and CustomPrincipal objects that allows me to leverage the User.IsInRole type functions you typically only get with Windows authentication.</p><br/><br/><p>That way in my web.config file, I can do stuff like...</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;location path="Login.aspx"&gt;<br/>   &lt;system.web&gt;<br/>      &lt;authorization&gt;<br/>         &lt;allow users ="*" /&gt;<br/>      &lt;/authorization&gt;<br/>   &lt;/system.web&gt;<br/>&lt;/location&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;location path="ManagementFolder"&gt;<br/>   &lt;system.web&gt;<br/>      &lt;authorization&gt;<br/>         &lt;allow roles ="Administrator, Manager" /&gt;<br/>      &lt;/authorization&gt;<br/>   &lt;/system.web&gt;<br/>&lt;/location&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Hope this helps!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USER CONTROL VIEWDATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The ViewData.Eval("DisplayMessage") method should work for you.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ACCESS ASP.NET DEVELOP SERVER IN AN INTRANET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>No, you can't. It's set up so it only works on localhost, and I couldn't find any workarounds to make it work.</p><br/><br/><p>But, here's what I've been doing - I created the website on a specific port in IIS and opened that port up so it's visible on the network. I pointed that IIS website to my website's root folder (the one with web.config in it). Then I continued to use the ASP.NET Development server on that local machine while developing - both IIS and the ASP.NET Development Server can access the files at the same time (unless you're doing something wacky).</p><br/><br/><p>Let me know if there's a challenge with running IIS on your machine and I'll update my answer.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AUTHENT ACROSS APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You might also need to put path="/"  in the &lt;forms tag(s) I think. Sorry, its been a while since i've done this</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BASE METHOD WHEN OVERRID PAGE LEVEL EVENT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I should clarify:</p><br/><br/><p>The guidelines recommend that firing an event should involve calling a virtual "On<em>EventName</em>" method, but they also say that if a derived class overrides that method and forgets to call the base method, the event should still fire.</p><br/><br/><p>See the "Important Note" about halfway down <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms229011.aspx" rel="nofollow">this page</a>:</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>Derived classes that override the protected virtual method are not required to call the base class implementation. The base class must continue to work correctly even if its implementation is not called.</p><br/></blockquote><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WINDOW WORKFLOW FOUNDAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You could try <a href="http://www.thefreakparade.com/2008/05/simplestatemachine-codeplex-project/" rel="nofollow">Simple State Machine</a>. You would have to implement access control and background timers yourself, but that shouldn't be a big deal. SSM was also built out of frustration with WF. <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/Project/ProjectDirectory.aspx?ProjectSearchText=%22state%20machine%22" rel="nofollow">There are some other state machine implementations on Codeplex</a> as well. If one of them doesn't fit he bill out of the box, they are open source and should get you close enough. </p><br/><br/><p>I wholeheartedly agree with you about state machines in WF - they aren't testable, are too complicated, the threading model is peculiar and hard to follow, and I'm not sure a visual designer could have been more poorly conceived for designing state machines graphically. I think this may be because the state machine concept feels tacked onto the WF runtime, which was designed for sequential state machines, something WF does a much better job with, in my opinion. The problem is that state machines are really not the same animal as a sequential work flow, and should have been given a first class implementation of their own, because the warping of WF to make it seem to support them turned out to be more or less unsupportable, if not actually unusable.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET WEB SERVIC FROM ASP USE SOAPCLIENT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I solved this:</p><br/><br/><p>The SOAP client <em>request</em> node was picking up the default namespace from:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;ProcessMessage xmlns="http://internalservice.net/messageprocessing"&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Adding an empty default namespace to the XML sent by the ASP client overrides this behaviour:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>xmlMessage = "&lt;request xmlns=''&gt;&lt;task&gt;....various xml&lt;/task&gt;&lt;/request&gt;"<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EXECUT PREVENT KILL ( VS2008 ) LOCAL ASP.NET DEVELOP SERVER ( AKA CASSINI ) ON VISTA 64
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The only way to know for sure would be to dig through the Cassini source and see if there are any areas where it generates code on the heap and then executes it without clearing the NX flag.</p><br/><br/><p>However, instead of doing that, why not use IIS?</p><br/><br/><p>EDIT:</p><br/><br/><p>The danger of disabling DEP is that you open up security holes. DEP works by not allowing arbitrary generated code on the heap to be executed. This helps prevent malware programs from inserting code into the data segments of legit programs.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DATALIST ROW WITH MULTIPL PRIMARI KEY
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can access all of the keys:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>gridView.DataKeys[rowNum][dataKeyName]<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>where rowNum is e.RowIndex from the gridView_RowDeleting event handler, and dataKeyName is the key you want to get:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;asp:GridView ID="gridView" runat="server" DataKeyNames="userid, id1, id2, id3" OnRowDeleting="gridView_RowDeleting"&gt;<br/><br/>protected void gridView_RowDeleting(object sender, GridViewDeleteEventArgs e)<br/>{<br/>    gridView.DataKeys[e.RowIndex]["userid"]...<br/>    gridView.DataKeys[e.RowIndex]["id1"]...<br/>    gridView.DataKeys[e.RowIndex]["id2"]...<br/>    gridView.DataKeys[e.RowIndex]["id3"]...<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TINYMC EDITOR IMAG MANAG FILE UPLOAD FOR ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There are a couple of open source plugins on SourceForge,</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=103281&amp;atid=738747" rel="nofollow">http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=103281&amp;atid=738747</a><br/>(search for image)</p><br/><br/><p>The plugin architecture is easy to understand if you know Javascript.<br/>If you have the time you could roll out your own.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IN SEPAR ASSEMBL IN ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Essentially this is the same issue as people had with WebForms and trying to compile their UserControl ASCX files into a DLL. I found this <a href="http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/ASP2UserControlLibrary.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/ASP2UserControlLibrary.aspx</a> that might work for you too.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FILING OPTIM ( SHAREPOINT 2007 ) WEB PART
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Back when we started with SP2003, we used to worry about not closing connection in apps or web parts.  We used the following query to check if the base number of connections (not counting the initial spike) would increase as the app is used on the development server:</p><br/><br/><p>SELECT hostname, sysdatabases.name , sysprocesses.status, last<em>batch from  sysprocesses, sysdatabases where sysprocesses.dbid = sysdatabases.dbid and nt</em>username = '<strong>SP Service Account</strong>' and (hostname='<strong>WFE1</strong>' or hostname='<strong>WFE2</strong>') and sysprocesses.dbid = <strong>10</strong> order by last_batch desc</p><br/><br/><p>(replace the bolded values with those appropriate for your environment)</p><br/><br/><p>We haven't tried this since the upgrade to MOSS though.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET YELLOW SCREEN OF DEATH DISPLAY CODE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>A .Net assembly is compiled with metadata about the bytecode included that allows easy decompilation of the code - that's how tools like <a href="http://www.red-gate.com/products/reflector/" rel="nofollow">.Net Reflector</a> work.  The PDB files are debug symbols only - the difference in the Yellow Screen Of Death is that you'll get line numbers in the stack trace.</p><br/><br/><p>In other words, you'd get the code, even if the PDB files were missing.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RAW HTTP REQUEST CONTENT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Something like this placed in your onload event.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>if (Request.RequestType == "POST")<br/>{<br/>    using (StreamReader sr = new StreamReader(Request.InputStream))<br/>    {<br/>        if (sr.ReadLine() == "SUCCESS")<br/>        {<br/>            /* Do your parsing here */<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Mind you that they might want some special sort of response to (ie; not your full webpage), so you might do something like this after you're done parsing.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.Clear();<br/>Response.ContentType = "text/plain";<br/>Response.Write("Thanks!");<br/>Response.End();<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Update: this should be done in a Generic Handler (.ashx) file in order to avoid a great deal of overhead from the page model. Check out <a href="http://www.aspcode.net/Creating-an-ASHX-handler-in-ASPNET.aspx">this article</a> for more information about .ashx files</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LMERG AND WEB RESOURC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>OK - I got this working.  It looks like the primary assembly was the only one whose assembly attributes were being copied.  With copyattrs set, the last one in would win, not a merge (as far as I can tell).  I created a dummy project to reference the other DLL's and included all the web resources from those projects in the dummy assembly info - now multiple resources from multiple projects are all loading correctly.</p><br/><br/><p>Final post-build command line for dummy project:<br/>"C:\Program Files\Microsoft\ILMerge\ILMerge.exe" /keyfile:../../Company.snk /wildcards:True /out:Company.dll Company.Merge.dll Company.*.dll </p><br/><br/><p>Thanks.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FOR TESTABL ON AN EXIST SYSTEM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Your PM's concerns are valid - make sure you get your system under test before making any major refactorings.</p><br/><br/><p>I would strongly recommend getting a copy of Michael Feather's book <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0131177052" rel="nofollow">Working Effectively With Legacy Code</a> (by "Legacy Code" Feathers means any system that isn't adequately covered by unit tests).  This is chock full of good ideas for how to break down those couplings and dependencies you speak of, in a safe manner that won't risk introducing regression bugs.</p><br/><br/><p>Good luck with the refactoring programme; in my experience it's an enjoyable and cathartic process from which you can learn a lot.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      POSTBACK PROBLEM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It's a very specific problem with this code, I doubt it will be useful for someone else, but here it goes:</p><br/><br/><p>A check was added to the combo's <code>onchange</code> with an if, if the condition was met, an explicit call to the postback function was made.<br/>If the combo was set to <code>AutoPostback</code>, asp.net added the postback call again, producing the two postbacks...</p><br/><br/><p>The generated html was like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>[select onchange="javascript: if (CustomFunction()){__doPostBack('name','')}; __doPostBack('name','')"]<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DIRECT LINK FROM YELLOW SCREEN TO LINE IN CODE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You would probably need to embed an ActiveX control in the page for something like that to be possible.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REPORT SERVIC VIEWER FOR WEBPAG CAN YOU MOVE THE VIEW REPORT BUTTON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It's kind of a hack, but you can move it in JavaScript. Just see what HTML the ReportViewer generates, and write the appropriate JavaScript code to move the button. I used JavaScript to hide the button (because we wanted our own View Report button). Any JavaScript code that manipulates the generated ReportViewer's HTML must come after the ReportViewer control in the .aspx page. Here's my code for hiding the button, to give you an idea of what you'd do:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function getRepViewBtn() {<br/>  return document.getElementsByName("ReportViewer1$ctl00$ctl00")[0];<br/>}<br/><br/>function hideViewReportButton() { // call this where needed<br/>  var btn = getRepViewBtn();<br/>  btn.style.display = 'none';<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VBSCRIPT II HOW DO I AUTOMAT SET ASP.NET VERSION FOR A PARTICULAR WEBSIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>@<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/20923/vbscriptiis-how-do-i-automatically-set-aspnet-version-for-a-particular-website#20953" rel="nofollow">Chris</a> beat me to the punch on the ADSI way</p><br/><br/><p>You can do this using the aspnet_regiis.exe tool. There is one of these tools per version of ASP.NET installed on the machine. You could shell out to -</p><br/><br/><p>This configures ASP.NET 1.1</p><br/><br/><pre><code>%windir%\microsoft.net\framework\v1.1.4322\aspnet_regiis -s W3SVC/[iisnumber]/ROOT<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This configures ASP.NET 2.0</p><br/><br/><pre><code>%windir%\microsoft.net\framework\v2.0.50727\aspnet_regiis -s W3SVC/[iisnumber]/ROOT<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>You probably already know this, but if you have multiple 1.1 and 2.0 sites on your machine, just remember to switch the website you're changing ASP.NET versions on to compatible app pool. ASP.NET 1.1 and 2.0 sites don't mix in the same app pool.</p><br/><br/><p>HTH</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NAMESPAC EQUIVAL IN ASP.NET MARKUP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I believe you can add something like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%@ Import Namespace="RootNamespace.SubNamespace1" %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>At the top of the page.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AND NUNIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>After a bunch of research and experimentation, I've found the answer.  </p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>For the record, the current release of nUnit 2.5 Alpha <em>does not</em> seem to contain templates for test projects in Visual Studio 2008. </li><br/><li>I followed the directions <a href="http://vishaljoshi.blogspot.com/2008/02/aspnet-mvc-test-framework-integration.html" rel="nofollow">here</a> which describe how to create your own project templates and then add appropriate registry entries that allow your templates to appear in the drop-down box in the <em>Create Unit Test Project</em> dialog box of an MVC project.</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>From a high level, what you have to do is:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>Create a project</li><br/><li>Export it as a template (which results in a single ZIP archive)</li><br/><li>Copy it from the local user's template folder to the Visual Studio main template test folder</li><br/><li>Execute <strong>devenv.exe /setup</strong></li><br/><li>Run <strong>regedit</strong> and create a few registry entries.  </li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>So much for the testing framework selection being easy!  Although, to be fair MVC is not even beta yet.  </p><br/><br/><p>After all that, I did get the framework of choice (NUnit) to show up in the drop down box.  However, there was still a bit left to be desired:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Although the test project gets properly created, it did not automatically have a project reference to the main MVC project.  When using  <em>Visual Studio Unit Test</em> as the test project, it automatically does this.</li><br/><li>I tried to open the ZIP file produced and edit the MyTemplate.vssettings file as well as the .csproj project file in order to correct the aforementioned issue as well as tweak the names of things so they'd appear more user friendly.  This for some reason does not work.  The ZIP file produced can not be updated via WinZip or Win-Rar -- each indicates the archive is corrupt.  Each can extract the contents, though.  So, I tried updating the extracted files and then recreating the ZIP file.  Visual Studio did not like it.</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>So, I should probably read <a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/s365byhx.aspx" rel="nofollow">this</a> as well which discusses making project templates for Visual Studio (also referenced in the blog post I linked to above.)  I admit to being disappointed though; from all the talk about MVC playing well with other testing frameworks, etc, I thought that it'd be easier to register a 3rd party framework.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GET PROTOCOL HOST AND PORT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The following (C#) code should do the trick</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Uri uri = new Uri("http://www.mywebsite.com:80/pages/page1.aspx");<br/>string requested = uri.Scheme + Uri.SchemeDelimiter + uri.Host + ":" + uri.Port;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      COMMUN SERVIC LAYER MESSAGES ERROR TO HIGHER LAYER USE MVP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>That sounds just right to me. Exceptions are preferable as they can be thrown up to the top of the service layer from anywhere inside the service layer, no matter how deeply nested inside the service method implementation it is. This keeps the service code clean as you know the calling presenter will always get notification of the problem.</p><br/><br/><p><strong>Don't catch Exception</strong></p><br/><br/><p>However, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/21938/is-it-really-that-bad-to-catch-a-general-exception" rel="nofollow">don't catch Exception</a> in the presenter, I know its tempting because it keeps the code shorter, but you need to catch specific exceptions to avoid catching the system-level exceptions. </p><br/><br/><p><strong>Plan a Simple Exception Hierarchy</strong></p><br/><br/><p>If you are going to use exceptions in this way, you should design an exception hierarchy for your own exception classes. <br/>At a minumum create a ServiceLayerException class and throw one of these in your service methods when a problem occurs. Then if you need to throw an exception that should/could be handled differently by the presenter, you can throw a specific subclass of ServiceLayerException: say, AccountAlreadyExistsException.</p><br/><br/><p>Your presenter then has the option of doing</p><br/><br/><pre><code>try {<br/>  // call service etc.<br/>  // handle success to view<br/>} <br/>catch (AccountAlreadyExistsException) {<br/>  // set the message and some other unique data in the view<br/>}<br/>catch (ServiceLayerException) {<br/>  // set the message in the view<br/>}<br/>// system exceptions, and unrecoverable exceptions are allowed to bubble <br/>// up the call stack so a general error can be shown to the user, rather <br/>// than showing the form again.<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Using inheritance in your own exception classes means you are not required to catch multipile exceptions in your presenter -- you can if there's a need to -- and you don't end up accidentally catching exceptions you can't handle. If your presenter is already at the top of the call stack, add a catch( Exception ) block to handle the system errors with a different view.</p><br/><br/><p>I always try and think of my service layer as a seperate distributable library, and throw as specific an exception as makes sense. It is then up to the presenter/controller/remote-service implementation to decide if it needs to worry about the specific details or just to treat problems as a generic error.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RENDER ASP IMAG FROM BLOB ENTRI IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Add a 'Generic Handler' to your web project, name it something like Image.ashx. Implement it like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public class ImageHandler : IHttpHandler<br/>{<br/><br/>    public void ProcessRequest(HttpContext context)<br/>    {<br/>        using(Image image = GetImage(context.Request.QueryString["ID"]))<br/>        {    <br/>            context.Response.ContentType = "image/jpeg";<br/>            image.Save(context.Response.OutputStream, ImageFormat.Jpeg);<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/><br/>    public bool IsReusable<br/>    {<br/>        get<br/>        {<br/>            return true;<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Now just implement the GetImage method to load the image with the given ID, and you can use</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;asp:Image runat="server" ImageUrl="~/Image.ashx?ID=myImageId" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>to display it. You might want to think about implementing some form of caching in the handler too. And remember if you want to change the image format to PNG, you need to use an intermediate MemoryStream (because PNGs require a seekable stream to be saved).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP XXX CONTROL VERSU STANDARD HTML
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Personally, </p><br/><br/><p>I think the standard ASP.NET controls are fine for inhouse stuff - quick and dirty is good in that scenario. But, I once worked with a web developer who was also a designer and he refused to use the ASP.NET controls and only code in HTML and add runat="server" tags when needed. This was more because he wanted to know exactly how his HTML was going to be rendered, and at the time anyway, some of the ASP.NET controls wouldn't render to standards compliance.</p><br/><br/><p>I sit somewhere in the middle - use HTML where appropriate and not when not. You can sort of best of both worlds with the <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2006/05/02/444850.aspx" rel="nofollow">CSS control Adapters</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTTPHANDLER AND A WEB USER CONTROL AND WHEN TO USE EACH ONE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Expect a better answer (probably before I finish typing this) but as a quick summary.</p><br/><br/><p>A user control is something that can be added to a page.</p><br/><br/><p>A HttpHandler can be used instead of a page.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VS. UPDATEPANEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Don't move to UpdatePanels.  After coming from jQuery, <a href="http://encosia.com/2007/07/11/why-aspnet-ajax-updatepanels-are-dangerous/" rel="nofollow">the drop in performance</a> would be untenable.  Especially on a page as complex as yours sounds.</p><br/><br/><p>If you have 2,000 lines of JavaScript code, the solution is to refactor that code.  If you put 2,000 lines of C# code in one file, it would be difficult to maintain too.  That would be difficult to manage effectively with <strong>any</strong> language or tool.</p><br/><br/><p>If you're using 3.5 SP1, you can use the ScriptManager's new script combining to separate your JavaScript into multiple files with no penalty.  That way, you can logically partition your code just as you would with server side code.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GZIP COMPRESS CORRUPT CSS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Is it only CSS files that get corrupted? Do JS files (or any other static text files) come through ok?</p><br/><br/><p>Also can you duplicate the behavior if you browse directly to the CSS file?</p><br/><br/><p>I've only enabled compression on Windows 2003 server's IIS using this approach:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>IIS → Web Sites → Properties → Service tab, check both boxes</li><br/><li>IIS → Web Service Extensions → Right click, Add New<pre><br/>  Name<br/>      Http Compression <br/>  Required Files<br/>      %systemroot%\system32\inetsrv\gzip.dll </pre></li><br/><li>IIS → Right click top node, Internet Information Services, check <em>Enable Direct Metabase Edit</em></li><br/><li>Backup and Edit <code>%systemroot%\system32\inetsrv\MetaBase.xml</code><br/><ol><br/><li>Find <code>Location ="/LM/W3SVC/Filters/Compression/gzip"</code></li><br/><li>Add <code>png</code>, <code>css</code>, <code>js</code> and any other static file extensions to <code>HcFileExtensions</code></li><br/><li>Add <code>aspx</code> and any other executable extensions to <code>HcScriptFileExtensions</code></li><br/><li>Save </li><br/></ol></li><br/><li>Restart IIS (run <code>iisreset</code>) </li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>If you have a Windows 2003/2008 server to play with you could try that approach.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      3RD PARTI ASP.NET MENU CONTROL REPLAC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Why not roll you own based upon some existing code? I have been using a modified version of the <a href="http://htmldog.com/articles/suckerfish/dropdowns/" rel="nofollow">Son of Suckerfish Dropdowns</a> without any major issues. There are a couple of <a href="http://htmldog.com/ptg/archives/000050.php" rel="nofollow">fixes</a> that you need to get things working across the various browsers but once they are up and running they give you an extremely nice platform to work off of.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CLUSTER AN UPLOAD FOLDER WITH ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>At a former job we had a cluster of web servers with an F5 load balancer in front of them.  We had a very similar problem in that our applications allowed users to upload content which might include photo's and such.  These were legacy applications and we did not want to edit them to use a database and a SAN solution was too expensive for our situation.</p><br/><br/><p>We ended up using a file replication service on the two clustered servers. This ran as a service on both machines using an account that had network access to paths on the opposite server.  When a file was uploaded, this backend service sync'd the data in the file system folders making it available to be served from either web server.</p><br/><br/><p>Two of the products we reviewed were <a href="http://www.tgrmn.com/" rel="nofollow">ViceVersa</a> and <a href="http://www.peersoftware.com/products/peersync/peersync.aspx" rel="nofollow">PeerSync</a>.  I think we ended up using PeerSync.</p><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TUTORI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>A great book if you're just beginning is Matthew MacDonald's <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/1590598911" rel="nofollow">Beginning ASP.NET 3.5 in C# 2008: From Novice to Professional</a>. Once you're done with that a great reference (also by MacDonald) is <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/1590598938" rel="nofollow">Pro ASP.NET 3.5 in C# 2008</a>. One of my favorite sources of information online is <a href="http://aspnet.4guysfromrolla.com/default.aspx" rel="nofollow">4GuysFromRolla</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DECOD VIEWSTAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Use <a href="http://www.fiddlertool.com" rel="nofollow">Fiddler</a> and grab the view state in the response and paste it into the bottom left text box then decode.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BUILD YOUR OWN ROUT SYSTEM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This is going to be a long answer, because I want to make sure you are fully aware of all the ways you can accomplish what you want to do.</p><br/><br/><p>The routing engine that powers the ASP.NET MVC Framework will work with the traditional ASP.NET Framework.  You can take advantage of using the RouteTable and assigning routes, just like you would in an ASP.NET MVC application.  You just don't get the MVC portion in traditional ASP.NET sites.  That was a huge enhancement for the ASP.NET Framework and it was great to see them reuse that code and make it work in both frameworks.  If you want to learn more about this, check out ScottGu's <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/05/27/asp-net-mvc-preview-3-release.aspx" rel="nofollow">post</a> and scroll down to URL Routing Improvements.  Also here is a <a href="http://haacked.com/archive/2008/03/11/using-routing-with-webforms.aspx" rel="nofollow">reference</a> on how to use the System.Web.Routing in WebForms by Phil Haack.</p><br/><br/><p>Now, if you still want to write you own.  You will need to learn the ASP.NET HTTP pipeline and how to implement the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ihttpmodule.aspx" rel="nofollow">IHttpModule</a> and the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ihttphandler.aspx" rel="nofollow">IHttpHandler</a> interfaces to create your own HttpModule or HttpHandler class to handle your routing.  These interfaces are the key in writing your own routing engine.  To help put those interfaces in a working example, I couldn't recommend this <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms972974.aspx" rel="nofollow">MSDN article</a> enough.  It shows you how to with either interface and explains the differences when creating your own routing/url rewriting engine.</p><br/><br/><p>Now, if you find out that this might be to much for you.  There are third party libraries you can use of people who already wrote a routing/url rewriting engine in .NET.  Here is a question that I saw not to long ago asking "<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/14697/what-url-rewriter-do-you-use-for-aspnet" rel="nofollow">What Url rewriter do you use for ASP.Net?</a>" right here on SO.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PREVENT LEAD ZERO FROM BE STRIP WHEN IMPORT AN EXCEL DOC USE C #
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I believe you have to set the option in your connect string to force textual import rather than auto-detecting it.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Provider=Microsoft.ACE.OLEDB.12.0;<br/>    Data Source=c:\path\to\myfile.xlsx;<br/>    Extended Properties=\"Excel 12.0 Xml;IMEX=1\";<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Your milage may vary depending on the version you have installed.  The IMEX=1 extended property tells Excel to treat intermixed data as text.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DO PAGIN WITH A REPEAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This isn't a way to page the data, but have you looked into the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb398790.aspx" rel="nofollow">ListView</a> control? It gives the flexibility of repeater / data list but with built in paging like the grid view.</p><br/><br/><p>And for paging in sql, you would want to do something like <a href="http://www.davidhayden.com/blog/dave/archive/2005/12/30/2652.aspx" rel="nofollow">this</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      POST DOE N T CONTAIN TEXTBOX DATA ASP.NET C #
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Are you initially loading the data only when !Page.IsPostBack? Also, is view state enabled for the text box?</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DEAL WITH CACH AND THE BROWSER BACK BUTTON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can try using the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.httpresponse.cache.aspx" rel="nofollow">HttpResponse.Cache property</a> if that would help:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.Cache.SetExpires(DateTime.Now.AddSeconds(60));<br/>Response.Cache.SetCacheability(HttpCacheability.Public);<br/>Response.Cache.SetValidUntilExpires(false);<br/>Response.Cache.VaryByParams["Category"] = true;<br/><br/>if (Response.Cache.VaryByParams["Category"])<br/>{<br/>   //...<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Or could could block caching of the page altogether with <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.httpresponse.cachecontrol.aspx" rel="nofollow">HttpResponse.CacheControl</a>, but its been deprecated in favor of the Cache property above:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.CacheControl = "No-Cache";<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Edit: OR you could really <a href="http://forums.asp.net/t/1013531.aspx" rel="nofollow">go nuts</a> and do it all by hand:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.ClearHeaders();<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "no-cache"); //HTTP 1.1<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "private"); // HTTP 1.1<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "no-store"); // HTTP 1.1<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "must-revalidate"); // HTTP 1.1<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "max-stale=0"); // HTTP 1.1 <br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "post-check=0"); // HTTP 1.1 <br/>Response.AppendHeader("Cache-Control", "pre-check=0"); // HTTP 1.1 <br/>Response.AppendHeader("Pragma", "no-cache"); // HTTP 1.1 <br/>Response.AppendHeader("Keep-Alive", "timeout=3, max=993"); // HTTP 1.1 <br/>Response.AppendHeader("Expires", "Mon, 26 Jul 1997 05:00:00 GMT"); // HTTP 1.1<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TEST AN AJAX TIMEOUT CONDIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>First off, I think you need to be clearer in your question - what technology are you using and where is this process that is timing out - server-side or client-side?</p><br/><br/><p>If you want to have the server-side code take a long time and you are using .NET, place this line in the method you call server-side:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>System.Threading.Thread.Sleep(timeoutMilliseconds);<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>As long as you use a number sufficient so that your client-side code assumes the server has timed out, you should be good.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET AND OR CSS THEME
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I wouldn't bother looking for ASP.NET stuff specifically (probably won't find any anyways). Finding a good CSS theme easily can be used in ASP.NET.   </p><br/><br/><p>Here's some sites that I love for CSS goodness:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.freecsstemplates.org/" rel="nofollow">http://www.freecsstemplates.org/</a><br /><br/><a href="http://www.oswd.org/" rel="nofollow">http://www.oswd.org/</a><br /><br/><a href="http://www.openwebdesign.org/" rel="nofollow">http://www.openwebdesign.org/</a><br /><br/><a href="http://www.styleshout.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.styleshout.com/</a><br /><br/><a href="http://www.freelayouts.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.freelayouts.com/</a>  </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AN IISRESET DO
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>IISReset stops and restarts the entire web server (including non-ASP.NET apps)<br /><br/>Recycling an app pool will only affect applications running in that app pool.<br /><br/>Editing the web.config in a web application only affects that web application (recycles just that app).<br /><br/>Editing the machine.config on the machine will recycle all app pools running.  </p><br/><br/><p>IIS will monitor the /bin directory of your application.  Whenever a change is detected in those dlls, it will recycle the app and re-load those new dlls.  It also monitors the web.config &amp; machine.config in the same way and performs the same action for the applicable apps.  </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PORT SYSTEM FOR ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Reporting Services, <strong>free</strong> and included with SQL Server 2005 and 2008.</p><br/><br/><p>Of course, this is great if you need a separation of report design and application, which for Enterprise applications is a huge plus.</p><br/><br/><p>However, if what you want is to be able to create "in application" dashboards, where "you" design the reports and have limited parameters you expose to the user, then I suggest looking into "control" based charting vendors like <a href="http://www.steema.com/" rel="nofollow">TeeChart</a> . </p><br/><br/><p>Pros/cons of each strategy:<br/>Crystal/Microsoft Reporting services will give you out of the box handling of things like report scheduling, export to excel and pdf, and separation between application and report design. <br/>The independent charting tools you can get give you better control, they render better on any size you need, easier to grammatically manipulate and can handle eye candy such as flash based (no flash charts in MS SSRS)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EXPERI USE ASP.NET MVC FRAMEWORK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've just been recently turned on to MVC and Linq to Sql for Asp.Net.  I'm still learning both, and I'm really enjoying them both.  There are quite a few screen casts on <a href="http://www.asp.net/learn/" rel="nofollow">http://www.asp.net/learn/</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUT ANCHOR TAG IN A STRING
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's a simple regular expression that should work.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Imports System.Text.RegularExpressions<br/><br/>' ....<br/><br/>Dim reg As New Regex("&lt;a.*?href=(?:'|"")(.+?)(?:'|"").*?&gt;.+?&lt;/a&gt;")<br/>Dim input As String = "This is a link: &lt;a href='http://www.stackoverflow.com'&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;"<br/>input = reg.Replace(input, "$1", RegexOptions.IgnoreCase)<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A COLUMN IN ASP.NET DYNAM DATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Had no idea what ASP.NET Dynamic Data was so you promted me to so some research :)</p><br/><br/><p>Looks like the property you are looking for is </p><br/><br/><pre><code>[ScaffoldColumn(false)]<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>There is also a similar property for tables</p><br/><br/><pre><code>[ScaffoldTable(false)]<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p><a href="http://davidhayden.com/blog/dave/archive/2008/05/15/DynamicDataWebsitesScaffoldTableScaffoldColumnAttributes.aspx" rel="nofollow">source</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>ASP.NET is a web application framework<br/>  developed and marketed by Microsoft,<br/>  that programmers can use to build<br/>  dynamic web sites, web applications<br/>  and web services. It was first<br/>  released in January 2002 with version<br/>  1.0 of the .NET Framework, and is the successor to Microsoft's Active Server<br/>  Pages (ASP) technology. ASP.NET is<br/>  built on the Common Language Runtime<br/>  (CLR), allowing programmers to write<br/>  ASP.NET code using any supported .NET<br/>  language.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASP.NET" rel="nofollow">ASP.NET </a> (Wikipedia)</p><br/><br/><p>That's on the second result searching on Google so I'm guessing (half-expecting) that you don't understand what that means either.</p><br/><br/><p>Webpage development started with simple static HTML pages. That meant the client asked for a page by means of an URL and the server sent the page back to him/her exactly as it has been designed. Sometime after that several technologies emerged in order to provide a more "dynamic" or personalized experience.</p><br/><br/><p>Several "server side languages" were developed (PHP, Perl, ASP...) which allowed the server to process the Web page before sending it back to the client. This way when a client requested a webpage the server could interpret the request, process it (for example connecting to a database and fetching some results) and send it back modifying the contents and making them "dynamic". The fact that the process took place on the server stands for the name of "server side".</p><br/><br/><p>So the original ASP (predecessor of the ASP.NET) was a server side language that was focused on serving web pages. In such way it supported several shortcuts such as the possibility to intercalate HTML and ASP source into the file which was on that time much popular due to PHP implementation. It was also (as most of these languages) a dynamic language and it was interpreted.</p><br/><br/><p>ASP.NET is an evolution of that original ASP with some improvements. First it does truly (try to) separate the presentation (HTML) from the code (.cs) which may be implemented by using Visual Basic or C# syntax. It also incorporate some sort of compilation to the final ASP pages, encapsulating them into assemblies and thus improving performance. Finally it has access to the full .NET framework which supports a wide number of helper classes.</p><br/><br/><p>So, summing up, it is a programming language located on the server and designed to make webpages.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SIT FIRST START IS VERI SLOW
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It's just your app domain loading up and loading any binaries into memory. Also, it's initializing static variables, so if you have a static variable that loads up a lot of data from the db, it might take a bit.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SUBFOLD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There isn't any issues with organizing your controllers.  You just need to setup the routes to take the organization into consideration.  The problem you will run into is finding the view for the controller, since you changed the convention.  There isn't any built in functionality for it yet, but it is easy to create a work around yourself with a ActionFilterAttribute and a custom view locator that inherits off ViewLocator.  Then when creating your controller, you just specify what ViewLocator to use, so the controller knows how to find the view.  I can post some code if needed.</p><br/><br/><p>This method kind of goes along with some advice I gave another person for separating their views out for a portal using ASP.NET MVC.  Here is the <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/19746/views-in-seperate-assemblies-in-aspnet-mvc" rel="nofollow">link to the question</a> as a reference.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USE SYSTEM.WEB.UI.CONTROL.RESOLVEURL ( ) IN A SHARED STAT FUNCTION
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I use <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.virtualpathutility.aspx" rel="nofollow">System.Web.VirtualPathUtility.ToAbsolute</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PROGRAMMAT FILL IN A FORM AND POST A WEB PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can see a sample of that here: <a href="http://en.csharp-online.net/HTTP_Post" rel="nofollow">http://en.csharp-online.net/HTTP_Post</a>  </p><br/><br/><p>Basically, the code will look something like this:  </p><br/><br/><pre><code>WebRequest req = WebRequest.Create("http://mysite/myform.aspx");<br/>string postData = "item1=11111&amp;item2=22222&amp;Item3=33333";<br/><br/>byte[] send = Encoding.Default.GetBytes(postData);<br/>req.Method = "POST";<br/>req.ContentType = "application/x-www-form-urlencoded";<br/>req.ContentLength = send.Length;<br/><br/>Stream sout = req.GetRequestStream();<br/>sout.Write(send, 0, send.Length);<br/>sout.Flush();<br/>sout.Close();<br/><br/>WebResponse res = req.GetResponse();<br/>StreamReader sr = new StreamReader(res.GetResponseStream());<br/>string returnvalue = sr.ReadToEnd();<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAVASCRIPT CALLBACK WITHOUT FULL POSTBACK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you don't want to create a blank page, you could call a IHttpHandler (ashx) file:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public class RSSHandler : IHttpHandler<br/>    {<br/>    	public void ProcessRequest (HttpContext context)<br/>    	{   <br/>    		context.Response.ContentType = "text/xml";<br/><br/>    		string sXml = BuildXMLString(); //not showing this function, <br/>    		//but it creates the XML string<br/>    		context.Response.Write( sXml );<br/>    	}<br/><br/>    	public bool IsReusable<br/>    	{<br/>    		get { return true; }<br/>    	}<br/><br/>    }<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AND PAGEREQUESTMANAGERPARSERERROREXCEPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The RoleProvider sets a cookie to cache role information in a cookie.  When the cookie resets during an asynch post back from AJAX, you will get this error.  The solution is to either set the cookieTimeout in the roleManager section of your web.config to a very large number of minutes, or set the cacheRolesInCookie=false.</p><br/><br/><p>This was a known bug in AJAX 1.0 Extensions.  I'm not sure if it was fixed in future releases, and I should have mentioned that I was using AJAX 1.0 extensions in VS2008 targeting the 2.0 framework.</p><br/><br/><p>Happy programming!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CREAT A THUMBNAIL USE ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I suppose your best solution would be using the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.drawing.image.getthumbnailimage.aspx" rel="nofollow">GetThumbnailImage </a> from the .NET <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.drawing.image.aspx" rel="nofollow">Image</a> class.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>// Example in C#, should be quite alike in ASP.NET<br/>// Assuming filename as the uploaded file<br/>using ( Image bigImage = new Bitmap( filename ) )<br/>{<br/>   // Algorithm simplified for purpose of example.<br/>   int height = bigImage.Height / 10;<br/>   int width = bigImage.Width / 10;<br/><br/>   // Now create a thumbnail<br/>   using ( Image smallImage = image.GetThumbnailImage( width, <br/>                                                       height,<br/>                                                       new Image.GetThumbnailImageAbort(Abort), IntPtr.Zero) )<br/>   {<br/>      smallImage.Save("thumbnail.jpg", ImageFormat.Jpeg);<br/>   }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SHARE ASP.NET .ASCX CONTROL ACROSS DIFFER WEBSIT APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You would need to create composite controls instead of .ASCX controls if you wanted to be able to use them in separate projects.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET WHAT ARE THE DIFFER WAY TO INLIN CODE IN THE .ASPX
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Check out the <a href="http://quickstarts.asp.net/QuickStartv20/aspnet/doc/pages/syntax.aspx#expressions" rel="nofollow">Web Forms Syntax Reference</a> on MSDN.</p><br/><br/><p>For basics, </p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><p>&lt;% %> is used for pure code blocks.  I generally only use this for if statements</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>&lt;% if (IsLoggedIn) { %><br/><br/>    &nbsp; &lt;div class="authenticated"><br/><br/>    &lt;% } else { %><br/><br/>    &nbsp; &lt;div class="unauthenticated"><br/><br/>    &lt;% } %></p><br/></blockquote></li><br/><li><p>&lt;%= Expression %> is used to add text into your markup; that is, it equates to &lt;% Response.Write(Expression) %></p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>&lt;div class='&lt;%= IsLoggedIn ? "authenticated" : "unauthenticated" %>'></p><br/></blockquote></li><br/><li><p>&lt;%# Expression %> is very similar to the above, but it is evaluated in a DataBinding scenario.  One thing that this means is that you can use these expressions to set values of runat="server" controls, which you can't do with the &lt;%= %> syntax.  Typically this is used inside of a template for a databound control, but you can also use it in your page, and then call Page.DataBind() (or Control.DataBind()) to cause that code to evaluate.</p></li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>The others mentioned in the linked article are less common, though certainly have their uses, too.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HANDL ERROR WHEN USE JQUERY.AJAX ( )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>Should I be throwing the errors in the<br/>  ashx, or should I be returning a<br/>  status code as part of the data<br/>  returned by the call to<br/>  userCreation.ashx, then using this to<br/>  decide what action to take? How do you<br/>  handle these situations?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Personally, if possible, I would prefer to handle this on the server side and work up a message to the user there. This works very well in a scenario where you only want to display a message to the user telling them what happened (validation message, essentially).</p><br/><br/><p>However, if you want to perform an action based on what happened on the server, you may want to use a status code and write some javascript to perform various actions based on that status code.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CONTROL THAT USE A CERTAIN INTERFAC IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Longhorn213 almost has the right answer, but as as Sean Chambers and bdukes say, you should use  </p><br/><br/><pre><code>ctrl is IInterfaceToFind<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>instead of  </p><br/><br/><pre><code>ctrl.GetType() == aTypeVariable<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>The reason why is that if you use .GetType(), you will get the true type of an object, not necessarily what it can also be cast to in its inheritance/Interface implementation chain. Also, .GetType() will never return an abstract type/interface since you can't new up an abstract type or interface. GetType() returns concrete types only.</p><br/><br/><p>The reason this doesn't work</p><br/><br/><pre><code>if(ctrl is typeToFind)<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Is because the type of the variable typeToFind is actually System.RuntimeType, not the type you've set its value to. Example, if you set a string's value to "foo", its type is still string not "foo". I hope that makes sense. It's very easy to get confused when working with types. I'm chronically confused when working with them.</p><br/><br/><p>The most import thing to note about longhorn213's answer is that <strong>you have to use recursion</strong> or you may miss some of the controls on the page. </p><br/><br/><p>Although we have a working solution here, I too would love to see if there is a more succinct way to do this with LINQ. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VISUAL STUDIO 2008 WEB DEPLOY PROJECT GET AN ERROR FIND ASPNET MERGE.EX
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Apparently aspnet_merge.exe (and all the other SDK tools) are NOT packaged in Visual Studio 2008.  Visual Studio 2005 packaged these tools as part of its installation.</p><br/><br/><p>The place to get this is an installation of the Windows 2008 SDK (<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/thankyou.aspx?familyId=e6e1c3df-a74f-4207-8586-711ebe331cdc&amp;displayLang=en" rel="nofollow">latest download</a>).<br/>Windows 7/Windows 2008 R2 SDK: <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=c17ba869-9671-4330-a63e-1fd44e0e2505&amp;displaylang=en" rel="nofollow">here</a></p><br/><br/><p>The solution is to install the Windows SDK and make sure you set FrameworkSDKDir as an environment variable before starting the IDE.  Batch command to set this variable:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>SET FrameworkSDKDir="C:\Program Files\Microsoft SDKs\Windows\v6.1"<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>NOTE: You will need to modify to point to where you installed the SDK if not in the default location.</p><br/><br/><p>Now VS2008 will know where to find aspnet_merge.exe.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EMOD BREAK ASP.NET POSTBACK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Both of you were on the right track.  What I realized is that SimpleModal appends the dialog to the body, which is outside ASP.Net's <code>&lt;form&gt;</code>, which breaks the functionality, since it can't find the elements.</p><br/><br/><p>To fix it, I just modified the SimpleModal source to append eveything to <code>'form'</code> instead of <code>'body'</code>.  When I create the dialog, I also use the <code>persist: true</code> option, to make sure the buttons stay through opening and closing.</p><br/><br/><p>Thanks everyone for the suggestions!</p><br/><br/><p><em>UPDATE:</em> Version 1.3 adds an <code>appendTo</code> option in the configuration for specifying which element the modal dialog should be appended to. <a href="http://www.ericmmartin.com/projects/simplemodal/#options" rel="nofollow">Here are the docs</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SERVERVARI APPL MD PATH RETREIV THE METABAS PATH FOR THE APPLIC FOR THE ISAPI DLL MEAN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Are you running your application locally inside of IIS or inside of the development web server? If it's the latter, then that's probably why: Cassini (the development web server) doesn't do ISAPI, so this value will be empty.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SUPPRESS NTLM DIALOG BOX AFTER UNAUTHOR REQUEST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/2199/mark-brackett">Mark</a>'s comment is correct; The NTLM auth prompt is triggered by a 401 response code and the presence of NTLM as the first mechanism offered in the WWW-Authenticate header (Ref: <a href="http://curl.haxx.se/rfc/ntlm.html" rel="nofollow">The NTLM Authentication Protocol</a>).</p><br/><br/><p>I'm not sure if I understand the question description correctly, but I think you are trying to wrap the NTLM authentication for SharePoint, which means you don't have control over the server-side authentication protocol, correct? If you're not able to manipulate the server side to avoid sending a 401 response on failed credentials, then you will not be able to avoid this problem, because it's part of the (client-side) spec:</p><br/><br/><h3><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2006/WD-XMLHttpRequest-20060619/" rel="nofollow">The XMLHttpRequest Object</a></h3><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>If the UA supports HTTP Authentication [RFC2617] it SHOULD consider requests<br/>  originating from this object to be part of the protection space that includes the<br/>  accessed URIs and send Authorization  headers and handle 401 Unauthorised requests<br/>  appropriately. if authentication fails, UAs should prompt the users for credentials.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>So the spec actually calls for the browser to prompt the user accordingly if any 401 response is received in an XMLHttpRequest, just as if the user had accessed the URL directly. As far as I can tell the only way to really avoid this would be for you to have control over the server side and cause 401 Unauthorized responses to be avoided, as Mark mentioned. </p><br/><br/><p>One last thought is that you may be able to get around this using a proxy, such a separate server side script on another webserver. That script then takes a user and pass parameter and checks the authentication, so that the user's browser isn't what's making the original HTTP request and therefore isn't receiving the 401 response that's causing the prompt. If you do it this way you can find out from your "proxy" script if it failed, and if so then prompt the user again until it succeeds. On a successful authentication event, you can simply fetch the HTTP request as you are now, since everything works if the credentials are correctly specified.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET EXECUTIONTIMEOUT IN CODE REFRESH REQUEST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you want to increase the execution timeout for this one request you can set</p><br/><br/><pre><code>HttpContext.Current.Server.ScriptTimeout</code></pre><br/><br/><p>But you still may have the problem of the client timing out which you can't reliably solve directly from the server.  To get around that you could implement a "processing" page (like Rob suggests) that posts back until the response is ready.  Or you might want to look into AJAX to do something similar.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DYNAM AD WEB.UI.ITEMPL CLASS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I have worked extensively with templated control and I have not found a better solution.</p><br/><br/><p>Why are you referencing the contentLable in the event handler?</p><br/><br/><p>The sender is the label you can cast it to the label and have the reference to the label.  Like below.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>        //add a custom data binding<br/>        contentLabel.DataBinding +=<br/>            (object sender, EventArgs e ) =&gt;<br/>            {<br/>                //do custom stuff at databind time<br/>                ((Label)sender).Text = //bound content<br/>            };<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Then you should be able to dispose of the label reference in InstantiateIn.</p><br/><br/><p>Please note I have not tested this.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MIGRAT TO ASP.NET MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you are quite happy with WebForms today, then maybe ASP.NET MVC isn't for you.</p><br/><br/><p>I have been frustrated with WebForms for a really long time.  I'm definitely not alone here.  The smart-client, stateful abstraction over the web breaks down severely in complex scenarios.  I happen to love HTML, Javascript, and CSS.  WebForms tries to hide that from me.  It also has some really complex solutions to problems that are really not that complex.  Webforms is also inherently difficult to test, and while you can use MVP, it's not a great solution for a web environment...(compared to MVC).</p><br/><br/><p>MVC will appeal to you if...<br/>- you want more control over your HTML<br/>- want a seamless ajax experience like every other platform has<br/>- want testability through-and-through<br/>- want meaningful URLs<br/>- HATE dealing with postback &amp; viewstate issues</p><br/><br/><p>And as for the framework being Preview 5, it is quite stable, the design is mostly there, and upgrading is not difficult.  I started an app on Preview 1 and have upgraded within a few hours of the newest preview being available.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ENTER KEY TO INSERT NEWLIN IN ASP.NET MULTILIN TEXTBOX CONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It turns out this is a bug with Firefox + ASP.NET where the generated javascript for the defaultButton stuff doesn't work in Firefox. I had to put a replacement for the WebForm_FireDefatultButton function as described <a href="http://forums.asp.net/t/1294544.aspx" rel="nofollow">here</a>:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function WebForm_FireDefaultButton(event, target) {<br/>    var element = event.target || event.srcElement;<br/>    if (event.keyCode == 13 &amp;&amp;<br/>    !(element &amp;&amp;<br/>    element.tagName.toLowerCase() == "textarea"))<br/>    {<br/>        var defaultButton;<br/>        if (__nonMSDOMBrowser)<br/>        {<br/>            defaultButton = document.getElementById(target);<br/>        }<br/>        else<br/>        {<br/>            defaultButton = document.all[target];<br/>        }<br/>        if (defaultButton &amp;&amp; typeof defaultButton.click != "undefined")<br/>        {<br/>            defaultButton.click();<br/>            event.cancelBubble = true;<br/>            if (event.stopPropagation)<br/>            {<br/>                event.stopPropagation();<br/>            }<br/>            return false;<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/>    return true;<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REFERENCEEXCEPT ON USER CONTROL HANDL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Where are you trying to access the property?  If you are in onInit, the control may not be loaded yet.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ROUT HOW DO I IGNOR MULTIPL WILDCARD ROUT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There are two possible solutions here.</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li><p>Add a constraint to the ignore route to make sure that only requests that should be ignored would match that route. Kinda kludgy, but it should work.</p><br/><br/><p>RouteTable.Routes.IgnoreRoute("{folder}/{*pathInfo}", new {folder="content"});</p></li><br/><li><p>What is in your content directory? By default, Routing does not route files that exist on disk (actually checks the VirtualPathProvider). So if you are putting static content in the Content directory, you might not need the ignore route.</p></li><br/></ol><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MVP HOW TO USE EVENT PROPERLI FOR TEST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't know if there's a universally preferred pattern. I tend to prefer adding the event to the view interface and having the presenter respond to the view. I described this pattern in <a href="http://haacked.com/archive/2006/08/09/ASP.NETSupervisingControllerModelViewPresenterFromSchematicToUnitTestsToCode.aspx" rel="nofollow">more detail here</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RETRIEV DATA SENT TO THE WEB SERVER IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can also search through both the Form and QueryString collections at the same time so that the data will be found regardless of the the request method.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>value = Request("formElementID")<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SHARE MASTERPAG ACROSS PROJECT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I have trying to accomplish the same thing.  I look into a couple of solutions but I think using a virtual directory is probably the best way to share master pages.  </p><br/><br/><p>Here are a couple sources that you can look at. </p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/shahpiyush/archive/2007/03/09/Sharing-Master-Pages-amongst-Applications-by-Embedding-it-in-a-Dll_2E00_.aspx" rel="nofollow">Sharing Master Pages amongst<br/>Applications by Embedding it in a<br/>Dll</a></li><br/><li><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa992039(VS.80).aspx" rel="nofollow">Sharing Master Pages in Visual Studio</a></li><br/><li><a href="http://www.odetocode.com/articles/450.aspx" rel="nofollow">ASP.Net 2.0 - Master Pages: Tips, Tricks, and Traps </a></li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>The third bullets near the end the article tells you of possible ways you can share Masterpages also.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DO YOU UNIT TEST WEBCONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can do model-view-controller or model-view-presenter type architectures without using a full blown framework. You already found out that unit-testing ui-components is difficult. There are ways around that but you probably don't want to go that route. Usually this will make your tests very hard to maintain, more maintenance nightmare's is something programmers can do without :-)</p><br/><br/><p>Try to separate out the functionality you want to test in a "controller" or "presenter" class. Then test that class. To make it more testable you can hide the usercontrol class (the view) behind an interface and make the controller or presenter talk to the view through the interface. That way you can mock up the view in your tests.</p><br/><br/><p>I know this sounds like a lot of work and it seems like a workaround but if you get used to this it's a realy nice architecture that makes it far easier to change ui behaviour. You can always start using a "real" mvc framework when you realy need it :-)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP CLASSIC TO .NET AND PAIN MITIG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Believe me, I know <em>exactly</em> where you are coming from.. I am currently migrating a large app from ASP classic to .NET.. And I am still learning ASP.NET! :S (yes, I am terrified!).</p><br/><br/><p>The main things I have kept in my mind is this:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>I dont stray <em>too</em> far from the current design (i.e. no massive "lets rip ALL of this out and make it ASP.NET magical!) due to the incredibly high amount of coupling that ASP classic tends to have, this would be very dangerous. Of course, if you are confident, fill your boots :) This can always be refactored later.</li><br/><li>Back everything up with tests, tests and more tests! I am really trying hard to get into TDD, but its very difficult to test existing apps, so every time I remove a chunk of classic and replace with .NET, I ensure I have as much green-light tests backing me as possible.</li><br/><li>Research a lot, there are some MAJOR changes between classic and .NET and sometimes what can be many lines of code and includes in classic can be achieved in a few lines of code, <em>think</em> before coding.. I've learnt this the hard way, several times :D</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>Its very much like playing <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/B00004XQW9" rel="nofollow">Jenga</a> with your code :)</p><br/><br/><p>Best of luck with the project, any more questions, then please ask :)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SPONSE.REDIRECT USE PATH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>I think you need to drop the "~/" and replace it with just "/", I believe / is the root</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p><strong>STOP RIGHT THERE!</strong> :-) unless you want to hardcode your web app so that it can only be installed at the root of a web site. </p><br/><br/><p>"~/" <strong><em>is</em></strong> the correct thing to use, but the reason that your original code didn't work as expected is that <code>ResolveUrl</code> (which is used internally by <code>Redirect</code>) tries to first work out if the path you are passing it is an absolute URL (e.g. "*<em>http://server/</em>*foo/bar.htm" as opposed to "foo/bar.htm") - but unfortunately it does this by simply looking for a colon character ':' in the URL you give it. But in this case it finds a colon in the URL you give in the <code>ReturnPath</code> query string value, which fools it - therefore your '~/' doesn't get resolved.</p><br/><br/><p>The fix is that you should be URL-encoding the <code>ReturnPath</code> value which escapes the problematic ':' along with any other special characters.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.Redirect("~/Login.aspx?ReturnPath=" + Server.UrlEncode(Request.Url.ToString()));<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Additionally, I recommend that you (or anyone) never use <code>Uri.ToString</code> - because it gives a human-readable, more "friendly" version of the URL - not a necessarily correct one (it unescapes things). Instead use Uri.AbsoluteUri - like so:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.Redirect("~/Login.aspx?ReturnPath=" + Server.UrlEncode(Request.Url.AbsoluteUri));<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GOOD ASP.NET MVC SAMPL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://code.google.com/p/codecampserver/" rel="nofollow">CodeCampServer</a> - Built with ASP.NET MVC, pretty light and small project.  No cruft at all.</p><br/><br/><p>@lomaxx - Just FYI, most of what Troy Goode wrote is now part of <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/07/14/asp-net-mvc-preview-4-release-part-1.aspx" rel="nofollow">ASP.NET MVC as of Preview 4</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OVERFLOW STYLE NOTIF IN ASP.NET AJAX
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I like it to.<br /><br/>div tag with a fade.<br /><br/><a href="http://www.asp.net/AJAX/AjaxControlToolkit/Samples/Walkthrough/UsingAnimations.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.asp.net/AJAX/AjaxControlToolkit/Samples/Walkthrough/UsingAnimations.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FIRE AN UPDATEPANEL AFTER THE PAGE LOAD IS COMPLET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Use a timer control that will be fired after a certain number of milliseconds (for page to load). In the timer tick event refresh the update panel.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EXTRACT THE INNER EXCEPT FROM A SOAP EXCEPT IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Unfortunately I don't think this is possible.</p><br/><br/><p>The exception you are raising in your web service code is being encoded into a Soap Fault, which then being passed as a string back to your client code.</p><br/><br/><p>What you are seeing in the SoapException message is simply the text from the Soap fault, which is not being converted back to an exception, but merely stored as text.</p><br/><br/><p>If you want to return useful information in error conditions then I recommend returning a custom class from your web service which can have an "Error" property which contains your information.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>[WebMethod]<br/>public ResponseClass HelloWorld()<br/>{<br/>  ResponseClass c = new ResponseClass();<br/>  try <br/>  {<br/>    throw new Exception("Exception Text");<br/>    // The following would be returned on a success<br/>    c.WasError = false;<br/>    c.ReturnValue = "Hello World";<br/>  }<br/>  catch(Exception e)<br/>  {<br/>    c.WasError = true;<br/>    c.ErrorMessage = e.Message;<br/>    return c;<br/>  }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET RADIOBUTTON WITH JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I found 2 ways to get this to work, the below code correctly distinguishes between the RadioButton and Checkbox controls.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>    private static void DisableControl(WebControl control)<br/>    {<br/>        Type controlType = control.GetType();<br/><br/>        if (controlType == typeof(CheckBox))<br/>        {<br/>            ((CheckBox)control).InputAttributes.Add("disabled", "disabled");<br/><br/>        }<br/>        else if (controlType == typeof(RadioButton))<br/>        {<br/>            ((RadioButton)control).InputAttributes.Add("disabled", "true");<br/>        }<br/>        else if (controlType == typeof(ImageButton))<br/>        {<br/>            ((ImageButton)control).Enabled = false;<br/>        }<br/>        else<br/>        {<br/>            control.Attributes.Add("readonly", "readonly");<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>And the solution I used is to set SubmitDisabledControls="True" in the form element which is not ideal as it allows a user to fiddle with the values but is fine in my scenario. The second solution is to mimic the Disabled behavior and details can be found here: http://aspnet.4guysfromrolla.com/articles/012506-1.aspx'>http://aspnet.4guysfromrolla.com/articles/012506-1.aspx.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FILE TO APP DATA UNDER MEDIUM TRUST HACK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't have access to the server itself, so I can't check that. I can only chmod files and folder from my FTP client.</p><br/><br/><p>I think my hosting provider needs to grant write permission to the network service account on the App_Data folder.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IMAG TO DISPLAY WITH ASP.NET AND APP OFFLINE.HTM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Yes, it just can't come from the site that has the app_offline.htm file. The image would have to be hosted elsewhere. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VALID INSID AN UPDATEPANEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I suspect you are running the original release (RTM) of .NET 2.0.</p><br/><br/><p>Until early 2007 validator controls were not compatible with UpdatePanels. This was resolved with the SP1 of the .NET Framework.</p><br/><br/><p>The source of the problem is that UpdatePanel can detect markup changes in your page, but it has no way to track scripts correctly. Validators rely heavily on scripts. During a partial postback, the scripts are either blown away, not updated, or not run when they are meant to.</p><br/><br/><p>In early betas, MS had the UpdatePanel try to <em>guess</em> what scripts needed to be re-rendered or run. It didn't work very well, and they had to take it out.</p><br/><br/><p>To get around the immediate problem, Microsoft released a patched version of the validator classes in a new DLL called Validators.DLL, and gave instructions on how to tell ASP.NET to use those classes instead of the real ones. If you Google for that DLL name, you should find more information. See also <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/mattgi/archive/2007/01/23/asp-net-ajax-validators.aspx" rel="nofollow">This blog post</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>This was a stop-gag measure and you should <strike>not use it</strike> <em>avoid it if possible</em>.</p><br/><br/><p>The real solution to the problem came shortly after, in .NET 2.0 SP1. Microsoft introduced a new mechanism to register scripts in SP1, and changed the real validator classes to use that mechanism instead of the older one.</p><br/><br/><p>Let me give you some details on the changes:</p><br/><br/><p>Traditionally, you were supposed to register scripts via Page methods such as Page.RegisterStartupScript() and Page.RegisterClientScriptBlock(). The problem is that these methods were not designed for extensibility and UpdatePanel had no way to monitor those calls.</p><br/><br/><p>In SP1 there is a new property object on the page called Page.ClientScripts. This object has methods to register scripts that are equivalent (and in some ways better) to the original ones. Also, UpdatePanel can monitor these calls, so that it rerenders or calls the methods when appropriate. The older RegisterStartupScript(), etc. methods have been deprecated. They still work, but not inside an UpdatePanel.</p><br/><br/><p>There is no reason (other than politics, I suppose) to not update your installations to .NET 2.0 SP1. Service Packs carry important fixes.</p><br/><br/><p>Good luck.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTTPCACHEABILITY.PRIV SUPPRESS ETAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think you need to use HttpCacheability.ServerAndPrivate</p><br/><br/><p>That should give you cache-control: private in the headers and let you set an ETag.</p><br/><br/><p>The documentation on that needs to be a bit better.</p><br/><br/><p><strong>Edit:</strong> Markus found that you also have call cache.SetOmitVaryStar(true) otherwise the cache will add the Vary: * header to the output and you don't want that.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SP.NET LOGIN CONTROL WHEN MY LOGIN.ASPX IS NOT AT THE ROOT OF MY APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Use the LoginUrl property for the forms item?</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;authentication mode="Forms"&gt;<br/>  &lt;forms defaultUrl="~/Default.aspx" loginUrl="~/login.aspx" timeout="1440" &gt;&lt;/forms&gt;<br/>&lt;/authentication&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      METHOD NAME TO CUSTOM SERVER CONTROL IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you want to be able to pass a method in the ASPX markup you need to use the Browsable attribute in your code on the event.</p><br/><br/><p>VB.NET</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;Browsable(True)&gt; Public Event InitializeStuffCallback<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>C#</p><br/><br/><pre><code>[Browsable(true)]<br/>public event EventHandler InitializeStuffCallback;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Reference:<br/><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/tk67c2t8.aspx" rel="nofollow">Design-Time Attributes for Components</a> and <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.componentmodel.browsableattribute.aspx" rel="nofollow">BrowsableAttribute Class</a></p><br/><br/><p>All the events, properties, or whatever need to be in the code-behind of the control with the browsable attribute to make it so you can change it in the tag code.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      KEEP MY LOGIN.ASPX PAGE S RETURNURL PARAMET FROM OVERRID MY ASP.NET LOGIN CONTROL S DESTINATIONPAGEURL PROPERTI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I found the answer on <a href="http://www.velocityreviews.com/forums/t367373-remove-quotreturnurlquot-from-url.html" rel="nofollow">Velocity Reviews</a>.  I handled the LoggedIn event to force a redirection to the DestinationPageUrl page.</p><br/><br/><pre><br/>    Public Partial Class Login<br/>        Inherits System.Web.UI.Page<br/><br/>        Protected Sub Login1_LoggedIn(ByVal sender As Object, _  <br/>                ByVal e As System.EventArgs) Handles Login1.LoggedIn<br/>            'overrides ReturnUrl page parameter<br/>            Response.Redirect(Login1.DestinationPageUrl)<br/>        End Sub<br/><br/>    End Class<br/></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ELEG SEMANT CSS WITH ASP.NET STILL A PIPE DREAM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The easiest way to generate elegant HTML and CSS is to use MVC framework, where you have much more control over HTML generation than with Web Forms.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ACTIV DIRECTORI DATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>In order to take control over the properties that you want to be cached you can call 'RefreshCache()' passing the properties that you want to hang around:</p><br/><br/><pre class="lang-c# prettyprint-override"><code>System.DirectoryServices.DirectoryEntry entry = new System.DirectoryServices.DirectoryEntry();               <br/><br/>// Push the property values from AD back to cache.<br/><br/>entry.RefreshCache(new string[] {"cn", "www" });<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ONRES FROM ASP.NET CONTENT PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Place the following in your content page:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/><br/>// here is a cross-browser compatible way of connecting <br/>// handlers to events, in case you don't have one<br/>function attachEventHandler(element, eventToHandle, eventHandler) {<br/>    if(element.attachEvent) {<br/>       element.attachEvent(eventToHandle, eventHandler);<br/>    } else if(element.addEventListener) {<br/>       element.addEventListener(eventToHandle.replace("on", ""), eventHandler, false);<br/>    } else {<br/>    element[eventToHandle] = eventHandler;<br/>  }<br/>}<br/><br/>attachEventHandler(window, "onresize", function() {<br/>    // the code you want to run when the browser is resized<br/>});<br/><br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>That code should give you the basic idea of what you need to do. Hopefully you are using a library that already has code to help you write up event handlers and such.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AJAX FRAMEWORK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://jquery.com/" rel="nofollow">jQuery</a> is, well, the shizznit, IMHO. After I bought "<a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=jQuery+in+Action&amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;aq=f&amp;oq=" rel="nofollow">jQuery In Action</a>", I realized there was no going back. There are a ton of ASP.NET developers (including those behind this very site) out there who use it if you are trying to figure out how to get rocking &amp; rolling, right away.</p><br/><br/><p>I would check out the following blogs:</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <ol><br/>  <li><a href="http://west-wind.com/Weblog/" rel="nofollow">Rick Strahl's Web Log</a><br/>  <br></li><br/>  <li>The ever talented Scott Guthrie mentioned <a href="http://mattberseth.com/" rel="nofollow">Matt Berseth</a><br/>  <br></li><br/>  <li>And my personal favorite Dave Ward's blog <a href="http://encosia.com/" rel="nofollow">Encosia</a>. (I think <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/60/dave-ward" rel="nofollow">this is his StackOverflow profile</a>.)</li><br/>  </ol><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>However, of course there are plenty of other libraries out there. In the end I really like JS Libraries because it frequently comes down to code re-use. Don't roll the same JS functionality from scratch over-and-over. Also, most of these community previewed products have had a helluva lot more eyes on the code than anything you roll yourself (probably). </p><br/><br/><p>With all of that said, I also highly suggest checking out these frameworks:</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <ol><br/>  <li><a href="http://extjs.com/" rel="nofollow">Ext JS</a><br/>  <br></li><br/>  <li><a href="http://www.mochikit.com/" rel="nofollow">MochiKit</a><br/>  <br></li><br/>  <li>Also check out Omar Al Zabir's (founder of <a href="http://www.pageflakes.com/" rel="nofollow">PageFlakes.com</a>) <a href="http://www.codeproject.com/KB/ajax/MakingGoogleIG.aspx" rel="nofollow">CodeProject article</a> and <a href="http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0596510500" rel="nofollow">his book</a> for cool stuff you can do with the ASP.NET AJAX Framework.</li><br/>  </ol><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>I believe Ext JS comes out of the box with ColdFusion installations these days, but I have been happy with the few .NET projects I dropped it into as well.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RADIOBUTTON VISIBL INSID A RADIOBUTTONLIST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Under the hood, you can access the attributes of the item and assign it a CSS style.</p><br/><br/><p>So you should be able to then programmatically assign it by specifying:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>RadioButtonList.Items(1).CssStyle.Add("visibility", "hidden")<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>and get the job done.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PATTERN IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Dirty tracking is the normal way to handle this, I think. Something like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>class MyObject {<br/>  public string SomeValue { <br/>     get { return _someValue; }<br/>     set { <br/>       if (value != SomeValue) {<br/>          IsDirty = true;<br/>          _someValue = value;<br/>       }<br/>  }<br/><br/>  public bool IsDirty {<br/>     get;<br/>     private set;<br/>  }<br/><br/>  void SaveToDatabase() {<br/>     base.SaveToDatabase(); <br/>     IsDirty = false;<br/>  }<br/>}<br/><br/>myoldObject = new MyObject { someValue = "old value" };<br/>cache.Insert("myObjectKey", myoldObject);<br/>myNewObject = cache.Get("myObjectKey");<br/>myNewObject.someValue = "new value";<br/>if(myNewObject.IsDirty)<br/>   myNewObject.SaveToDatabase();<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RECOMMEND AN ASP.NET CONTROL LIBRARI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'll second the vote for <a href="http://www.telerik.com" rel="nofollow">Telerik</a>. Their controls for the most part "just work" and their support has been excellent. I primarily use their forums and I still receive a response within a day (unlike some other vendors who barely seem to notice that they've even got a forum). </p><br/><br/><p>It also feels like they've actually spent time trying out a lot of the ways customer's will use their controls. The documentation and support reflects it. They aren't perfect, though. One issue that they had in the past, and that they've addressed in the latest releases (what they were calling their "Prometheus" controls, now just "Rad Controls for ASP.NET AJAX") is the performance of the controls. In previous releases they were definitely a bit sluggish (I'm thinking specifically of their RadGrid and RadEditor). Now they're noticeably faster (esp. the RadEditor - it loads MUCH faster).</p><br/><br/><p>Overall I wouldn't think twice of recommending them.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VS. SILVERLIGHT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>It is mainly going to be an iternal<br/>  product so browsers are not an issue.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>You still have not written a <em>proper</em> description about the nature of your application. It is difficult to assess which technology is a good fit without first knowing well enough the domain the application is being applied to, and the problems it is designed to solve.</p><br/><br/><p>In general, Microsoft is positioning these array of presentation technologies on the "<strong>Reach vs Rich</strong>" continuum. You have "plain old" HTML and Javascript on one end, acceptable by the most number of client machines out there, and the ultimate full-blown WPF on the other side where limited number of machines can handle. You did mention this to be an internal app, so WPF via XBAP or ClickOnce are also possible.</p><br/><br/><p>So the scale would align this way: (reach) ASP.NET, AJAX, Silverlight, WPF (rich).</p><br/><br/><p>So the question is just how rich you want/need it to be for the users until it hurts the deployment base? Frankly if all you fetch are forms and tabular data and statistics then regular ASP.NET web forms are just fine. If you want on-the-fly resizable graphs and client-side interactive with back-end WCF web services Silverlight can do that. If you want even more powerful graphical rendering than WPF via the remote deployment options is your bet.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EXACTLI DO YOU CONFIGUR HTTPONLYCOOKI IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you're using ASP.NET 2.0 or greater, you can turn it on in the Web.config file. In the &lt;system.web&gt; section, add the following line:</p><br/><br/><p>&lt;httpCookies httpOnlyCookies="true"/&gt;</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ONCURR LOGIN IN A WEB FARM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You could look at using a distributed cache system like <a href="http://www.danga.com/memcached/" rel="nofollow">memcached</a></p><br/><br/><p>It would solve this problem pretty well (it's MUCH faster than a database), and is also excellent for caching pretty much anything else too</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WEB.CONFIG FROM .NET 2.0 TO 3.5
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There is a good description of the 3.5 web.config available here:<br/><a href="http://www.4guysfromrolla.com/articles/121207-1.aspx">http://www.4guysfromrolla.com/articles/121207-1.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>The assemblies and config sections are important because they tell the runtime to use the new 3.5 dlls instead of the 2.0 dlls</p><br/><br/><p>The codedom section tells the compiler to use 3.5</p><br/><br/><p>If your not using ASP.Net ajax you can probably skip the rest.  I've never tested that though.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VS2008 COPI WEB SITE FROM COMMAND LINE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Would this help you get started?</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/f735abw9.aspx" rel="nofollow">Walkthrough: Deploying an ASP.NET Web Application Using XCOPY</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      THE CANCEL BUTTON ON AN ASP.NET CHANGEPASSWORD CONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Set CancelButtonStyle.CssClass to something like "hiddenItem" and set the CSS to "display:none".</p><br/><br/><p>Otherwise you can convert the control to a template and simply delete away the cancel-button manually. When you click the control in Design-mode in Visual Studio, you get a little arrow with options and one of them is "Convert to Template".</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ING INTERCEPT HTTPCONTEXT.CURRENT.REQUEST.QUERYSTR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Without using reflection, the simplest way to do it would be to use the RewritePath function on the current HttpContext object in order to modify the querystring. </p><br/><br/><p>Using an <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ihttpmodule.aspx" rel="nofollow">IHttpModule</a>, it might look something like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>context.RewritePath(context.Request.Path, context.Request.PathInfo, newQueryStringHere!);<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Hope this helps!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USER CONTROL KNOW ABOUT CSS CLASS IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's what I did:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;link rel="Stylesheet" type="text/css" href="Stylesheet.css" id="style" runat="server" visible="false" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>It fools Visual Studio into thinking you've added a stylesheet to the page but it doesn't get rendered.</p><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>Here's an even more concise way to do this with multiple references;</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;% if (false) { %&gt;<br/>    &lt;link rel="Stylesheet" type="text/css" href="Stylesheet.css" /&gt;<br/>    &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="js/jquery-1.2.6.js" /&gt;<br/>&lt;% } %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>As seen in <a href="http://haacked.com/archive/2008/11/21/combining-jquery-form-validation-and-ajax-submission-with-asp.net.aspx" rel="nofollow">this blog post</a> from Phil Haack.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FROM ELMAH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You need the ErrorMail httpModule.</p><br/><br/><p>add this line inside the &lt;httpModules&gt; section</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;add name="ErrorMail" type="Elmah.ErrorMailModule, Elmah" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>If your using a remote SMTP server (which it looks like you are) you don't need SMTP on the server.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FORM S ACTION IN .NET 3.5 SP1 CAUS ERROR WHEN COMPIL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://john-sheehan.com/blog/index.php/less-code-is-fun-aspnet-35-sp1-removes-need-for-control-adapter-when-using-url-rewriting/" rel="nofollow">.NET 3.5 SP1 tries to use the action="" attribute</a> (.NET 3.5 RTM did not). So, when you deploy, your code is attempting to set the HtmlForm.Action property and failing, as the System.Web.dll on the deploy target is RTM and does not have a setter on the property.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ENTIR PAGE REFRESH EVEN THOUGH GRIDVIEW IS IN AN UPDAT PANEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Several months later this problem was fixed. The project I was working in was a previous v1.1 which was converted with 2.0. However, in the web.config this line remained:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;xhtmlConformance mode="Legacy"/&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>When it was commented out all of the bugs that we seemed to have with the ajax control toolkit disappeared</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BUILT IN WAY IN .NET AJAX TO MANUAL SERIAL AN OBJECT TO A JSON STRING
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This should do the trick</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Dim jsonSerialiser As New System.Web.Script.Serialization.JavaScriptSerializer<br/>Dim jsonString as String = jsonSerialiser.Serialize(yourObject)<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      QUIREDFIELD VALID IS PREVENT ANOTH FORM FROM SUBMIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Are you using ValidationGroups?  Try assigning each control with a validation group as well as the validator that you want to use.  Something like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;asp:TextBox ID="txt1" ValidationGroup="Group1" ruant="server" /&gt;<br/>&lt;asp:RequiredFieldValidator ID="rfv1" ... ValidationGroup="Group1" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Note, if a button doesn't specify a validation group it will validate all controls that aren't assigned to a validation group.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BUILD AN APPLIC USE A SQL SERVER DATABAS FILE ( MDF ) BE A TERRIBL IDEA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've long since completed the project which prompted this question, but recently I've had another project come along with very minor data requirements, so I spent some more time experimenting with this.</p><br/><br/><p>I had assumed that Sql Server Express required licensing fees to deploy, but this is not in fact the case. According to Microsoft's website, you are free to use it with certain restrictions:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Maximum database size: 4 GB</li><br/><li>Maximum memory used: 1 GB</li><br/><li>Maximum CPUs used: 1 (complete procs, not cores)</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>Sql Server Compact is a bad idea for web applications because it requires a hack to make it work, and it isn't built for the concurrent access you'd need for the web. But if your application can fit within the modest limitations of Sql Server Express, it works pretty well. And since it speaks regular T-SQL like its larger siblings, you can use Linq to SQL with it.</p><br/><br/><p>I hear that <a href="http://twitter.com/migueldeicaza/status/2368465000" rel="nofollow">Linq to Sql support is now in the Mono trunk</a> for the 2.6 release, so L2S' tight-coupling to Sql Server will likely be a moot point in the near future. I will either end up porting my code to use Mono's superior Linq to Sql implementation on the db of my choice, or go <a href="http://subsonicproject.com/" rel="nofollow">another route entirely</a> (SubSonic has improved by leaps and bounds since I last tried it). But for the time being, Sql Server Express is a valid choice for very small database-driven apps.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BYPASS FORM AUTHENT AUTO REDIRECT TO LOGIN HOW TO
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Might be a kludge (and may not even work) but on your Login page see if <code>Request.QueryString["ReturnUrl"] != null</code> and if so set <code>Response.StatusCode = 401</code>.</p><br/><br/><p>Bear in mind that you'll still need to get your console app to authenticate somehow. You don't get HTTP basic auth for free: you have to roll your own, but there are plenty of implementations about.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IN WEB SERVIC LOCK DLL AND PREVENT PUBLISHING. WORKAROUND
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Using the IISReset command line tool will only restart IIS on the local machine, not on a remote server to which you are publishing.</p><br/><br/><p>Assuming that you are publishing to a Windows 2003 server, I'd suggest trying the slightly less drastic step of stopping and restarting the IIS AppPool in the web site or virtual folder in which the web service runs.  (That way you are not taking all sites that run on the target server offline.)  This too assumes that the web service runs in its own app pool.  Ideally it should, so you keep it isolated.</p><br/><br/><p>I'd recommend getting away from using the Publishing process and to look into using a Web Deployment Project.  Here is a post on ScottGu's blog detailing <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2005/11/06/429723.aspx" rel="nofollow" title="VS 2005 Web Deployment Projects">VS 2005 Web Deployment Projects</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>The advantage to the Web Deployment Project approach is that it provides you with all the power and capability of MSbuild, as it is really just a convenience wrapper around MSBuild.  Here's a post from the MSBuild team about <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/msbuild/archive/2005/10/12/480212.aspx" rel="nofollow">pre-build and post-build capabilities</a></p><br/><br/><p>Hope this helps.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A METHOD S OUTPUT TO A TEXTBOX VALU WITHOUT CODE BEHIND
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There's a couple of different expression types in .ASPX files. There's:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%= TextFromMethod %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>which simply reserves a literal control, and outputs the text at render time.</p><br/><br/><p>and then there's:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%# TextFromMethod %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>which is a databinding expression, evaluated when the control is DataBound(). There's also expression builders, like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%$ ConnectionStrings:Database %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>but that's not really important here....</p><br/><br/><p>So, the &lt;%= %> method won't work because it would try to insert a Literal into the .Text property...obviously, not what you want.</p><br/><br/><p>The &lt;%# %> method doesn't work because the TextBox isn't DataBound, nor are any of it's parents. If your TextBox was in a Repeater or GridView, then this method would work.</p><br/><br/><p>So - what to do? Just call TextBox.DataBind() at some point. Or, if you have more than 1 control, just call Page.DataBind() in your Page_Load.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Private Function Page_Load(sender as Object, e as EventArgs)<br/>   If Not IsPostback Then<br/>      Me.DataBind()<br/>   End If<br/>End Function<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      L ROOT WITH VISUAL STUDIO ASP.NET DEBUGG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>you can try this trick that Scott Guthrie posted on his blog <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2006/12/19/tip-trick-how-to-run-a-root-site-with-the-local-web-server-using-vs-2005-sp1.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2006/12/19/tip-trick-how-to-run-a-root-site-with-the-local-web-server-using-vs-2005-sp1.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>to cut to the fix: select your project/solution in solution explorer and then open the Properties tab like you would if you were editing a textbox. If you right click and go to "Property Pages" that is the wrong place. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      USER FROM EDIT PAGE BACK TO CALL PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I would store the referring URL using the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ui.control.viewstate.aspx" rel="nofollow">ViewState</a>. Storing this outside the scope of the page (i.e. in the Session state or cookie) may cause problems if more than one browser window is open.</p><br/><br/><p>The example below validates that the page was called internally (i.e. not requested directly) and bounces back to the referring page after the user submits their response.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public partial class _Default : System.Web.UI.Page<br/>{<br/>    protected void Page_Load(object sender, EventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        if (Request.UrlReferrer == null)<br/>        {<br/>            //Handle the case where the page is requested directly<br/>            throw new Exception("This page has been called without a referring page");<br/>        }<br/><br/>        if (!IsPostBack)<br/>        {   <br/>            ReturnUrl = Request.UrlReferrer.PathAndQuery;<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/><br/>    public string ReturnUrl<br/>    {<br/>        get { return ViewState["returnUrl"].ToString();  }<br/>        set { ViewState["returnUrl"] = value; }<br/>    }<br/><br/>    protected void btn_Click(object sender, EventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        //Do what you need to do to save the page<br/>        //...<br/><br/>        //Go back to calling page<br/>        Response.Redirect(ReturnUrl, true);<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REDIRECT ON LOGIN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The <code>SetAuthCookie</code> allows you to issue the auth cookie but retain control over the navigation. After that method is called you can run your logic to do a typical ASP.NET redirect to wherever you want.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BETWEEN PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't think you need to set up Java just to use a servlet for this. I would use AJAX and the database. I don't know ASP.NET but I PHP is similar in this case, being also basically "stateless". If you want to display some kind of asynchronous communication between two different users, say, from two different sessions, without a lot of refreshing (like chat), you can have the AJAX page constantly poll the database for new messages, and display them when they come in. You can also use AJAX to insert the new messages, giving the user read/write access to this messages data structure. Since the "other" user is doing the same thing, user A should see new messages pop up when user B types them in.</p><br/><br/><p>Is that what you mean?</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUTPUTCACH FOR WEBSIT WITHOUT RESTART APP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This should do the trick:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Private Sub Button1_Click(ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e As System.EventArgs)<br/><br/> Dim path As String<br/> path="/AbosoluteVirtualPath/OutputCached.aspx"<br/> HttpResponse.RemoveOutputCacheItem(path)<br/><br/>End Sub<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      THE INSTAL ASP.NET VERSION OF HOST FROM A WEB PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Thanks!</p><br/><br/><p>I just dropped &lt;%=Environment.Version%> on a page and got 2.0.50727.3053</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ASP.NET VERSION
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.NET_Framework_version_list" rel="nofollow">List of .NET Framework versions</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SERVER SID EVENT TO EXTEND CONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>After plenty of reading up on extender controls and javascript, I've cobbled together a solution that seems to be working so far.</p><br/><br/><p>The main trick was getting the necessary postback code from server-side to the client-side behavior script. I did this by using an ExtenderControlProperty which is set in the control's OnPreRender function, and then eval'd in the behavior script. The rest was basic event handling stuff.</p><br/><br/><p>So now my extender control's .cs file looks something like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public class DelayedSubmitExtender : ExtenderControlBase, IPostBackEventHandler<br/>{<br/>    // This is where we'll give the behavior script the necessary code for the <br/>    // postback event<br/>    protected override void OnPreRender(EventArgs e)<br/>    {<br/>        string postback = Page.ClientScript.GetPostBackEventReference(this, "DelayedSubmit") + ";";<br/>        PostBackEvent = postback;<br/>    }<br/><br/>    // This property matches up with a pair of get &amp; set functions in the behavior script<br/>    [ExtenderControlProperty]<br/>    public string PostBackEvent<br/>    {<br/>        get<br/>        {<br/>            return GetPropertyValue&lt;string&gt;("PostBackEvent", "");<br/>        }<br/>        set<br/>        {<br/>            SetPropertyValue&lt;string&gt;("PostBackEvent", value);<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/><br/>    // The event handling stuff<br/>    public event EventHandler Submit;  // Our event<br/><br/>    protected void OnSubmit(EventArgs e)  // Called to raise the event<br/>    {<br/>        if (Submit != null)<br/>        {<br/>            Submit(this, e);<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/><br/>    public void RaisePostBackEvent(string eventArgument)  // From IPostBackEventHandler<br/>    {<br/>        if (eventArgument == "DelayedSubmit")<br/>        {<br/>            OnSubmit(new EventArgs());<br/>        }<br/>    }<br/><br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>and my behavior script looks something like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>DelayedSubmitBehavior = function(element) {<br/>    DelayedSubmitBehavior.initializeBase(this, [element]);<br/><br/>    this._postBackEvent = null; // Stores the script required for the postback<br/>}<br/><br/>DelayedSubmitBehavior.prototype = {<br/>    // Delayed submit code removed for brevity, but normally this would be where <br/>    // initialize, dispose, and client-side event handlers would go<br/><br/>    // This is the client-side part of the PostBackEvent property<br/>    get_PostBackEvent: function() {<br/>        return this._postBackEvent;<br/>    },<br/>    set_PostBackEvent: function(value) {<br/>        this._postBackEvent = value;<br/>    }<br/><br/>    // This is the client-side event handler where the postback is initiated from<br/>    _onTimerTick: function(sender, eventArgs) {<br/>        // The following line evaluates the string var as javascript,<br/>        // which will cause the desired postback<br/>        eval(this._postBackEvent);<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Now the server-side event can be handled the same way you'd handle an event on any other control.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      IS APPDOMAIN RECYCL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well, I think the thread was getting smoothly to a final conclusion, but in the end, it was otherwise.</p><br/><br/><p>I'll try to answer the question based on my understanding and levearing what i've just read about in other web sites.</p><br/><br/><p>First of all, I myself try to avoid the term recycle other than for Application Pools since this may render someone confused. Now, getting to process, pools and AppDomain, I see the picture as follows:</p><br/><br/><p>An Application Pool is, in short, a region of memory that is mantained up and running by a process called W3WP.exe, aka Worker Process. Recycling an Application Pool means bringing that process down, eliminating it from memory and then originating a brand new Worker Process, with a newly assigned process ID.</p><br/><br/><p>Regarding Application Domains, I see it as subsets of memory regions, within the aforementioned region that plays the role of a container. In other words, the process in memory, W3WP.exe in this case, is a macro memory region for applications that stores subset regions, called Application Domains. Having said that, one process in memory may store different Application Domains, one for each application that is assigned to run within a given Application Pool.</p><br/><br/><p>When it comes to recycling, as I initially told, it's something that I myself reserve only for Application Pools. For AppDomains, I prefer using the term 'restart', in order to avoid misconception. Based on this, restarting a AppDomain means starting over agiven application with the newly added settings, such as refreshing the existing configuration. That happens within the boundaries of that subregion of memory, called AppDomain, that ultimately lies within the process associated with a respective Application Pool. Those new settings may come from files such as </p><br/><br/><p>web.config,<br/>machine.config,<br/>global.asax,<br/>Bin directory,<br/>App_Code,</p><br/><br/><p>and there may be others.</p><br/><br/><p>AppDomain are isolated from each other, what makes total sense. If not so, if changes to a web.config, let's say, of application 1, requited recycle of the pool, all other applications assigned to that pool would get restarted, what was definitely not desired by Microsoft and by anyone else.</p><br/><br/><p>Summarizing my point, </p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Process (W3WP.exe)<br/><ul><br/><li>AppDomain 1</li><br/><li>AppDomain 2</li><br/><li>AppDomain 3</li><br/><li>AppDomain n</li><br/></ul></li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>n = the number of assigned applications to the Application Pool managed by the given W3WP.exe</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Processes are memory regions isolated from one another</li><br/><li>AppDomains are submemory regions isolated from one another, within the same process</li><br/><li>Global IIS settings changes may require Application Pool recycle (killing and starting a new Worker Process, W3WP.exe)</li><br/><li>Application-wide settings changes AppDomains concerns, and they may get restarted after changes in some specific files such as the ones outline above</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>For futher information, I recommend:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/david.wang/archive/2006/03/12/thoughts-on-iis-configuration-changes-and-when-it-takes-effect.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://blogs.msdn.com/b/david.wang/archive/2006/03/12/thoughts-on-iis-configuration-changes-and-when-it-takes-effect.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/302110/what-causes-an-application-pool-in-iis-to-recycle">What causes an application pool in IIS to recycle?</a></p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/tess/archive/2006/08/02/asp-net-case-study-lost-session-variables-and-appdomain-recycles.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://blogs.msdn.com/b/tess/archive/2006/08/02/asp-net-case-study-lost-session-variables-and-appdomain-recycles.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>Regards from Brazil!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FILE DOWNLOAD IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Does this help:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.west-wind.com/weblog/posts/76293.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.west-wind.com/weblog/posts/76293.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><pre><code>Response.ContentType = "application/octet-stream";<br/>Response.AppendHeader("Content-Disposition","attachment; filename=logfile.txt");<br/>Response.TransmitFile( Server.MapPath("~/logfile.txt") );<br/>Response.End();<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Response.TransmitFile is the accepted way of sending large files, instead of Response.WriteFile.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PREVENT THE II DEFAULT SITE WEB.CONFIG FILE BE INHERIT BY VIRTUAL DIRECTORI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've found the answer.  Wrap the HttpModule section in location tags and set the inheritInChildApplications attribute to false.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;location path="." inheritInChildApplications="false"&gt;<br/>  &lt;system.web&gt;<br/>    &lt;httpModules&gt;<br/>      &lt;add type="MDL.BexWebControls.Charts.ChartStreamHandler,Charts" name="ChartStreamHandler"/&gt;<br/>    &lt;/httpModules&gt;<br/>  &lt;/system.web&gt;<br/>&lt;/location&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Now any virtual directories will not inherit the settings in this location section.</p><br/><br/><p>@GateKiller This isn't another website, its a virtual directory so inheritance does occur.</p><br/><br/><p>@petrich I've had hit and miss results using <code>&lt;remove /&gt;</code>.  I have to remember to add it to every virtual directory which is a pain.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EVENT LOG VIA A WEB INTERFAC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>No, but there are two solutions I would recommend:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><p>Adiscon <a href="http://www.eventreporter.com/en/" rel="nofollow">EventLogger</a> is a third-party product that will send your Windows EventLog to a SQL database. You can either send all events or create filters. Of course, once the events are in a SQL database, you can use any of the usual tools to create a web interface.</p></li><br/><li><p>You can use ASP.NET's <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms998306.aspx" rel="nofollow">HealthMonitoring</a> configuration section to configure .NET to send all ASP.NET-related events directly to a SQL database. This covers exceptions, heartbeats, and a host of other event types. The <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.management.sqlwebeventprovider.aspx" rel="nofollow">SqlWebEventProvider</a> is a cinch to setup.</p></li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      .NET WRAPPER FOR GOOGL MAP OR YAHOO MAP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'm the creator of one of the most important GoogleMaps controls for ASP.NET.</p><br/><br/><p>You can find it on <a href="http://en.googlemaps.subgurim.net" rel="nofollow">googlemaps.subgurim.net</a>. It's translated to 15 languages, has more than 25.000 downloads, a very active forum, code gallery, icon gallery, etc.</p><br/><br/><p>It's great for novel developers and advanced ones. You can done almost everything that can be done with the javascript API, plus a lot of extra features.</p><br/><br/><p>Of course, it has a great documentation.</p><br/><br/><p>Try it!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PAGE POSTBACK DOE N T WORK FOR CLIENT SID ENABL BUTTON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It looks like when the button is disabled .Net doesn't bother adding the necessary bits to handle the cross page postback on the client, so they will be missing when the button is enable client-side.</p><br/><br/><p>I guess one solution would be to have the button enabled to start with (so that .Net adds the cross page postback controls) and then disable it using javascript as soon as the control loads on the client. But this sounds a bit clunky.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CACH WITH .NET 2.0 +
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There is also <a href="http://www.alachisoft.com/ncache/" rel="nofollow">NCache</a> as another tool in addition to Velocity and memcached ports.<br/>As for strategies you will need to think about what <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/38548/distributed-caching-with-net-20#38556" rel="nofollow">@Unsliced</a> is talking about because the strategy is different from the tool.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      .NET 3.5 SP1 REQUIR ON THE SERVER TO USE DYNAM DATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Yes, SP1 is required.</p><br/><br/><p>There are several bits of SP1 that Dynamic Data uses, notably the ASP.NET routing extensions and the new data annotation classes in System.ComponentModel.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DISPLAY FORMAT SQL 2005 MONEY DATA TYPE IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>this.txtPayment.Text = string.Format("{0:c}", dr[Payment"].ToString());</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DROPDOWNLIST ERROR DROPDOWNLIST1 HA A SELECTEDVALU WHICH IS INVALID BECAUS IT DOE NOT EXIST IN THE LIST OF ITEM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'm not sure it's the same issue, but I had a similar sounding issue with trying to bind a DropDownList that I wanted to contain in a GridView.     When I looked around I found a lot of people asking similar questions, but no robust solutions.  I did read conflicting reports about whether you could intercept databinding, etc events. I tried most of them but I couldn'f find a way of intercepting or pre-empting the error.</p><br/><br/><p>I ended up creating a subclass of the ddl, intercepting the error from there hacking a fix.</p><br/><br/><p>Not tidy but it worked for my needs.  I put the code up on my blog in case it's of help. <a href="http://david.safitech.com/?p=53" rel="nofollow">link text</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ONTROL CAN NOT BE REFERENC IN CODE BEHIND IN VISUAL STUDIO 2008
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>try clearing your local VS cache. find your project and delete the folder. the folder is created by VS for what reason I honestly don't understand. but I've had several occasions where clearing it and doing a re-build fixes things... hope this is all that you need as well.</p><br/><br/><p>here</p><br/><br/><pre><code>%Temp%\VWDWebCache<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>and possibly here</p><br/><br/><pre><code>%LocalAppData%\Microsoft\WebsiteCache<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      M SECUR FTP REPLAC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>the question has three subquestions:</p><br/><br/><p>1) choosing the secure transfer protocol</p><br/><br/><p>The secure version of old FTP exists - it's called FTP/SSL (plain old FTP over SSL encrypted channel). Maybe you can still use your old deployment infrastructure - just check whether it supports the FTPS or FTP/SSL.</p><br/><br/><p>You can check details about FTP, FTP/SSL and SFTP differences at <a href="http://www.rebex.net/secure-ftp.net/" rel="nofollow">http://www.rebex.net/secure-ftp.net/</a> page.</p><br/><br/><p>2) SFTP or FTP/SSL server for Windows</p><br/><br/><p>When you choose whether to use SFTP or FTPS you have to deploy the proper server. For FTP/SSL we use the Gene6 (<a href="http://www.g6ftpserver.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.g6ftpserver.com/</a>) on several servers without problems. There is plenty of FTP/SSL Windows servers so use whatever you want. The situation is a bit more complicated with SFTP server for Windows - there is only a few working implementations. The Bitvise WinHTTPD looks quite promising (<a href="http://www.bitvise.com/winsshd" rel="nofollow">http://www.bitvise.com/winsshd</a>).</p><br/><br/><p>3) Internet File Transfer Component for ASP.NET</p><br/><br/><p>Last part of the solution is secure file transfer from asp.net. There is several components on the market. I would recommend the <a href="http://www.rebex.net/file-transfer-pack/" rel="nofollow">Rebex File Transfer Pack</a> - it supports both FTP (and FTP/SSL) and SFTP (SSH File Transfer).</p><br/><br/><p>Following code shows how to upload a file to the server via SFTP. The code is taken from our <a href="http://www.rebex.net/sftp.net/tutorial-sftp.aspx#upload-download" rel="nofollow">Rebex SFTP tutorial page</a>.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>// create client, connect and log in <br/>Sftp client = new Sftp();<br/>client.Connect(hostname);<br/>client.Login(username, password);<br/><br/>// upload the 'test.zip' file to the current directory at the server <br/>client.PutFile(@"c:\data\test.zip", "test.zip");<br/><br/>// upload the 'index.html' file to the specified directory at the server <br/>client.PutFile(@"c:\data\index.html", "/wwwroot/index.html");<br/><br/>// download the 'test.zip' file from the current directory at the server <br/>client.GetFile("test.zip", @"c:\data\test.zip");<br/><br/>// download the 'index.html' file from the specified directory at the server <br/>client.GetFile("/wwwroot/index.html", @"c:\data\index.html");<br/><br/>// upload a text using a MemoryStream <br/>string message = "Hello from Rebex SFTP for .NET!";<br/>byte[] data = System.Text.Encoding.Default.GetBytes(message);<br/>System.IO.MemoryStream ms = new System.IO.MemoryStream(data);<br/>client.PutFile(ms, "message.txt");<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Martin</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LOCK CACH IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's the basic pattern:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Check the cache for the value, return if its available</li><br/><li>If the value is not in the cache, then implement a lock</li><br/><li>Inside the lock, check the cache again, you might have been blocked</li><br/><li>Perform the value look up and cache it</li><br/><li>Release the lock</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>In code, it looks like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>private static object ThisLock = new object();<br/><br/>public string GetFoo()<br/>{<br/><br/>  // try to pull from cache here<br/><br/>  lock (ThisLock)<br/>  {<br/>    // cache was empty before we got the lock, check again inside the lock<br/><br/>    // cache is still empty, so retreive the value here<br/><br/>    // store the value in the cache here<br/>  }<br/><br/>  // return the cached value here<br/><br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DEBUG SERVER SIDE OF A WEB APPLIC WITH VISUAL STUDIO 2008
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>First, this is MUCH easier if both the server and your workstation are on the same domain (the server needs access to connect to your machine). In your C:\Program Files\Microsoft Visual Studio 9.0\Common7\IDE\Remote Debugger\x86 (or x64, or ia64) directory are the files you need to copy to your server. There are different versions between Visual Studio versions, so make sure they match on the client and server side. On the server, fire up msvsmon. It will say something like "Msvsmon started a new server named xxx@yyyy". This is the name you'll use in Visual Studio to connect to this server. You can go into Tools > Options to set the server name and to set the authentication mode (hopefully Windows Authentication) - BTW No Authentication doesn't work for managed code. </p><br/><br/><p>On the client side, open up Visual Studio and load the solution you're going to debug. Then go to Debug > Attach to Process. In the "Qualifier" field enter the name of the server as you saw it appear earlier. Click on the Select button and select the type of code you want to debug, then hit OK. Hopefully you'll see a list of the processes on the server that you can attach to (you should also see on the server that the debugging monitor just said you connected). Find the process to attach to (start up the app if necessary). If it's an ASP.NET website, you'd select w3wp.exe, then hit Attach. Set your breakpoints and hopefully you're now remotely debugging the code.</p><br/><br/><p>AFAIK - the VMWare option lets you start up code inside of a VM but debug it from your workstation. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FULL URL OF THE PAGE I AM ON IN C #
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I usually use <code>Request.Url.ToString()</code> to get the full url (including querystring), no concatenation required.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      YOU STORE YOUR DATABAS CONNECTIONSTR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I wouldn't cache the connection object, that will defeat the built-in connection pooling -- ADO.NET will handle connections (assuming you instantiate and close them) efficiently by itself.</p><br/><br/><p>As far as the connection string itself, you shouldn't need to cache it if you load it from connection -- the connection manager object in the .NET 2.0 framework loads the config into memory when you first access it, so there are no repeat trips to the file system.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ACCESS STRATEGI IN A MULTI THREAD ENVIRON ( WEB APP )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is the code that I use to make sure a file is not locked by another process.  It's not 100% foolproof, but it gets the job done most of the time:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>    /// &lt;summary&gt;<br/>    /// Blocks until the file is not locked any more.<br/>    /// &lt;/summary&gt;<br/>    /// &lt;param name="fullPath"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;<br/>    bool WaitForFile(string fullPath)<br/>    {<br/>        int numTries = 0;<br/>        while (true)<br/>        {<br/>            ++numTries;<br/>            try<br/>            {<br/>                // Attempt to open the file exclusively.<br/>                using (FileStream fs = new FileStream(fullPath,<br/>                    FileMode.Open, FileAccess.ReadWrite, <br/>                    FileShare.None, 100))<br/>                {<br/>                    fs.ReadByte();<br/><br/>                    // If we got this far the file is ready<br/>                    break;<br/>                }<br/>            }<br/>            catch (Exception ex)<br/>            {<br/>                Log.LogWarning(<br/>                   "WaitForFile {0} failed to get an exclusive lock: {1}", <br/>                    fullPath, ex.ToString());<br/><br/>                if (numTries &gt; 10)<br/>                {<br/>                    Log.LogWarning(<br/>                        "WaitForFile {0} giving up after 10 tries", <br/>                        fullPath);<br/>                    return false;<br/>                }<br/><br/>                // Wait for the lock to be released<br/>                System.Threading.Thread.Sleep(500);<br/>            }<br/>        }<br/><br/>        Log.LogTrace("WaitForFile {0} returning true after {1} tries",<br/>            fullPath, numTries);<br/>        return true;<br/>    }<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Obviously you can tweak the timeouts and retries to suit your application.  I use this to process huge FTP files that take a while to be written.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VIEWSTAT ON POSTBACK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><code>Page_Load</code> fires before <code>btnSubmit_Click</code>.</p><br/><br/><p>If you want to do something after your postback events have fired use <code>Page_PreRender</code>.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>//this will work because YourName has now been set by the click event<br/>protected void Page_PreRender(object sender, EventArgs e)<br/>{<br/>    if (Page.IsPostBack)<br/>        lblInfo.InnerText = String.Format("Hello {0} at {1}!", YourName, DateTime.Now.ToLongTimeString());<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>The basic order goes:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Page init fires (init cannot access ViewState)</li><br/><li>ViewState is read</li><br/><li>Page load fires</li><br/><li>Any events fire</li><br/><li>PreRender fires</li><br/><li>Page renders</li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DISPLAY IN ASPX PAGE ON SHAREPOINT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>So in that case I would wrap it up in a feature and deploy it via a solution. This way I think you will avoid the issue you are seeing. This is especially useful if you plan to use this functionality within other sites too. </p><br/><br/><p>You can also embed web parts directly in the page, much like you do a WebControl, thereby avoiding any gallery clutter.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CUSTOM MEMBERSHIPPROVID WITHOUT A LOGIN CONTROL IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>After validation is successful, you need to sign in the user, by calling FormsAuthentication.Authenticate: <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.security.formsauthentication.authenticate.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.security.formsauthentication.authenticate.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>EDIT: It is FormsAuthentication.SetAuthCookie:<br/><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/twk5762b.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/twk5762b.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>Also, to redirect the user back where he wanted to go, call: FormsAuthentication.RedirectFromLoginPage: <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.security.formsauthentication.redirectfromloginpage.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.security.formsauthentication.redirectfromloginpage.aspx</a> </p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.security.formsauthentication.authenticate.aspx" rel="nofollow">link text</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TABLESORT PLUGIN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This is a common layout problem in IE.  If you are using CSS to style the columns width, also add the column widths to the td tags.  Set the first column to a percentage that will try to suck up most of the space, like 50% or something.  The first column width will take everything that it can and the other columns will abide by their static width.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      RADIT ASP .NET WEB FORM VS MVC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is the great thing about MVC.  It works closer to the base of the framework than normal ASP.NET Web Forms.  So by using MVC and understanding it, you will have a better understanding of how WebForms work.  The problem with WebForms is there is a lot of magic and about 6 years of trying to make the Web work like Windows Forms, so you have the control tree hierarchy and everything translated to the Web.  With MVC you get the core with out the WinForm influence.</p><br/><br/><p>So start with MVC, and you will easily be able to move in to WebForms if needed.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A FOLDER FROM SOURC CONTROL IN AN ASP.NET WEBSIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think you've found one of the main reasons MS went back to projects in VS2008 and in MVC.</p><br/><br/><p>It's been a long time since I've used VSS (mainly because it's really out of date now), but most source providers let you exclude files and folders as a setting of the provider, rather than the project under control.</p><br/><br/><p>If you can switch to a Web Project rather than a WebSite then do so, otherwise I'd look at updating your source control provider, as this sort of exclusion is easy with Vault, CSV, SVN, Git, VSTS and so on (to name but a few).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VISUAL STUDIO
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper/" rel="nofollow">Resharper</a></strong> is definitely a great tool.  It has a moderate learning curve but is easy to pick up for some simple things and add mastery later.  It is a good price for students and kinda expensive for the rest of us.  Resharper is similar to CodeRush, but seems to have a larger following.</p><br/><br/><p><strong><a href="http://www.visualstudiogallery.com/ExtensionDetails.aspx?ExtensionID=df3f0c30-3d37-4e06-9ef8-3bff3508be31" rel="nofollow">PowerCommands</a></strong> is a great set of add-ons that comes free from Microsoft.  Things like "Open in Windows Explorer", "Command Prompt Here", and Copy/Paste references.  </p><br/><br/><p>A discussion regarding <strong>add-ins</strong> is <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2767/do-you-have-any-recommended-add-onsplugins-for-microsoft-visual-studio" rel="nofollow">floating around here somewhere</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>For straight-up customization, <strong>changing colors</strong> is fun, easy, and gives you a big bang for your buck.  I prefer a slightly personalized version of <a href="http://blog.wekeroad.com/2007/10/17/textmate-theme-for-visual-studio-take-2/" rel="nofollow">Rob Conery's TextMate theme for Visual Studio.</a>  Once you get colors you like, you can just <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/zbhkx167(VS.80).aspx" rel="nofollow">export the settings</a> and carry them with you wherever you go.</p><br/><br/><p>Related to colors and themes, the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=22e69ae4-7e40-4807-8a86-b3d36fab68d3&amp;displaylang=en" rel="nofollow"><strong>Consolas</strong> font pack</a> is pretty nifty and easy on the eye.</p><br/><br/><p>And like John recommends, a <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/20507/give-me-awesome-visual-studio-keyboard-short-cuts" rel="nofollow">mastery of <strong>keyboard shortcuts</strong></a> will pay big dividends.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REQUEST WA ABORT COULD NOT CREAT SSL TL SECUR CHANNEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I seem to recall having this problem last year.  I suspect that you aren't closing your WebRequest objects properly, which is why after a certain amount of use it won't allow you to create any new connections.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WHI IS MY BUTTON S CLICK COMMAND EVENT NOT BINDING FIR IN A REPEAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Controls nested inside of Repeaters do not intercept events. Instead you need to bind to the Repeater.ItemCommand Event.</p><br/><br/><p>ItemCommand contains RepeaterCommandEventArgs which has two important fields:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>CommandName</li><br/><li>CommandArgument</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><p>So, a trivial example:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>  void rptr_ItemDataBound(object sender, RepeaterItemEventArgs e)<br/>        {<br/>            if (e.Item.ItemType == ListItemType.AlternatingItem || e.Item.ItemType == ListItemType.Item)<br/>            {<br/>                // Stuff to databind<br/>                Button myButton = (Button)e.Item.FindControl("myButton");<br/><br/>                myButton.CommandName = "Add";<br/>                myButton.CommandArgument = "Some Identifying Argument";<br/>            }<br/>        }<br/><br/>void rptr_ItemCommand(object source, RepeaterCommandEventArgs e)<br/>        {<br/>            if (e.CommandName == "Add")<br/>            {<br/>                // Do your event<br/>            }<br/>        }<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>EDIT: Markdown totally hosed my indentation, oh well, I should stop writing code in this textbox anyways.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      UPDATEPROGRESS SURPRESS THE LINE BREAK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I just blogged about my own solution to this problem.<br/><a href="http://www.joeaudette.com/solving-the-aspnet-updateprogress-div-problem.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://www.joeaudette.com/solving-the-aspnet-updateprogress-div-problem.aspx</a></p><br/><br/><p>What I did was borrow the UpdateProgress control from the Mono project and modified it to render as a span instead of a div. I also copied an modifed the ms-ajax javascript associated with the control and modified it to toggle between display:inline and display:none instead of using display:block</p><br/><br/><p>There is a .zip file linked in my post which contains the modified files.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MY EVENT TO FIRE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>@<a href="#42559" rel="nofollow">Brad</a>:  Your answer isn't complete; he's most likely doing it too late in the page lifecycle, during the Page_Load event.</p><br/><br/><p>Okay, here's what you're missing.</p><br/><br/><p>ASP.NET is stateless.  That means, after your page is rendered and sent to the browser, the page object and everything on it is destroyed.  There is no link that remains on the server between that page and what is on the user's browser.</p><br/><br/><p>When the user clicks a button, that event is sent back to the server, along with other information, like the hidden viewstate field.  </p><br/><br/><p>On the server side, ASP.NET determines what page handles the request, and rebuilds the page from scratch.  New instances of server controls are created and linked together according to the .aspx page.  Once it is reassembled, the postback data is evaluated.  The viewstate is used to populate controls, and events are fired.</p><br/><br/><p>This all happens in a specific order, called the <a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ui.page_events.aspx" rel="nofollow">Page Lifecycle</a>.  In order to do more complex things in ASP.NET, such as creating dynamic controls and adding them to the web page at runtime, you MUST understand the page lifecycle.  </p><br/><br/><p>With your issue, you must create that button every single time that page loads.  In addition, you must create that button BEFORE events are fired on the page.  Control events fire between Page_Load and Page_LoadComplete.</p><br/><br/><p>You want your controls loaded before ViewState information is parsed and added to controls, and before control events fire, so you need to handle the PreInit event and add your button at that point.  Again, you must do this EVERY TIME the page is loaded.</p><br/><br/><p>One last note; page event handling is a bit odd in ASP.NET because the events are autowired up.  Note the Load event handler is called Page_Load...</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUT OF BAND PROCESS TECHINIQU FOR ASP.NET APPLIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Years ago, I saw Rob Howard describe a way to use an HttpModule to process tasks in the background. It doesn't seem as slick as using the Cache, but it might be better for certain circumstances.</p><br/><br/><p><strong><a href="http://blogs.telerik.com/KevinBabcock/Posts/08-07-24/Using_an_HttpModule_to_Run_a_Background_Service.aspx" rel="nofollow">This blog post</a></strong> has the details, and there are many others that capture the same information if you look around.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FOCU WITH ASP.NET AJAX CONTROL TOOLKIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>We had exactly the same problem.  What we had to do is write a script at the bottom of the page that quickly blurs then refocuses to the textbox.  You can have a look at the (terribly hacky) solution here: <a href="http://www.drive.com.au" rel="nofollow">http://www.drive.com.au</a> </p><br/><br/><p>The textbox id is <code> MainSearchBox_SearchTextBox</code>.  Have a look at about line 586 &amp; you can see where I'm wiring up all the events (I'm actually using prototype for this bit.</p><br/><br/><p>Basically on the focus event of the textbox I set a global var called <code>textBoxHasFocus</code> to true and on the blur event I set it to false.  The on the load event of the page I call this script:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>if (textBoxHasFocus) {<br/>    $get("MainSearchBox_SearchTextBox").blur();<br/>    $get("MainSearchBox_SearchTextBox").focus();<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This resets the textbox.  It's really dodgy, but it's the only solution I could find</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REFER A JAVASCRIPT FILE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you reference the JS-file in a section that is "runat=server" you could write src="~/Javascript/jsfile.js" and it will always work.</p><br/><br/><p>You could also do this in your Page_Load (In your masterpage):</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Page.ClientScript.RegisterClientScriptInclude("myJsFile", Page.ResolveClientUrl("~/Javascript/jsfile.js"))<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PUT AN ASP.NET SESSION ID IN A HIDDEN FORM FIELD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://swfupload.org/forum/generaldiscussion/98" rel="nofollow">Here</a> is a post from the maintainer of <a href="http://swfupload.org" rel="nofollow">SWFUpload</a> which explains how to load the session from an ID stored in Request.Form. I imagine the same thing would work for the Yahoo component.</p><br/><br/><p>Note the security disclaimers at the bottom of the post.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PERFORM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>We haven't performed the type of scalability and perf tests necessary to come up with any conclusions. I think ScottGu may have been discussing potential perf targets. As we move towards Beta and RTM, we will internally be doing more perf testing. However, I'm not sure what our policy is on publishing results of perf tests.</p><br/><br/><p>In any case, any such tests really need to consider real world applications...</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BEST POPUL AN HTML TABL IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>@<a href="#43818" rel="nofollow">Geoff</a></p><br/><br/><p>That sort of Eval statement was actually added in 2.0, but if performance is important Eval should be avoided since it uses Reflection.</p><br/><br/><p>The repeater is a pretty good way of doing it, although it might be faster to generate the table in code:</p><br/><br/><p>ASPX Page:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;table class="report" id="bookTable" runat="server"&gt;<br/>        &lt;tr&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Published&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Author&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;<br/>        &lt;/tr&gt;<br/> &lt;/table&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Code Behind:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Protected Sub Page_Load( ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e As System.EventArgs) Handles Me.Load<br/>    If Not Page.IsPostback Then<br/>        BuildTable()<br/>    End If<br/>End Sub<br/><br/>Private Sub BuildTable()<br/>    Dim db As New BookstoreDataContext<br/>    Dim bookCollection = from b in db.Books _<br/>                         Order By b.Published _<br/>                         Select b<br/>    Dim row As HtmlTableRow<br/>    Dim cell As HtmlTableCell<br/><br/>    For Each book As Books In bookCollection<br/>        row = New HtmlTableRow()<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = b.Published.ToShortDateString }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = TryNbsp(HttpContext.Current.Server.HtmlEncode(b.Title)) }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = TryNbsp(HttpContext.Current.Server.HtmlEncode(b.Author))<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = Format(b.Price, "c") }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        bookTable.Controls.Add(row)<br/>    Next<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>I guess it depends on how important speed is to you. For simplicity's sake I think I would go with the Repeater.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WEB CONTROL LIBRARI TO USE FOR EASI FORM CREATION WITH MANI DIFFER TYPE OF INPUT FIELD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I would be tempted to look at Ext JS for this. </p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://extjs.com/products/extjs/" rel="nofollow">Ext JS</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
</aiml>
