<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<aiml version="1.0">
  <meta content="SimpleAIMLGenerator" name="author"/>
  <meta content="en" name="language"/>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PERCENTAG WIDTH CHILD IN ABSOLUT POSIT PARENT WORK IN IE 7
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Does the parent div have a defined width either pixel or percentage? Not 100% sure but I think in IE7, the parent div needs a defined width for child percentage divs to work correctly.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A WEB USER S TIME ZONE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<h1>timezone.js:</h1><br/><br/><pre><code>function ajaxpage(){<br/>    var url = "timezone.php";<br/>    var visitortime = new Date();<br/>    vat time = visitortime.getTimezoneOffset()/60;<br/>    var page_request = false<br/>    if (window.XMLHttpRequest)<br/>            page_request = new XMLHttpRequest()<br/>    else if (window.ActiveXObject){ <br/>            try {<br/>                    page_request = new ActiveXObject("Msxml2.XMLHTTP")<br/>            } catch (e){<br/>                    try{<br/>                            page_request = new ActiveXObject("Microsoft.XMLHTTP")<br/>                    } catch (e) {}<br/>            }<br/>    } else<br/>            return false<br/><br/>    page_request.onreadystatechange=function() {<br/>            loadpage(page_request, containerid)<br/>    }<br/><br/>    if (bustcachevar)<br/>            bustcacheparameter=(url.indexOf("?")!=-1) ? "&amp;"+new Date().getTime() : "?"+new Date().getTime()<br/><br/>    page_request.open('GET', url+bustcacheparameter+"&amp;time="+time, true)<br/>    page_request.send(null) }<br/><br/><br/>function loadpage(page_request, containerid){<br/>    if (page_request.readyState == 4 &amp;&amp; (page_request.status==200 || window.location.href.indexOf("http")==-1))<br/>            document.write('&lt;meta http-equiv="refresh" content="0;url=http://example.com/"/&gt;');<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><hr><br/><br/><h1>timezone.php:</h1><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;?php<br/>session_start();<br/>$_SESSION['time'] = $_GET['time'];<br/>?&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><hr><br/><br/><p>When you want to use it add onLoad="ajaxpage();" to the body tag and it should cause the timezone to be stored in the PHP session variable $_SESSION['time']</p><br/><br/><p>Edit: P.S. This is untested.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SUBMIT BUTTON IN AN HTML FORM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I hope this helps. I'm just doing the trick of <code>float</code>ing the buttons on the right - like in normal wizard :-)</p><br/><br/><p>This way the Prev button is left of the Next button but the Next comes first in the HTML code:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;html&gt;<br/>&lt;head&gt;<br/>    &lt;style&gt;<br/>        .f {<br/>            float: right;<br/>        }<br/>    &lt;/style&gt;<br/>&lt;/head&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/>    &lt;form action="action" method="get"&gt;<br/>        &lt;input type="text" name="abc"&gt;<br/>        &lt;div id="buttons"&gt;<br/>            &lt;input type="submit" class="f" name="next" value="Next"&gt;<br/>            &lt;input type="submit" class="f" name="prev" value="Prev"&gt;<br/>            &lt;div style="clear:both"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- Need this to have the buttons actually inside div#buttons --&gt;<br/>        &lt;/div&gt;<br/>    &lt;/form&gt;<br/>&lt;/body&gt;<br/>&lt;/html&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Hope this helps... :-)<br/>Edit: benefits over other suggestions: no javascript, accessible, both buttons remain <code>type="submit"</code></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TEST LAYOUT DESIGN ACROSS MULTIPL BROWSERS OSS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Screen capturing services are a great way to do this.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://browsershots.org/" rel="nofollow">http://browsershots.org/</a> is free.</p><br/><br/><p>and there are some "pay" services like:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.browsercam.com" rel="nofollow">http://www.browsercam.com</a><br/>and<br/><a href="http://litmusapp.com" rel="nofollow">http://litmusapp.com</a></p><br/><br/><p>These kinds of services are nice because they allow you to specify a certain amount of time to wait for the page to load, and allow you have them perform actions (clicking links etc). Then you get a nice array of screenshots you can quickly browse to ensure your site looks like you expected across your desired platforms.</p><br/><br/><p>Also, there is a service for Firefox that allows you to run sand-boxed versions of multiple browsers on your machine called <a href="http://spoon.net/Browsers/" rel="nofollow">"Browser Sandbox" from spoon.net</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FONT IN JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've seen it done in a kind of iffy, but pretty reliable way.  Basically, an element is set to use a specific font and a string is set to that element.  If the font set for the element does not exist, it takes the font of the parent element.  So, what they do is measure the width of the rendered string.  If it matches what they expected for the desired font as opposed to the derived font, it's present.</p><br/><br/><p>Here's where it came from:<br/><a href="http://ajaxian.com/archives/javascriptcss-font-detector" rel="nofollow">Javascript/CSS Font Detector (ajaxian.com; 12 Mar 2007)</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML HOW TO WORD BREAK ON A DASH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Replace your hyphens with this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&amp;shy;<br></code></pre><br/><br/><p>It's called a "soft" hyphen.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GIVE MY WEB SITE AN ICON FOR IPHON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>See the <strong><a href="http://developer.apple.com/safari/library/documentation/AppleApplications/Reference/SafariWebContent/ConfiguringWebApplications/ConfiguringWebApplications.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40002051-CH3-SW4" rel="nofollow">Specifying a Webpage Icon for Web Clip</a></strong> section of the <em>Configuring Web Applications</em> page of the <em>Safari Web Content Guide</em> in the <em>Safari Reference Library</em>...</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <h2>Specifying a Webpage Icon for Web Clip</h2><br/>  <br/>  <blockquote><br/>    <p><strong>iPhone OS Note:</strong> The Web Clip feature<br/>    is available in iPhone OS 1.1.3 and<br/>    later. The<br/>    <code>apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</code><br/>    filename is available in iPhone OS 2.0<br/>    and later.</p><br/>  </blockquote><br/>  <br/>  <p>You may want users to be able to add<br/>  your web application or webpage link<br/>  to the Home screen. These links,<br/>  represented by an icon, are called Web<br/>  Clips. Follow these simple steps to<br/>  specify an icon to represent your web<br/>  application or webpage on iPhone OS.</p><br/>  <br/>  <ul><br/>  <li><p>To specify an icon for the entire<br/>  website (every page on the website),<br/>  place an icon file in PNG format in<br/>  the root document folder called<br/>  <code>apple-touch-icon.png</code> or<br/>  <code>apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</code>. If<br/>  you use<br/>  <code>apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</code> as<br/>  the filename, Safari on iPhone OS<br/>  won't add any effects to the icon.</p></li><br/>  <li><p>To specify an icon for a single<br/>  webpage or replace the website icon<br/>  with a webpage-specific icon, add a<br/>  link element to the webpage, as in:<br><br/>  <code>&lt;link rel="apple-touch-icon" href="/custom_icon.png"/&gt;</code><br><br/>  In the above example, replace<br/>  <code>custom_icon.png</code> with your icon<br/>  filename. If you don't want Safari on<br/>  iPhone OS to add any effects to the<br/>  icon, replace <code>apple-touch-icon</code> with<br/>  <code>apple-touch-icon-precomposed</code>.</p></li><br/>  </ul><br/>  <br/>  <p>See <a href="http://developer.apple.com/safari/library/documentation/InternetWeb/Conceptual/iPhoneWebAppHIG/MetricsLayout/MetricsLayout.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40007900-CH6-SW31" rel="nofollow">"Create an Icon for Your Web Application or Webpage"</a> in <a href="http://developer.apple.com/safari/library/documentation/InternetWeb/Conceptual/iPhoneWebAppHIG/Introduction/Introduction.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40007900" rel="nofollow">iPhone Human Interface Guidelines for Web Applications</a> for webpage icon metrics.</p><br/></blockquote><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EDITOR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.aptana.com/" rel="nofollow">Aptana</a> is rather nice if you want all the bells and whistles without paying for Visual Studio. If, like sasb suggested, you can get Microsoft products for free from school, then I would tend to lean towards Microsoft Expression Web or Visual Studio.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CHECKBOX TOGGL FROM CLICK ON THE TEXT LABEL AS WELL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Set the CSS "display" property for the label to be a block element and use that instead of your div - it keeps the semantic meaning of a label while allowing whatever styling you like.</p><br/><br/><p>For example</p><br/><br/><pre><code> &lt;label for="test" style="width: 100px; height: 100px; display: block; background-color: #e0e0ff;"&gt;<br>   A ticky box! &lt;input type="checkbox" id="test" /&gt;<br> &lt;/label&gt;<br></code></pre>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DISABL BROWSER AUTOCOMPLET ON WEB FORM FIELD INPUT TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<pre><code>&lt;input type="text" name="foo" autocomplete="off" /&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Doesn't that work on major browsers?</p><br/><br/><p>See: <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/How_to_Turn_Off_Form_Autocompletion" rel="nofollow">https://developer.mozilla.org/en/How_to_Turn_Off_Form_Autocompletion</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FOR HTML SCRAPE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The Ruby world's equivalent to Beautiful Soup is why_the_lucky_stiff's <a href="http://code.whytheluckystiff.net/hpricot/" rel="nofollow" title="Hpricot">Hpricot</a>.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      VERSION CHOIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'd shoot for XHTML Transitional 1.0. There are still a few nuances out there that don't like XHTML strict, and most editors I've seen now will give you the proper nudges to make sure that things are done right.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      XMP TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well a quick google search on W3C shows it was for displaying formatted text in HTML 3.2 and earlier and was deprecated and pre preferred instead.</p><br/><br/><p>Update: <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html32#xmp" rel="nofollow">http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html32#xmp</a>, <a href="http://www.w3.org/MarkUp/html-spec/html-spec_5.html#SEC5.5.2.1" rel="nofollow">http://www.w3.org/MarkUp/html-spec/html-spec_5.html#SEC5.5.2.1</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LIST INTO COLUMN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>So I dug up this article from A List Apart <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/multicolumnlists" rel="nofollow">CSS Swag: Multi-Column Lists</a>.  I ended up using the first solution, it's not the best but the others require either using complex HTML that can't be generated dynamically, or creating a lot of custom classes, which could be done but would require loads of in-line styling and possibly a huge page.</p><br/><br/><p>Other solutions are still welcome though.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      DIV S HEIGHT IN HTML WITH CSS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Ahem</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <blockquote><br/>    <p>The short answer to your question is that you must set the height of 100% to the body and html tag, then set the height to 100% on each div element you want to make 100% the height of the page.</p><br/>  </blockquote><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>actually, 100% height will not work in most design situations - this may be short but it is not a good answer. Google "any column longest" layouts. The best way is to put the left and right cols inside a wrapper div, float the left and right cols and then float the wrapper - this makes it stretch to the height of the inner containers - then set background image on the outer wrapper. But watch for any horizontal margins on the floated elements in case you get the IE double margin float bug.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      COMMENT MARKUP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think that your version with the cite, blockquote, etc. would definitely work , but if semantics is your main concern then I personally wouldn't use cite and blockquote as they have specific things that they are supposed to represent.</p><br/><br/><p>The blockquote tag is meant to represent a quotation taken from another source and the cite tag is meant to represent a source of information (like a magazine, newspaper, etc.).</p><br/><br/><p>I think an argument can certainly made that you can use semantic HTML with class names, provided they are meaningful. This article on Plain Old Semantic HTML makes a reference to using class names - <a href="http://www.fooclass.com/plain_old_semantic_html" rel="nofollow">http://www.fooclass.com/plain_old_semantic_html</a></p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      COMMENT BREAK DOWN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Comments in the XML Spec: <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml/#sec-comments" rel="nofollow">http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml/#sec-comments</a></p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>For compatibility, the string "--"<br/>  (double-hyphen) MUST NOT occur within<br/>  comments.</p><br/></blockquote>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REASON NOT TO START USE THE HTML 5 DOCTYP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well consider this:</p><br/><br/><p>When serving as text/html, all you need a doctype for is to trigger standards mode. Beyond that, the doctype does nothing as far as browsers are concerned.</p><br/><br/><p>When serving as text/html, whether you use XHTML markup or HTML markup, it's treated by browsers as HTML.</p><br/><br/><p>So, really it comes down to using the shortest doctype that triggers standards mode (&lt;!DOCTYPE html>) and using HTML markup that produces the correct result in browsers.</p><br/><br/><p>The rest is about conforming, validation and markup prerference.</p><br/><br/><p>With that said, using &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; now and trying to make your markup conform to HTML5 is not a bad idea as long as you stick to stable features that work in browsers now. You wouldn't use anything in HTML4 or XHTML 1.x that doesn't work in browsers, would you?</p><br/><br/><p>In other words, you use &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; with HTML4-like markup while honoring things that have been clarified in HTML5. HTML5 is about browser compatibility after all.</p><br/><br/><p>The downside to using HTML5 now is that the spec can change quite often. This makes it important for you to keep up with the spec as it actively changes. Also <a href="http://validator.nu/" rel="nofollow">http://validator.nu/</a> might not always be up-to-date, but <a href="http://validator.w3.org/" rel="nofollow">http://validator.w3.org/</a> isn't always up-to-date either, so don't let that stop you.</p><br/><br/><p>Of course, if you want to use XHTML 1.0 markup and conform to XHTML 1.0, then you shouldn't use &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;.</p><br/><br/><p>Personally, I always use &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; for HTML.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WYSIWYG HTML EDITOR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you're looking for an OSS app, Nvu is fairly good.</p><br/><br/><p>It's based off of Mozilla code, so you get a WYSIWYG editor that displays a site the same way Firefox would.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.nvu.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.nvu.com/</a></p><br/><br/><p><strong>Edit:</strong> I didn't know this, but apparently Nvu has been discontinued, so the last release was a few years ago. The project has been picked up under a new name, KompoZer.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://www.kompozer.net/" rel="nofollow">http://www.kompozer.net/</a></p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GOOD TOOL FOR CREAT COMPIL HTML HELP FILE ( .CHM )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.codeplex.com/Sandcastle" rel="nofollow" title="Codeplex">Sandcastle</a>, Microsoft's replacement for the long-lost nDoc, works pretty well.</p>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FOR PARS LINK FROM A WEBPAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>((mailto\:|(news|(ht|f)tp(s?))\://){1}\S+)</p><br/><br/><p>I took this from <a href="http://regexlib.com/Search.aspx?k=URL" rel="nofollow">regexlib.com</a></p><br/><br/><p>[editor's note: the {1} has no real function in this regex; <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/13470/question-about-specific-regular-expression" rel="nofollow">see this post</a>]</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAVASCRIPT ENABL DISABL RADIO BUTTON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>To get FF to mimic IE's behavior when using the keyboard, you can use the keyup event on the select box. In your example (I am not a fan of attaching event handlers this way, but that's another topic), it would be like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;select name="user" id="selUser" onchange="javascript:SetLocationOptions()" onkeyup="javascript:SetLocationOptions()"&gt;<br></code></pre>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      S TEXTAREA USE PROTOTYP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Facebook does it, when you write on people's walls, but only resizes vertically. </p><br/><br/><p>Horizontal resize strikes me as being a terrible mess, due to word-wrap, long lines, and so on, but vertical resize would be pretty safe and nice</p><br/><br/><p>Facebook is inhabited by every idiot on the planet, and none of the facebook-using-idiots I know have ever mentioned anything about it or been remotely confused.</p><br/><br/><p>I'd use this as anecdotal evidence to say 'go ahead, implement it'</p><br/><br/><p>Some javascript to do it, using prototype.js (cos that's what I know)</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN"<br/>  "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd"&gt;<br/>&lt;html&gt;<br/>&lt;head&gt;<br/>  &lt;script src="http://www.google.com/jsapi"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;<br/>  &lt;script language="javascript"&gt;<br/>  google.load('prototype', '1.6.0.2');<br/>  &lt;/script&gt;<br/>&lt;/head&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/>  &lt;textarea id="text-area" rows="1" cols="50"&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;<br/><br/>  &lt;script type="text/javascript" language="javascript"&gt;<br/>  resizeIt = function() {<br/>    var str = $('text-area').value;<br/>    var cols = $('text-area').cols;<br/><br/>    var linecount = 0;<br/>    $A(str.split("\n")).each( function(l) {<br/>      linecount += Math.ceil( l.length / cols ); // take into account long lines<br/>    } )<br/>    $('text-area').rows = linecount + 1;<br/>  };<br/><br/>  Event.observe('text-area', 'keydown', resizeIt ); // you could attach to keyUp or whatever if keydown doesn't work<br/>  resizeIt(); //initial on load<br/>  &lt;/script&gt;<br/>&lt;/body&gt;<br/>&lt;/html&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>PS: Obviously this javascript is very naive, and you probably don't want to use it on textboxes with novels in them, but you get the general idea</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SOLV THE SELECT OVERLAP BUG IN IE6
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't know anything better than an Iframe</p><br/><br/><p>But it does occur to me that this could be added in JS by looking for a couple of variables </p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>IE 6</li><br/><li>A high Z-Index (you tend to have to set a z-index if you are floating a div over)</li><br/><li>A box element</li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>Then a script that looks for these items and just add an iframe layer would be a neat solution</p><br/><br/><p>Paul</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ENTITI INSID ASP.NET PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The ASCII table is set of characters, arguable the first standardized set of characters back in the days when you could only spare 1 byte per character.  <a href="http://asciitable.com/" rel="nofollow" title="Unison Home Page"><a href="http://asciitable.com/" rel="nofollow">http://asciitable.com/</a></a>  But I did some looking around at the extended character set of ASCII and it appears that the character you are referencing is an ASCII character.  So there really isn't a problem which ever way you choose to display your title.  </p><br/><br/><p>My revised answer is go for less expensive one according to space (i.e. the first one)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PLAN AND BUILD A MOBIL ENABL SITE FOR YOUR MAIN SITE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Newer phones come with WAP2 which uses HTML Mobile Profile (XHTML MP), which is quite similar to normal HTML.  Older phones use Wireless Markup Language (WML). </p><br/><br/><p>Depending on your audience I would consider making a mobile phone friendly version of the site using XHTML MP and drop WML completely. By mobile phone friendly I mean light graphics, little JavaScript and simple navigation.</p><br/><br/><p>To check capabilities of different hand phones, take look at <a href="http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/" rel="nofollow" title="Wireless Universal Resource File">WURFL</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>Also, you might want to take a look at <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2008/REC-mobile-bp-20080729/" rel="nofollow" title="Mobile Web Best Practices">Mobile Web Best Practices</a> from w3c.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      .DISPLAY NOT WORK IN FIREFOX OPERA SAFARI IE7 OK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Since setting the properties with javascript never seemed to work, but setting using Firebug's inspect did, I started to suspect that the javascript ID selector was broken - maybe there were multiple items in the DOM with the same ID?  The source didn't show that there were, but looping through all divs using javascript I found that that was the case. Here's the function I ended up using to show the popup:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function openPopup(popupID)<br/>{<br/>  var divs = getObjectsByTagAndClass('div','popupDiv');<br/>  if (divs != undefined &amp;&amp; divs != null)<br/>  {<br/>    for (var i = 0; i &lt; divs.length; i++)<br/>    {<br/>      if (divs[i].id == popupID)<br/>        divs[i].style.display = 'block';    	<br/>    }<br/>  }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>(utility function getObjectsByTagAndClass not listed)</p><br/><br/><p>Ideally I'll find out why the same item is being inserted multiple times, but I don't have control over the rendering platform, just its inputs.</p><br/><br/><p>So when debugging issues like this, <strong>remember to check for duplicate IDs in the DOM, which can break getElementById</strong>.</p><br/><br/><p>To everyone who answered, thanks for your help!</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CUSTOM THE NUMBER IN AN ORDER LIST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This is the solution I have working in Firefox 3, Opera and Google Chrome. The list still displays in IE7 (but without the close bracket and left align numbers):</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;<br/>&lt;!--<br/>ol {<br/>    counter-reset: item;<br/>    margin-left: 0;<br/>    padding-left: 0;<br/>}<br/>li {<br/>    display: block;<br/>    margin-bottom: .5em;<br/>    margin-left: 2em;<br/>}<br/>li:before {<br/>    display: inline-block;<br/>    content: counter(item) ") ";<br/>    counter-increment: item;<br/>    width: 2em;<br/>    margin-left: -2em;<br/>}<br/>--&gt;<br/>&lt;/style&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/>&lt;ol&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;One&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Two&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Three&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Four&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Five&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Six&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Seven&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Eight&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Nine&lt;br&gt;Items&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Ten&lt;br&gt;Items&lt;/li&gt;<br/>&lt;/ol&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p><strong>EDIT:</strong> Included multiple line fix by strager</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>Also is there a CSS solution to change from numbers to alphabetic/roman lists instead of using the type attribute on the ol element.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Refer to <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS2/generate.html#lists" rel="nofollow">list-style-type</a> CSS property. Or when using counters the second argument accepts a list-style-type value. For example the following will use upper roman:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>li:before {<br/>    content: counter(item, upper-roman) ") ";<br/>    counter-increment: item;<br/>/* ... */<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      UPLOAD A FILE VIA AN HTTP POST WITH A WEB FORM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>File upload boxes is where we're currently at if you don't want to involve other technologies like Flash, Java or ActiveX.</p><br/><br/><p>With plain HTML you are pretty much limited to the experience you've described (no progress bar, double submits, etc). If you are willing to use some javascript, you can solve some of the problems by giving feedback that the upload is in progress and even <a href="http://www.raditha.com/php/progress.php" rel="nofollow" title="Coding Guidelines for Cocoa">showing the upload progress</a> (it is a hack because you shouldn't have to do a full round-trip to the server and back, but at least it works).</p><br/><br/><p>If you are willing to use Flash (which is available pretty much anywhere and on many platforms), you can overcome pretty much all of these problems. A quick googling turned up <a href="http://www.downloadsquad.com/2006/11/16/swfupload-open-source-flash-multi-file-upload/" rel="nofollow" title="Apple Developer Connection">two</a> <a href="http://www.codeproject.com/KB/aspnet/FlashUpload.aspx" rel="nofollow">such</a> components, both of them free <em>and</em> open source. I never used any of them, but they look good. BTW, Flash isn't without its problems either, for example when using the multi-file uploader for slide share, the browser kept constantly crashing on me :-(</p><br/><br/><p>Probably the best solution currently is to detect dynamically if the user has Flash, and if it's the case, give her the flash version of the uploader, while still making it possible to choose the basic HTML one.</p><br/><br/><p>HTH</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML ON THI SITE SO CLEAN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>One of the goals of ASP.NET MVC is to give you control of your markup. However, there have always been choices with ASP.NET which would allow you to generate relatively clean HTML.</p><br/><br/><p>For instance, ASP.NET has always offered a choice with validator controls. Do you value development speed over markup? Use validators. Value markup over development speed? Pick another validation mechanism. Your comments on validators are kind of contradictory there - it's possible to use ASP.NET and still make choices for markup purity over development speed.</p><br/><br/><p>Also, with webforms, we've had the CSS Friendly Control Adapters for a few years which will modify the controls to render more semantic markup. ASP.NET 3.5 included the ListView, which makes it really easy to write repeater type controls which emit semantic HTML. We used ASP.NET webforms on the Microsoft PDC site and have kept the HTML pretty clean: <a href="http://microsoftpdc.com/Agenda/Speakers.aspx" rel="nofollow" title="Araxis Merge"><a href="http://microsoftpdc.com/Agenda/Speakers.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://microsoftpdc.com/Agenda/Speakers.aspx</a></a> - the Viewstate could probably be disabled on most pages, although in reality it's only a few dozen bytes.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PRE TAG INSID A CODE TAG WITH JQUERI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>That's the difference between <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/struct/global.html#h-7.5.3" rel="nofollow">block and inline</a> elements. <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/sgml/dtd.html#block" rel="nofollow"><code>pre</code> is a block level element</a>. It's not legal to put it inside a <code>code</code> tag, which <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/struct/text.html#h-9.2.1" rel="nofollow">can only contain inline content</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>Because browsers have to support whatever godawful tag soup they might find on the real web, Firefox tries to do what you mean. IE happens to handle it differently, which is fine by the spec; behavior in that case is unspecified, because it should never happen.</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Could you instead <em>replace</em> the <code>code</code> element with the <code>pre</code>? (Because of the block/inline issue, technically that should only work if the elements are inside <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/sgml/dtd.html#flow" rel="nofollow">an element with "flow" content</a>, but the browsers might do what you want anyway.)</li><br/><li>Why is it a <code>code</code> element in the first place, if you want <code>pre</code>'s behavior?</li><br/><li>You could also give the <code>code</code> element <code>pre</code>'s whitespace preserving power with the CSS <a href="http://www.blooberry.com/indexdot/css/properties/text/whitespace.htm" rel="nofollow"><code>white-space: pre</code></a>, but apparently <a href="http://www.quirksmode.org/css/whitespace.html" rel="nofollow">IE 6 only honors that in Strict Mode</a>.</li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A CHILD NODE IN HTML USE JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>To answer the original question - there are various ways to do this, but the following would be the simplest.</p><br/><br/><p>If you already have a handle to the child node that you want to remove, i.e. you have a JavaScript variable that holds a reference to it:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>myChildNode.parentNode.removeChild(myChildNode);<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Obviously, if you are not using one of the numerous libraries that already do this, you would want to create a function to abstract this out:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function removeElement(node) {<br/>    node.parentNode.removeChild(node);<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>EDIT: As has been mentioned by others: if you have any event handlers wired up to the node you are removing, you will want to make sure you disconnect those before the last reference to the node being removed goes out of scope, lest poor implementations of the JavaScript interpreter leak memory.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      INCLUD FILE IN SHTML THE BEST METHOD TO KEEP NON DATABAS CHANG DATA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I don't think there is anything wrong with it, and I've done some similar things with PHP. If the people that make the changes are comfortable with how they do it and they can do what they need to, I think you should stick with it. There could be some retraining involved and/or a fair amount of work involved for changing the system.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAVASCRIPT TO RENDER HTML FOR SERVER SID CACH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Wikipedia's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server-side_JavaScript" rel="nofollow">"Server-side JavaScript"</a> article lists numerous implementations, many of which are based on Mozilla's <strong>Rhino</strong> JavaScript-to-Java converter, or its cousin <strong>SpiderMonkey</strong> (the same engine as found in Firefox and other Gecko-based browsers). In particular, something simple like <a href="http://www.modjs.org/" rel="nofollow"><strong>mod_js</strong></a> for Apache may suit your needs.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SPECIF FIREFOX EXTENS PROGRAM FOR FORM POST
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Actually I think <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/2691" rel="nofollow">Poster</a> is what you're looking for.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/img/uploads/previews/full/19/19951.png" rel="nofollow">A Screen shot of an older Poster version</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ON THE WEB
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Safari and to a lesser extent Firefox 3 have support for @font-face in CSS which lets you use custom fonts. You need to have the appropriate licence to distribute the font files though. These articles explain it in more detail:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li><a href="http://www.css3.info/preview/web-fonts-with-font-face/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.css3.info/preview/web-fonts-with-font-face/" rel="nofollow">http://www.css3.info/preview/web-fonts-with-font-face/</a></a></li><br/><li><a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/cssatten" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/cssatten" rel="nofollow">http://www.alistapart.com/articles/cssatten</a></a></li><br/><li><a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/blogs/2008/07/30/custom-web-fonts-pick-your-poison/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/blogs/2008/07/30/custom-web-fonts-pick-your-poison/" rel="nofollow">http://www.sitepoint.com/blogs/2008/07/30/custom-web-fonts-pick-your-poison/</a></a></li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HANDL WHITE SPACE IN YOUR HTML
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>For your specific example, there is no need to worry about it. Web browsers perform typographical rendering and place the correct amount of space between periods and whatever character follows (and it's different depending on the next character, according to kerning rules.)</p><br/><br/><p>If you want line breaks, &lt;br/&gt; isn't really a big deal, is it?</p><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>Not sure what's worthy of a downmod here... You should not be forcing two spaces after a period, unless you're using a monospace font. For proportional fonts, the rederer kerns the right amount of space after a period. See <a href="http://www.webword.com/reports/period.html">here</a> and <a href="http://everything2.com/node/540926">here</a> for detailed discussions.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ALPHABET NAVIG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>So, there were plenty of good suggestions, but none did exactly what I wanted. Fortunately I was able to use them to figure out what I really wanted to do. The only thing the following doesn't do is print the last few unused letters (if there are any). That's why I have that cfif statement checking for 'W' as that's the last letter I use, otherwise it should check for Z.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;cfquery datasource="#application.dsn#" name="qTitles"&gt;<br/>SELECT title, url, substr(titles,1,1) as indexLetter<br/>FROM list<br/>ORDER BY indexLetter,title<br/>&lt;/cfquery&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;cfset linkLetter = "#asc('A')#"&gt;<br/>&lt;cfoutput query="titles" group="indexletter"&gt;<br/>    &lt;cfif chr(linkLetter) eq #qTitles.indexletter#&gt;<br/>        &lt;a href="###ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#"&gt;#ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#&lt;/a&gt;<br/>        &lt;cfif asc('W') neq linkLetter&gt;|&lt;/cfif&gt;<br/>        &lt;cfset linkLetter = ++LinkLetter&gt;<br/>    &lt;cfelse&gt;<br/>        &lt;cfscript&gt;<br/>        while(chr(linkLetter) != qTitles.indexletter)<br/>                {<br/>                        WriteOutput(" " &amp; chr(linkLetter) &amp; " ");<br/>                        IF(linkLetter != asc('W')){WriteOutput("|");};<br/>                        ++LinkLetter;<br/>                }<br/>        &lt;/cfscript&gt;<br/><br/>        &lt;a href="###ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#"&gt;#ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#&lt;/a&gt;<br/>        &lt;cfif asc('W') neq linkLetter&gt;|&lt;/cfif&gt;<br/>        &lt;cfset linkLetter = ++LinkLetter&gt;<br/>    &lt;/cfif&gt;<br/>&lt;/cfoutput&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;ul&gt;<br/>&lt;cfset currentLetter = ""&gt;<br/>&lt;cfoutput query="qTitles" group="title"&gt;<br/>&lt;cfif currentLetter neq #qTitles.indexletter#&gt;<br/>    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a name="#ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#"&gt;#ucase(qTitles.indexletter)#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;<br/>&lt;/cfif&gt;<br/>&lt;cfset currentLetter = #qTitles.indexletter#&gt;<br/>&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#url#"&gt;#title#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;<br/>&lt;/cfoutput&gt;<br/>&lt;/ul&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BEST PRACTIC
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>I should also have mentioned that I would like the banner rotation to keep moving. When the visitor clicks on a link, the banner rotation starts over. It would be nice if the "animation" kept rotating, regardless of the page the user visits.Blockquote</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Well, in that case I would strongly recommend not doing that. The only real way of achieving that is to have the actual website content in the iframe, which means that you suddenly have lots of negative sides to the site: not being able to bookmark urls easily due to the address bar not changing; accessibility concerns; etc</p><br/><br/><p>I think you'll find that most people won't care that it reloads again. Once a visitor lands on your website, they'll marvel at the wonderful banner immediately, and then will continue to ignore it while they browse your site - until an image they haven't seen appears and distracts them away from your content.</p><br/><br/><p>Keep the rotation random enough, and with enough images, and people will stop to look at it from whatever page they're on.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SET OR WHERE IS THE LOCAL DOCUMENT ROOT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It depends on what browser you use, but Internet Explorer, for example, would take you to the root directory of your harddrive (eg. C:/), while browsers such as Firefox does nothing. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AN IMAG GET COORDIN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This thread answers exactly the same <a href="http://bytes.com/forum/thread507079.html" rel="nofollow">question</a></p><br/><br/><p>With more info <a href="http://www.quirksmode.org/js/events_properties.html#position" rel="nofollow">here</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GO FROM A PHOTOSHOP MOCKUP TO SEMANT HTML AND CSS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I have a fairly natural way of coding. The key is to treat the page like a document or an article. If you think of it like this the following becomes logically clear:</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li><p>The page title is a top level heading </p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Whether you make the site title or actual page title the h1 is up to you - personally I'd make About Us the h1 rather than Stack Overflow.</li><br/></ul></li><br/><li><p>The navigation is a table of contents, and thus an <strong>ordered list</strong> - you may as well use an ol over a ul.</p></li><br/><li><p>Section headers are h2, sections within those sections are h3s etc. Stack them up.</p></li><br/><li><p>Use blockquotes and quotes where possible. Don't just surround it with ".</p></li><br/><li><p>Don't use b and i. Use strong and em. This is because HTML is structural rather than presentational markup. <strong>Strong</strong> and <strong>em</strong>phasis tags should be used where you'd put emphasis on the word.</p></li><br/><li><p><code>&lt;label&gt;</code> your form elements.</p></li><br/><li><p>Use <code>&lt;acronym&gt;</code>s and <code>&lt;abbr&gt;</code>s where possible, but only in the first instance.</p></li><br/><li><p>The easiest: always, <em>always</em> give your images some alternate text.</p></li><br/><li><p>There's lots of HTML tags you could use that you probably haven't - address for postal addresses, screen code output. Have a look at <a href="http://www.htmldog.com/" rel="nofollow">HTML Dog</a> for some, it's my favourite reference.</p></li><br/></ol><br/><br/><p>That's just a few pointers, I'm sure I could think of more.</p><br/><br/><p>Oh, and if you want a challenge write your XHTML first, then write the CSS. When CSS-ing you aren't allowed to touch the HTML. It's actually harder than you think (but I've found it's made me quicker).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML ANCHOR TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>They must be doing some really crazy stuff with JavaScript to get it to work (notice how neither the parent nor the nested anchor tags have a name or href attribute - all functionality is done through the class name and JS).</p><br/><br/><p>Here is what the html looks like:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;a class="page_tab page_tab"&gt;<br/>  &lt;div class="page_title" title="Click to rename this page."&gt;Click &amp; Type Page Name&lt;/div&gt;<br/>  &lt;a class="delete_page" title="Click to delete this page" style="display: block;"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;<br/>&lt;/a&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TO US WEB RICH TEXT EDITOR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well it depends what platform you are on if you are looking for server-side functionality as well, but the defacto badass WYSIWYg in my opinion is <a href="http://www.fckeditor.net/" rel="nofollow">FCKeditor</a>. I have worked with this personally in numerous environments (both professional and hobby level) and have always been impressed.</p><br/><br/><p>It's certainly worth a look. I believe it is employed by open source projects such as SubText as well. Perhaps, <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/jgalloway/" rel="nofollow">Jon Galloway</a> can add to this if he reads this question. Or <a href="http://haacked.com/Default.aspx" rel="nofollow">Phil</a> if he is currently a user.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CELL LARGER THAN THEY ARE MEANT TO BE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I think you need to use 'display: block' on your images. When images are inline there's a little extra space for the line spacing.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      INLIN SEARCH FUNCTION TO WEB PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vision-media.ca/resources/jquery/jquery-inline-search-plugin" rel="nofollow">jQuery inline search plugin</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SOME WAY TO SHOW HTML CONTENT INSID FLASH
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wdvl.com/Reviews/Graphics/Flash5/external.html" rel="nofollow">Here is a decent article</a> on how to accomplish that.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/22909/is-there-some-way-to-show-html-content-inside-flash#24396" rel="nofollow">@Flubba</a>: I didn't say "<em>great</em>" article, I said "<em>decent</em>" - there is a big difference. Besides, no one else had answered and it had been around a while. I figured a "decent" answer was better than none. I am no Flash expert, so...</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REGEX TO CATCH XSS ( CROSS SIT SCRIPT ) ATTACK ( IN JAVA )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Don't do this with regular expressions. Remember, you're not protecting just against valid HTML; you're protecting against the DOM that web browsers create. Browsers can be tricked into producing valid DOM from invalid HTML quite easily. </p><br/><br/><p>For example, see this list of <a href="http://ha.ckers.org/xss.html" rel="nofollow">obfuscated XSS attacks</a>. Are you prepared to tailor a regex to prevent this real world attack on <a href="http://www.greymagic.com/security/advisories/gm005-mc/" rel="nofollow">Yahoo and Hotmail</a> on IE6/7/8?</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;HTML&gt;&lt;BODY&gt;<br/>&lt;?xml:namespace prefix="t" ns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:time"&gt;<br/>&lt;?import namespace="t" implementation="#default#time2"&gt;<br/>&lt;t:set attributeName="innerHTML" to="XSS&amp;lt;SCRIPT DEFER&amp;gt;alert(&amp;quot;XSS&amp;quot;)&amp;lt;/SCRIPT&amp;gt;"&gt;<br/>&lt;/BODY&gt;&lt;/HTML&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>How about this attack that works on IE6? </p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;TABLE BACKGROUND="javascript:alert('XSS')"&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>How about attacks that are not listed on this site? The problem with Jeff's approach is that it's not a whitelist, as claimed. As someone on <a href="http://refactormycode.com/codes/333-sanitize-html#refactor_13642" rel="nofollow">that page</a> adeptly notes:</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>The problem with it, is that the html<br/>  must be clean. There are cases where<br/>  you can pass in hacked html, and it<br/>  won't match it, in which case it'll<br/>  return the hacked html string as it<br/>  won't match anything to replace. This<br/>  isn't strictly whitelisting.</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>I would suggest a purpose built tool like <a href="http://www.owasp.org/index.php/Category:OWASP_AntiSamy_Project" rel="nofollow">AntiSamy</a>. It works by actually parsing the HTML, and then traversing the DOM and removing anything that's not in the <em>configurable</em> whitelist. The major difference is the ability to gracefully handle malformed HTML. </p><br/><br/><p>The best part is that it actually unit tests for all the XSS attacks on the above site. Besides, what could be easier than this API call:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>public String toSafeHtml(String html) throws ScanException, PolicyException {<br/><br/>    Policy policy = Policy.getInstance(POLICY_FILE);<br/>    AntiSamy antiSamy = new AntiSamy();<br/>    CleanResults cleanResults = antiSamy.scan(html, policy);<br/>    return cleanResults.getCleanHTML().trim();<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NAME ENTITI IN HTML STILL NECESSARI IN THE AGE OF UNICOD AWAR BROWSER
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Named entities in "real" XHTML (i.e. with <code>application/xhtml+xml</code>, rather than the more frequently-used <code>text/html</code> compatibility mode) are discouraged. Aside from the five defined in XML itself (<code>&amp;lt;</code>, <code>&amp;gt;</code>, <code>&amp;amp;</code>, <code>&amp;quot;</code>, <code>&amp;apos;</code>), they'd all have to be defined in the DTD of the particular DocType you're using. That means your browser has to explicitly support that DocType, which is far from a given. Numbered entities, on the other hand, obviously only require a lookup table to get the right Unicode character.</p><br/><br/><p>As for whether you need entities at all these days: you can pretty much expect any modern browser to support UTF-8. Therefore, as long as you can guarantee that the database, the markup and the web server all agree to serve that, ditch the entities.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TIP ON AN IMAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Yes, you can do this without Javascript. Use an HTML image map, with title attributes, like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;img usemap="#logo" src="http://stackoverflow.com/Content/Img/stackoverflow-logo-250.png"&gt;<br/>&lt;map name="logo"&gt;<br/>&lt;area shape="rect" href="" coords="52,42,121,65" title="Stack"&gt;<br/>&lt;area shape="rect" href="" coords="122,42,245,65" title="Overflow"&gt;<br/>&lt;/map&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>The Stack Overflow logo refers to the <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/struct/objects.html#edef-MAP" rel="nofollow">image map</a>, which defines a rectangle for each of the two words using an <em>area</em> tag. Each area tag's <em>title</em> element specifies the text that browsers generally show as a tooltip. The <em>shape</em> attribute can also specify a circle or polygon. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUT ANCHOR TAG IN A STRING
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here's a simple regular expression that should work.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Imports System.Text.RegularExpressions<br/><br/>' ....<br/><br/>Dim reg As New Regex("&lt;a.*?href=(?:'|"")(.+?)(?:'|"").*?&gt;.+?&lt;/a&gt;")<br/>Dim input As String = "This is a link: &lt;a href='http://www.stackoverflow.com'&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;"<br/>input = reg.Replace(input, "$1", RegexOptions.IgnoreCase)<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PUT A SPACE CHARACT BEFOR OPTION TEXT IN A HTML SELECT ELEMENT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Isnt <strong>&amp;#160</strong> the entity for space?</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;select&gt;<br/>&lt;option&gt;&amp;#160;option 1&lt;/option&gt;<br/>&lt;option&gt;    option 2&lt;/option&gt;<br/>&lt;/select&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Works for me..</p><br/><br/><h3>EDIT:</h3><br/><br/><p>Just checked this out, there <em>may</em> be compat issues with this on older browsers, but all seems to work fine for me here. Just thought I should let you know as you may want to replace with <em><code>&amp;nbsp;</code></em></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PARS HYPERLINK AND DESCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>As long as there are no nested tags (and no line breaks), the following variant works well:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;a\s+href=(?:"([^"]+)"|'([^']+)').*?&gt;(.*?)&lt;/a&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>As soon as nested tags come into play, regular expressions are unfit for parsing. However, you can still use them by applying more advanced features of modern interpreters (depending on your regex machine). E.g. .NET regular expressions use a stack; I found this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>(?:&lt;a.*?href=[""'](?&lt;url&gt;.*?)[""'].*?&gt;)(?&lt;name&gt;(?&gt;&lt;a[^&lt;]*&gt;(?&lt;DEPTH&gt;)|&lt;/a&gt;(?&lt;-DEPTH&gt;)|.)+)(?(DEPTH)(?!))(?:&lt;/a&gt;)<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Source: <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottcate/archive/2004/12/13/281955.aspx" rel="nofollow">http://weblogs.asp.net/scottcate/archive/2004/12/13/281955.aspx</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PREVIEW HTML IN JAVA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Many of the Swing controls (like JLabel) can render basic HTML content. <a href="http://java.sun.com/javase/6/docs/api/javax/swing/JEditorPane.html" rel="nofollow">JEditorPane</a> can be used to display HTML pages. However, these controls are limited to <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html32" rel="nofollow">HTML 3.2</a> support.</p><br/><br/><p>For a richer experience, I would use the <a href="https://jdic.dev.java.net/" rel="nofollow">JDesktop Integration Components</a>.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>JDIC provides Java applications with<br/>  access to functionalities and<br/>  facilities provided by the native<br/>  desktop. It consists of a collection<br/>  of Java packages and tools. JDIC<br/>  supports a variety of features such as<br/>  <strong>embedding the native browser</strong>,<br/>  launching the desktop applications,<br/>  creating tray icons on the desktop,<br/>  registering file type associations,<br/>  creating JNLP installer packages, etc.</p><br/></blockquote><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML PARS LIBRARI DO YOU RECOMMEND IN JAVA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/nekohtml/" rel="nofollow">NekoHTML</a>, <a href="http://home.ccil.org/~cowan/XML/tagsoup/" rel="nofollow">TagSoup</a>, and <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/jtidy/" rel="nofollow">JTidy</a> will allow you to parse HTML and then process with XML tools, like XPath.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      KEY VALU PAIR TOGETH IN HTML SELECT WITH JQUERI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Like lucas said the value attribute is what you need. Using your code it would look something like this ( I added an id attribute to the select to make it fit ):</p><br/><br/><pre><code>$select = $('&lt;select id="mySelect"&gt;&lt;/select&gt;');<br/>$select.append('&lt;option value="1"&gt;Jason&lt;/option&gt;') //Key = 1<br/>   .append('&lt;option value="32"&gt;John&lt;/option&gt;') //Key = 32<br/>   .append('&lt;option value="423"&gt;Paul&lt;/option&gt;') //Key = 423<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>jQuery lets you get the value using the val() method. Using it on the select tag you get the current selected option's value.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>$( '#mySelect' ).val(); //Gets the value for the current selected option<br/><br/>$( '#mySelect &gt; option' ).each( function( index, option ) {<br/>    option.val(); //The value for each individual option<br/>} );<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Just in case, the .each method loops throught every element the query matched.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      M MANIPUL IN PHP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>PHP has <a href="http://php.net/tidy" rel="nofollow">a PECL extension that gives you access to the features of HTML Tidy</a>.  Tidy is a pretty powerful library that should be able to take code like that and close tags in an intelligent manner.</p><br/><br/><p>I use it to clean up malformed XML and HTML sent to me by a classified ad system prior to import.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WEBSIT EXPAND ON WINDOW RESIZ
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Raw HTML does just that.  Are you changing your data so that it doesn't render so good in random sized windows?</p><br/><br/><p>In the olden days, everyone had VGA screens.  Now, that resolution is most uncommon.  Who knows what resolutions are going to be common in the future?  And why expect a certain minimum width or height?</p><br/><br/><p>From a usability viewpoint, demanding a certain resolution from your users is just going to create a degraded experience for anyone not using that resolution.  Another thing that comes from this is what <em>is</em> fixed width?  I've seen plenty of fixed size windows (popups) that just don't render right because my fonts are different from the designer's.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SIMPL WAY TO MAKE HTML TEXTAREA AND INPUT TYPE TEXT EQUAL WIDE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You should be able to use</p><br/><br/><pre><code>   .mywidth{<br/>       width:100px;   <br/>   }<br/><br/><br/>  &lt;input class="mywidth" &gt;<br/> &lt;textarea class="mywidth"&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SELECT TAG WITH BLACK BACKGROUND DROPDOWN TRIANGL IS INVIS IN FIREFOX 3
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Must be a Vista problem.  I have XP SP 2 and it looks normal.  </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MATCH ALL HTML TAG EXCEPT P AND P
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I came up with this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;(?!\/?p(?=&gt;|\s.*&gt;))\/?.*?&gt;<br/><br/>x/<br/>&lt;   		# Match open angle bracket<br/>(?! 		# Negative lookahead (Not matching and not consuming)<br/>    \/? 	# 0 or 1 /<br/>    p   		# p<br/>    (?= 	# Positive lookahead (Matching and not consuming)<br/>    &gt;		# &gt; - No attributes<br/>        |		# or<br/>    \s		# whitespace<br/>    .*		# anything up to <br/>    &gt;		# close angle brackets - with attributes<br/>    )   		# close positive lookahead<br/>)   		# close negative lookahead<br/>    		# if we have got this far then we don't match<br/>    		# a p tag or closing p tag<br/>    		# with or without attributes<br/>\/? 		# optional close tag symbol (/)<br/>.*? 		# and anything up to<br/>&gt;   		# first closing tag<br/>/<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This will now deal with p tags with or without attributes and the closing p tags, but will match pre and similar tags, with or without attributes.</p><br/><br/><p>It doesn't strip out attributes, but my source data does not put them in.  I may change this later to do this, but this will suffice for now.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SUBMIT A FORM WHEN THE RETURN KEY IS PRESS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>IMO, this is the cleanest answer: </p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;html&gt;<br/>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;title&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/>  &lt;form action="" method="get"&gt;<br/>  Name: &lt;input type="text" name="name"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;<br/>  Pwd: &lt;input type="password" name="password"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;<br/>  &lt;div class="yourCustomDiv"/&gt;<br/>  &lt;input type="submit" style="display:none"/&gt;<br/>&lt;/form&gt;<br/>&lt;/body&gt;<br/>&lt;/html&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Better yet, if you are using javascript to submit the form using the custom div, you should also use javascript to create it, and to set the display:none style on the button. This way users with javascript disabled will still see the submit button and can click on it.</p><br/><br/><hr><br/><br/><p>It has been noted that display:none will cause IE to ignore the input.  I created a <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/Suyw6/1/" rel="nofollow">new JSFiddle example</a> that starts as a standard form, and uses progressive enhancement to hide the submit and create the new div.  I did use the CSS styling from <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/29943/how-to-submit-a-form-when-the-return-key-is-pressed/6602788#6602788">StriplingWarrior</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      INSTEAD OF DIV
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The whole "Tables vs Divs" thing just barely misses the mark.  It's not "table" or "div".  It's about using a semantic layout.</p><br/><br/><p>Even the div tag plays only a small part in a well laid out page.  Don't overuse it.  You shouldn't need that many if you put your html together correctly.  Things like lists, field sets, legends, labels, paragraphs, etc can replace much of what a div or span is often used to accomplish.  Div should be used primarily when it makes sense to indicate a logical *<em>div</em>*ision, and only appropriated for extra layout when absolutely necessary.  The same is true for table; use it when you have tabular data, but not otherwise.</p><br/><br/><p>Then you have a more semantic page and you don't need quite as many classes defined in your CSS; you can target the tags directly instead.  Possibly most importantly, you have a page that will score much better with Google (anecdotally) than the equivalent table or div-heavy page and will help you better connect with a portion of your audience.</p><br/><br/><p>So if we go back and look at it in terms of table vs div, it's my opinion that we've actually come to the point where div is over-used and table is under-used.  Why? Because when you really think about it, there are a lot of things out there that fall into the category of "tabular data" that tend to be overlooked.  Answers and comments on this very web page, for example.  They consist of multiple records, each with the same set of fields, and stored in a database table.  The exact definition of tabular data.  So an html table tag would absolutely be a good semantic choice to layout something like the posts here on StackOverflow.  And this same principle applies to many other things as well.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML OPPOSIT TO NOSCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You could have an invisible div that gets shown via JavaScript when the page loads.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PAGE LAYOUT IN IE6
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Might be overkill for your project, but <a href="http://dean.edwards.name/IE7/" rel="nofollow">Dean Edwards' IE7 javascript adds support for fixed positioning to IE6</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REASON LENGTH LIMIT ON PERSON NAME FIELD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://interim.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/govtalk/schemasstandards/e-gif/datastandards.aspx" rel="nofollow">UK Government Data Standards Catalogue</a> suggests 35 characters for each of Given Name and Family Name, or 70 characters for a single field to hold the Full Name.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      WAY TO FIND A VALU IN HTML ( JAVA )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Depends on how sophisticated of an Http request you need to build (authentication, etc). Here's one simple way I've seen used in the past. </p><br/><br/><pre><code>StringBuilder html = new StringBuilder();<br/>java.net.URL url = new URL("http://www.google.com/");<br/>BufferedReader input = null;<br/>try {<br/>    input new BufferedReader(<br/>        new InputStreamReader(url.openStream()));<br/><br/>    String htmlLine;<br/>    while ((htmlLine=input.readLine())!=null) {<br/>        html.appendLine(htmlLine);<br/>    }<br/>}<br/>finally {<br/>    input.close();<br/>}<br/><br/>Pattern exp = Pattern.compile(<br/>    "&lt;meta name=\"generator\" value=\"([^\"]*)\" /&gt;");<br/>Matcher matcher = exp.matcher(html.toString());<br/>if(matcher.find())<br/>{<br/>    System.out.println("Generator: "+matcher.group(1));<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p><em>Probably plenty of typos here to be found when compiled.<br/>(hope this wasn't homework)</em></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML IN JAVA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I'm currently using this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>String content = null;<br/>URLConnection connection = null;<br/>try {<br/>  connection =  new URL("http://www.google.com").openConnection();<br/>  Scanner scanner = new Scanner(connection.getInputStream());<br/>  scanner.useDelimiter("\\Z");<br/>  content = scanner.next();<br/>}catch ( Exception ex ) {<br/>    ex.printStackTrace();<br/>}<br/>System.out.println(content);<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>But not sure if there's a better way.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      FETCH AN UNSTANDARD HTML TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The answer is: <strong>don't use regular expressions</strong>.</p><br/><br/><p>Seriously. Use a SGML parser, or an XML parser if you happen to know it's valid XML (probably almost never true). You will absolutely screw up and waste tons of time trying to get it right. Just use what's already available.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HAVE A DIFF ALGORITHM FOR RENDER HTML
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There's another nice trick you can use to significantly improve the look of a rendered HTML diff.  Although this doesn't fully solve the initial problem, it will make a significant difference in the appearance of your rendered HTML diffs.</p><br/><br/><p>Side-by-side rendered HTML will make it very difficult for your diff to line up vertically.  Vertical alignment is crucial for comparing side-by-side diffs.  In order to improve the vertical alignment of a side-by-side diff, you can insert invisible HTML elements in each version of the diff at "checkpoints" where the diff should be vertically aligned.  Then you can use a bit of client-side javascript to add vertical spacing around checkpoint until the sides line up vertically.</p><br/><br/><p>Explained in a little more detail:</p><br/><br/><p>If you want to use this technique, run your diff algorithm and insert a bunch of visibility:hidden s or tiny s wherever your side-by-side versions should match up, according to the diff.  Then run javascript that finds each checkpoint (and its side-by-side neighbor) and adds vertical spacing to the checkpoint that is higher-up (shallower) on the page.  Now your rendered HTML diff will be vertically aligned up to that checkpoint, and you can continue repairing vertical alignment down the rest of your side-by-side page.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      EXPORT HTML TO WORD WITHOUT HAVE MS WORD INSTAL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>If you have only simple HTML pages as you said, it can be opened with Word.</p><br/><br/><p>Otherwise there are some libraries which can do this, but I don't have experience with them.</p><br/><br/><p>My last idea is that if you are using ASP.NET, try to add <code>application/msword</code> to the header and you can save it as a Word document (it won't be a real Word doc, only an HTML renamed to doc to be able to open).</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HEIGHT OF A DIV DYNAM
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try this simple, specific function:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function resizeElementHeight(element) {<br/>  var height = 0;<br/>  var body = window.document.body;<br/>  if (window.innerHeight) {<br/>      height = window.innerHeight;<br/>  } else if (body.parentElement.clientHeight) {<br/>      height = body.parentElement.clientHeight;<br/>  } else if (body &amp;&amp; body.clientHeight) {<br/>      height = body.clientHeight;<br/>  }<br/>  element.style.height = ((height - element.offsetTop) + "px");<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>It does not depend on the current distance from the top of the body being specified (in case your 300px changes).</p><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>EDIT: By the way, you would want to call this on that div every time the user changed the browser's size, so you would need to wire up the event handler for that, of course.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      UNUS IMAG AND CSS STYLE IN A WEBSIT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>There's a Firefox extension that finds unused CSS selectors on a page. It has an option to spider the whole site.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/dust-me-selectors/" rel="nofollow">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/dust-me-selectors/</a></p><br/><br/><p>Use this for the newest version on FF:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/css-usage/" rel="nofollow">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/css-usage/</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A FLASH OBJECT AS A LINK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Though the object really should respond to being wrapped in an a href tag, you could open the swf in vim and just throw in an <code>_root.onPress=function(){getURL("http://yes.no/");};</code> or if it's AS3, something like <code>_root.addEventHandler(MouseEvent.PRESS, function (e:event) {getURL("http://yes.no/");});</code> But if editing the swf is your route, you'd likely have more success with <a href="http://www.buraks.com/uae/1.html" rel="nofollow">a tool for the purpose</a>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AN HTML TAG SPLIT ACROSS MULTIPL LINE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Perhaps for future projects I'll use a parsing library, but that's kind of aside from the question at hand. This is my current solution. <code>rstrpos</code> is strpos, but from the reverse direction. Example use:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>for($i=0; $i&lt;count($lines); $i++)<br/>{<br/>    $line = handle_mulitline_tags(&amp;$i, $line, $lines);<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>And here's that implementation:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function rstrpos($string, $charToFind, $relativePos)<br/>{<br/>    $searchPos = $relativePos;<br/>    $searchChar = '';<br/><br/>    while (($searchChar != $charToFind)&amp;&amp;($searchPos&gt;-1))<br/>    {<br/>        $newPos = $searchPos-1;<br/>        $searchChar = substr($string,$newPos,strlen($charToFind));<br/>        $searchPos = $newPos;<br/>    }<br/><br/>    if (!empty($searchChar))<br/>    {<br/>        return $searchPos;<br/>        return TRUE;<br/>    }<br/>    else<br/>    {<br/>        return FALSE;<br/>    }<br/>}<br/><br/>function handle_multiline_tags(&amp;$i, $line, $lines)<br/>{<br/>    //if a tag is opened but not closed before a line break,<br/><br/>    $open = rstrpos($line, '&lt;', strlen($line));<br/>    $close = rstrpos($line, '&gt;', strlen($line));<br/>    if(($open &gt; $close)&amp;&amp;($open &gt; -1)&amp;&amp;($close &gt; -1))<br/>    {<br/>    	$i++;<br/>    	return trim($line).trim(handle_multiline_tags(&amp;$i, $lines[$i], $lines));<br/>    }<br/>    else<br/>    {<br/>    	return trim($line);<br/>    }<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This could probably be optimized in some way, but for my purposes, it's sufficient.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SCRAPE IN PHP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I would recomend <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/simplehtmldom/" rel="nofollow">PHP Simple HTML DOM Parser</a> after you have scraped the HTML from the page. It supports invalid HTML, and provides a very easy way to handle HTML elements. </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ADD EVENT IN JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>In my experience, there are two major points to this:</p><br/><br/><p>1) The most important thing is to be consistent. I don't think either of the two methods is necessarily easier to read, as long as you stick to it. I only get confused when both methods are used in a project (or even worse on the same page) because then I have to start searching for the calls and don't immediately know where to look.</p><br/><br/><p>2) The second kind, i.e. Event.observe() has advantages when the same or a very similar action is taken on multiple events because this becomes obvious when all those calls are in the same place. Also, as Konrad pointed out, in some cases this can be handled with a single call.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      UNORD LIST INLIN BUT KEEP THE BULLET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The best option I saw in other answers was to use <code>float:left;</code>.  Unfortunately, it doesn't work in IE7 which is a requirement here &mdash; you still lose the bullet.  I'm not really keen on using a background image either.</p><br/><br/><p>What I'm gonna do instead (that no one else suggested, hence the self-answer) is go with manually adding <code>&amp;bull;</code> to the my html, rather than styling this.  It's less than ideal, but it's the most compatible option I found.  </p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SWAP DIV ON MOUSEOV ( JQUERI )
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<pre><code>$(document).ready(function() {<br/>    switches = $('#switches &gt; li');<br/>    slides = $('#slides &gt; div');<br/>    switches.each(function(idx) {<br/>            $(this).data('slide', slides.eq(idx));<br/>        }).hover(<br/>        function() {<br/>            switches.removeClass('active');<br/>            slides.removeClass('active');             <br/>            $(this).addClass('active');  <br/>            $(this).data('slide').addClass('active');<br/>        });<br/>    });<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Rather than displaying all slides when JS is off (which would likely break the page layout) I would place inside the switch LIs real A links to server-side code which returns the page with the "active" class pre-set on the proper switch/slide.</p><br/><br/><p>And here's the HTML:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;html&gt;<br/>&lt;head&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;title&gt;test&lt;/title&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="jquery.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;<br/>&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="switch.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;<br/><br/>#switches .active {<br/>  font-weight: bold;<br/>}<br/><br/>#slides div {<br/>  display: none;<br/>}<br/><br/>#slides div.active {<br/>  display: block;<br/>}<br/><br/>&lt;/style&gt;<br/>&lt;/head&gt;<br/>&lt;body&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;ul id="switches"&gt;<br/>  &lt;li class="active"&gt;First slide&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Second slide&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Third slide&lt;/li&gt;<br/>  &lt;li&gt;Fourth slide&lt;/li&gt;<br/>&lt;/ul&gt;<br/>&lt;div id="slides"&gt;<br/>  &lt;div class="active"&gt;Well well.&lt;/div&gt;<br/>  &lt;div&gt;Oh no!&lt;/div&gt;<br/>  &lt;div&gt;You again?&lt;/div&gt;<br/>  &lt;div&gt;I'm gone!&lt;/div&gt;<br/>&lt;/div&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;/body&gt;<br/>&lt;/html&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      E BLOCK ON SPAN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<pre><code>float: left;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Try adding that to span.left</p><br/><br/><p>It will cause it to float to the left (as suggested by the syntax).</p><br/><br/><hr><br/><br/><p>I am not a CSS expert by any means so please don't take this as unarguable fact but I find that when something is floated, it makes no difference to the vertical position of things below it.</p><br/><br/><p>If you float the span.right to the right then add text beneath them you should get some interesting results, to stop these "interesting results" you can use "clear: left/right/both" which will cause the block with the clear styling to be under anything floated to the left/right/both. <a href="http://w3schools.com/css/pr_class_clear.asp" rel="nofollow">W3Schools</a> have a page on this property too.</p><br/><br/><p>And welcome to Stackoverflow.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      N IFRAM TAKE VERTIC SPACE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This should set the IFRAME height to its content's height:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/>the_height = document.getElementById('the_iframe').contentWindow.document.body.scrollHeight;<br/>document.getElementById('the_iframe').height = the_height;<br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>You may want to add <code>scrolling="no"</code> to your IFRAME to turn off the scrollbars.</p><br/><br/><p><em>edit:</em> Oops, forgot to declare <code>the_height</code>.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      COMPLEX FILENAM INTO HTML LINK
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can use <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/function.rawurlencode.php" rel="nofollow">rawurlencode()</a> to convert a string according to the RFC 1738 spec.<br/>This function replaces all non-alphanumeric characters by their associated code.</p><br/><br/><p>The difference with <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/function.urlencode.php" rel="nofollow">urlencode()</a> is that spaces are encoded as plus signs.</p><br/><br/><p>You'll probably want to use the last one.</p><br/><br/><p>This technique is called Percent or URL encoding. See <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Url_encoding" rel="nofollow">Wikipedia</a> for more details.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ( X ) HTML IN PYTHON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>XHTML is easy, use <a href="http://codespeak.net/lxml/validation.html" rel="nofollow">lxml</a>.</p><br/><br/><p>HTML is harder, since there's traditionally not been as much interest in validation among the HTML crowd (run StackOverflow itself through a validator, yikes). The easiest solution would be to execute external applications such as <a href="http://www.jclark.com/sp/" rel="nofollow">nsgmls</a> or <a href="http://openjade.sourceforge.net/" rel="nofollow">OpenJade</a>, and then parse their output.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      ONLIN RESOURC FOR CSS DESIGN PATTERN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I refer to <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/" rel="nofollow">A List Apart</a> articles all the time for those sorts of things. They do a lot of trial-and-error research to come up with really creative ways to handle those common CSS problems in the cleanest most portable way possible.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      A TWO COLUMN PAGE HOW CAN I GROW THE LEFT DIV TO THE SAME HEIGHT OF THE RIGHT DIV USE CSS OR JAVASCRIPT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Use jQuery for this problem; just call this function in your ready function:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function setHeight(){<br/>  var height = $(document).height(); //optionally, subtract some from the height<br/>  $("#leftDiv").css("height", height + "px");<br/>}<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NAME OF A WINDOW IN ROR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You have to use JavaScript for this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/>  window.name = "MyWindow";<br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Of course you could easily package this up into a Rails helper method. For example, in <code>app/helpers/application_helper.rb</code> add a new method:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>def window_name(name)<br/>  content_for(:window_name) do<br/>    "&lt;script type=\"text/javascript\"&gt;window.name = \"#{name}\";&lt;/script&gt;"<br/>  end<br/>end<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Next, in your layout file, add this line somewhere within the HTML <code>&lt;head&gt;</code> element:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;%= yield :window_name %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Finally, in your view templates, simply add a line like this (can be anywhere you want) to output the correct JavaScript:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;% window_name 'MyWindow' %&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      PREVIEW THEME IN WORDPRESS
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>It's open source - use the source, Luke.</p><br/><br/><p>Look in wp-admin/js/theme-preview.js</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LEGEND IN GOOGL MAP MASHUP
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can add your own Custom Control and use it as a legend.</p><br/><br/><p>This code will add a box 150w x 100h (Gray Border/ with White Background) and the words "Hello World" inside of it. You swap out the text for any HTML you would like in the legend. This will stay Anchored to the Top Right (G_ANCHOR_TOP_RIGHT) 10px down and 50px over of the map.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>function MyPane() {}<br/>MyPane.prototype = new GControl;<br/>MyPane.prototype.initialize = function(map) {<br/>  var me = this;<br/>  me.panel = document.createElement("div");<br/>  me.panel.style.width = "150px";<br/>  me.panel.style.height = "100px";<br/>  me.panel.style.border = "1px solid gray";<br/>  me.panel.style.background = "white";<br/>  me.panel.innerHTML = "Hello World!";<br/>  map.getContainer().appendChild(me.panel);<br/>  return me.panel;<br/>};<br/><br/>MyPane.prototype.getDefaultPosition = function() {<br/>  return new GControlPosition(<br/>      G_ANCHOR_TOP_RIGHT, new GSize(10, 50));<br/>      //Should be _ and not &amp;#95;<br/>};<br/><br/>MyPane.prototype.getPanel = function() {<br/>  return me.panel;<br/>}<br/>map.addControl(new MyPane());<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      KEEP WHITESPAC FORMAT USE PHP HTML
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>use the &lt;pre&gt; tag (pre formatted), that will use a mono spaced font (for your art) and keep all the white space</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;pre&gt;<br/>text goes here and here <br/>             and here and here            Some out here<br/>                          <br/>        <br/>                <br/>               <br/>              <br/>                               <br/><br/>&lt;/pre&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>You might have to convert any &lt;'s to &amp;lt; 's</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CURRENT THE BEST WAY TO GET A FAVICON TO DISPLAY IN ALL BROWSER THAT SUPPORT FAVICON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I go for a belt and braces appraoch here. I create a 32x32 icon in both the <code>.ico</code> and <code>.png</code> formats called <code>favicon.ico</code> and <code>favicon.png</code>. The name doesn't really matter unless you are dealing with older browsers.</p><br/><br/><ol><br/><li>Place <code>favicon.ico</code> at your site root to support the older browsers (optional and only relevant for older browsers.</li><br/><li>Place favicon.png in my images sub-directory (just to keep things tidy).</li><br/><li>Add the following HTML to the <code>&lt;head/&gt;<code> element.</li><br/></ol><br/><br/><pre>&lt;link rel="icon" href="/images/favicon.png" type="image/png" /&gt;<br/>&lt;link rel="shortcut icon" href="/favicon.ico" /&gt;</code></pre><br/><br/><p>Please note that:</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>The MIME type for .ico files was registered as image/vnd.microsoft.icon by the <a href="http://www.iana.org" rel="nofollow">IANA</a>. </li><br/><li>IE will ignore the type</code> attribute for the shortcut icon relationship and since IE is the only browser to support this relationship you need not supply it.</li><br/></ul><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      N HTML PAGE PRINT IN LANDSCAP WHEN THE USER SELECT PRINT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>A quick Google indicates that it's not really supported. There's more than a few folks out there trying to <a href="http://www.daniweb.com/forums/showthread.php?t=14877&amp;page=2&amp;highlight=javascript+print+landscape" rel="nofollow">hack</a> <a href="http://home.tampabay.rr.com/bmerkey/examples/landscape-test.html" rel="nofollow">their</a> way to it - but I'd strongly suggest just rendering a server side PDF instead.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OUT HTML TAG AND RESOLV ENTITI IN PYTHON
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Use <a href="http://codespeak.net/lxml/lxmlhtml.html" rel="nofollow">lxml</a> which is the best xml/html library for python.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>import lxml.html<br/>t = lxml.html.fromstring("...")<br/>t.text_content()<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>And if you just want to sanitize the html look at the lxml.html.clean <a href="http://codespeak.net/lxml/lxmlhtml.html#cleaning-up-html" rel="nofollow">module</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SAMBA SHARE IN HTML
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Hmm, protocol handlers look interesting.</p><br/><br/><p>As <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/37804/link-to-samba-shares-in-html#38258" rel="nofollow">Mark</a> said, in Windows protocol handlers can be dealt with at the OS level</p><br/><br/><p>Protocol handlers can also be done at the browser level (which is preferred, as it is cross platform and doesn't involve installing anything).</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://kb.mozillazine.org/Register_protocol" rel="nofollow">Summary of how it works in Firefox</a><br /><br/><a href="http://www.opera.com/support/search/view/535/" rel="nofollow">Summary of how it works in Opera</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      GRAB THE CONTENT OF HTML TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Well, sysrqb will let you match anything in the first paragraph assuming there's no other html in the paragraph. You might want something more like this</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;p&gt;.*?&lt;/p&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Placing the ? after your * makes it non-greedy, meaning it will only match as little text as necessary before matching the &lt;/p&gt;</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      STOP .NET EAT ID
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The short answer is no, with webforms the id can always be rewritten depending on the nesting of the element.  You can get access to the id through the ClientID property, so you could set the ids into variables in a script at the end of the page/control then put them into jQuery.  </p><br/><br/><p>something like this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;asp:button id="ImAButton" runat="server"&gt;Click Me&lt;/asp:button&gt;<br/><br/>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;<br/>var buttonId = "&lt;%=ImAButton.ClientId%&gt;";<br/>$("#"+buttonId).bind('click', function() { alert('hi); });<br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>It's a hack I know, but it will work.<br/>(I should note for the un-initiated, I'm using the Prototype $ get by id method there)</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML WYSIWYG TOOL DO YOU RECOMMEND
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>None.</p><br/><br/><p>Real men handcode HTML, even the best WYSIWYG tool is lousy at generating HTML.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      CAN NOT JQUERI MY PAGE UNDER INTERNET EXPLOR
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Try upgrading to jQuery 1.2.6, you should be on the latest release of jQuery if you are having problems first ensure you are on the latest and greatest.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AJAX PHP CONTACT FORM WITH VALID
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.dustindiaz.com/ajax-contact-form/" rel="nofollow">This one</a> is a few years old, but should work fine.</p><br/><br/><p>Personally, I'd recommend taking a look at the jQuery <a href="http://plugins.jquery.com/project/form" rel="nofollow">Form Plug-in</a>. It's not plug and play, but it's well tested and easy to build on top of.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      TABLESORT PLUGIN
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>This is a common layout problem in IE.  If you are using CSS to style the columns width, also add the column widths to the td tags.  Set the first column to a percentage that will try to suck up most of the space, like 50% or something.  The first column width will take everything that it can and the other columns will abide by their static width.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      JAPPLET HOW DO YOU EMB IT IN A WEBPAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Here is an example from <a href="http://java.sun.com/docs/books/tutorial/uiswing/components/applet.html" rel="nofollow">sun's website</a>:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;applet code="TumbleItem.class" <br/>        codebase="examples/"<br/>        archive="tumbleClasses.jar, tumbleImages.jar"<br/>        width="600" height="95"&gt;<br/>    &lt;param name="maxwidth" value="120"&gt;<br/>    &lt;param name="nimgs" value="17"&gt;<br/>    &lt;param name="offset" value="-57"&gt;<br/>    &lt;param name="img" value="images/tumble"&gt;<br/><br/>Your browser is completely ignoring the &amp;lt;APPLET&amp;gt; tag!<br/>&lt;/applet&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      AND INSID PRE TAG
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<pre><code>&lt;pre&gt;<br/>    PrimeCalc calc = new PrimeCalc();<br/>    Func&amp;lt;int, int&amp;gt; del = calc.GetNextPrime;<br/>&lt;/pre&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      THE FOOTER TO STAY AT THE BOTTOM OF A WEB PAGE
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Sticky footer on <a href="http://ryanfait.com/sticky-footer/" rel="nofollow">google</a></p><br/><br/><p>Have a <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> with <code>class="wrapper"</code> contain everything. After the <code>wrapper &lt;/div&gt;</code> place the <code>push div</code>, then the <code>footer div</code>.</p><br/><br/><pre><code>* {<br/>    margin: 0;<br/>  }<br/>  html, body {<br/>    height: 100%;<br/>  }<br/>  .wrapper {<br/>    min-height: 100%;<br/>    height: auto !important;<br/>    height: 100%;<br/>    margin: 0 auto -142px; /* the bottom margin is the negative value of the footer's height */<br/>  }<br/>  .footer, .push {<br/>    height: 142px; /* .push must be the same height as .footer */<br/>  }<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      REND UL S INCORRECTLI
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>try giving it hasLayout with</p><br/><br/><pre><code>zoom: 1<br/></code></pre><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      MAX NUMBER OF OPTION ( VALU ) IN HTML DROP DOWN CONTROL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<blockquote><br/>  <p>Does anyone know how many options a drop down list can have? Is it unlimited? </p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>I imagine it is unlimited in theory, obviously not in practice as a computer's RAM and the specific browser's limitations come into play.</p><br/><br/><blockquote><br/>  <p>How many before performance degrades?</p><br/></blockquote><br/><br/><p>Again, this would depend on a few factors, at the least the specific browser, the computer's memory and processing power.</p><br/><br/><p><hr /></p><br/><br/><p>EDIT: From experience, I have had drop down lists with thousands of options. It wasn't ideal though because who wants to scroll through all of those? This is why an auto-complete of some type is more desirable for numerous reasons, especially the end user's experience.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      QUOT VS DIV
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>In theory, HTML should be as "semantic" as possible - meaning that every element should indicate something about its content. &lt;h1&gt;s should enclose the most important headline; &lt;p&gt;s should surround paragraphs; &lt;em&gt; should indicate emphasis, etc.</p><br/><br/><p>That way the code makes sense when you - or a screen reader, or whatever - look at it. This also helps for devices that don't understand all (or any) of your CSS rules.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      HTML LAYOUT WITH MULTIPL CSS STYLE AVAIL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I've used <a href="http://www.blueprintcss.org/" rel="nofollow">Bluprint CSS</a>, it's easy and useful as you'll see. It also has some ruby scripts that allow you to change the number of columns and the distance between them. By default it's 950px for a span-24 element.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      NOT DISPLAY IN WEBKIT BASE BROWSER
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>Imagemagick reports that this particular image is saved in CMYK colorspace instead of the more standard RGB. Try converting it, it should be more compatible with the webkit rendering engine.</p><br/><br/><p>Imagemagick is available for download from <a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php" rel="nofollow">http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php</a> - it's available for windows and *NIX systems.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      LENGTH FOR HTML TEXT AREA
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The TEXTAREA tag does not have a MAXLENGTH attribute the way that an<br/>INPUT tag does, at least not in most standard browsers. A very simple and<br/>effective way to limit the number of characters that can be <em>typed</em> into a<br/>TEXTAREA tag is:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;textarea onKeyPress="return ( this.value.length &lt; 50 );"&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>This works because the boolean expression compares the field's length<br/>before the new character is added to the maximum length you want (50 in this<br/>example, use your own here), and returns true if there is room for one more,<br/>false if not. Returning false from most events cancels the default action.<br/>So if the current length is already 50 (or more), the handler returns false,<br/>the KeyPress action is cancelled, and the character is not added.</p><br/><br/><p>One fly in the ointment is the possibility of pasting into a TEXTAREA,<br/>which does not cause the KeyPress event to fire, circumventing this check.<br/>Internet Explorer 5+ contains an onPaste event whose handler can contain the<br/>check. However, note that you must also take into account how many<br/>characters are waiting in the clipboard to know if the total is going to<br/>take you over the limit or not. Fortunately, IE also contains a clipboard<br/>object from the window object.<a href="http://lists.evolt.org/archive/Week-of-Mon-20040315/156773.html" rel="nofollow">1</a> Thus:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;textarea onKeyPress="return ( this.value.length &lt; 50 );"<br/>onPaste="return (( this.value.length +<br/>window.clipboardData.getData('Text').length) &lt; 50 );"&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Again, the onPaste event and clipboardData object are IE 5+ only. For a<br/>cross-browser solution, you will just have to use an OnChange or OnBlur<br/>handler to check the length, and handle it however you want (truncate the<br/>value silently, notify the user, etc.). Unfortunately, this doesn't catch<br/>the error as it's happening, only when the user attempts to leave the field,<br/>which is not quite as friendly.</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://lists.evolt.org/archive/Week-of-Mon-20040315/156773.html" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p><br/><br/><p>Also, there is another way here, including a finished script you could include in your page:</p><br/><br/><p><a href="http://cf-bill.blogspot.com/2005/05/textarea-maxlength-revisited.html" rel="nofollow">http://cf-bill.blogspot.com/2005/05/textarea-maxlength-revisited.html</a></p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      STYLE ( CSS ) RADIO BUTTON AND LABEL
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>The first part of your question can be solved with just HTML &amp; CSS; you'll need to use Javascript for the second part.</p><br/><br/><h3>Getting the Label Near the Radio Button</h3><br/><br/><p>I'm not sure what you mean by "next to": on the same line and near, or on separate lines? If you want all of the radio buttons on the same line, just use margins to push them apart. If you want each of them on their own line, you have two options (unless you want to venture into <code>float:</code> territory):</p><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Use <code>&lt;br /&gt;s </code> to split the options apart and some CSS to vertically align them:</li><br/></ul><br/><br/><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;style type='text/css'&gt;<br/>    .input input<br/>    {<br/>        width: 20px;<br/>    }<br/>&lt;/style&gt;<br/>&lt;div class="input radio"&gt;<br/>    &lt;fieldset&gt;<br/>        &lt;legend&gt;What color is the sky?&lt;/legend&gt;<br/>        &lt;input type="hidden" name="data[Submit][question]" value="" id="SubmitQuestion" /&gt;<br/><br/>        &lt;input type="radio" name="data[Submit][question]" id="SubmitQuestion1" value="1"  /&gt;<br/>        &lt;label for="SubmitQuestion1"&gt;A strange radient green.&lt;/label&gt;<br/>        &lt;br /&gt;<br/>        &lt;input type="radio" name="data[Submit][question]" id="SubmitQuestion2" value="2"  /&gt;<br/>        &lt;label for="SubmitQuestion2"&gt;A dark gloomy orange&lt;/label&gt;<br/>        &lt;br /&gt;<br/>        &lt;input type="radio" name="data[Submit][question]" id="SubmitQuestion3" value="3"  /&gt;<br/>        &lt;label for="SubmitQuestion3"&gt;A perfect glittering blue&lt;/label&gt;<br/>    &lt;/fieldset&gt;<br/>&lt;/div&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><ul><br/><li>Follow <em>A List Apart</em>'s article: <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/prettyaccessibleforms" rel="nofollow">Prettier Accessible Forms</a></li><br/></ul><br/><br/><h3>Applying a Style to the Currently Selected Label + Radio Button</h3><br/><br/><p>Styling the <code>&lt;label&gt;</code> is why you'll need to resort to Javascript. A library like <a href="http://jquery.com" rel="nofollow">jQuery</a><br/>is perfect for this:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;style type='text/css'&gt;<br/>    .input label.focused<br/>    {<br/>        background-color: #EEEEEE;<br/>        font-style: italic;<br/>    }<br/>&lt;/style&gt;<br/>&lt;script type='text/javascript' src='jquery.js'&gt;&lt;/script&gt;<br/>&lt;script type='text/javascript'&gt;<br/>    $(document).ready(function() {<br/>        $('.input :radio').focus(updateSelectedStyle);<br/>        $('.input :radio').blur(updateSelectedStyle);<br/>        $('.input :radio').change(updateSelectedStyle);<br/>    })<br/><br/>    function updateSelectedStyle() {<br/>        $('.input :radio').removeClass('focused').next().removeClass('focused');<br/>        $('.input :radio:checked').addClass('focused').next().addClass('focused');<br/>    }<br/>&lt;/script&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>The <code>focus</code> and <code>blur</code> hooks are needed to make this work in IE.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      BEST POPUL AN HTML TABL IN ASP.NET
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>@<a href="#43818" rel="nofollow">Geoff</a></p><br/><br/><p>That sort of Eval statement was actually added in 2.0, but if performance is important Eval should be avoided since it uses Reflection.</p><br/><br/><p>The repeater is a pretty good way of doing it, although it might be faster to generate the table in code:</p><br/><br/><p>ASPX Page:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;table class="report" id="bookTable" runat="server"&gt;<br/>        &lt;tr&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Published&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Author&lt;/th&gt;<br/>            &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;<br/>        &lt;/tr&gt;<br/> &lt;/table&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>Code Behind:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>Protected Sub Page_Load( ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e As System.EventArgs) Handles Me.Load<br/>    If Not Page.IsPostback Then<br/>        BuildTable()<br/>    End If<br/>End Sub<br/><br/>Private Sub BuildTable()<br/>    Dim db As New BookstoreDataContext<br/>    Dim bookCollection = from b in db.Books _<br/>                         Order By b.Published _<br/>                         Select b<br/>    Dim row As HtmlTableRow<br/>    Dim cell As HtmlTableCell<br/><br/>    For Each book As Books In bookCollection<br/>        row = New HtmlTableRow()<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = b.Published.ToShortDateString }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = TryNbsp(HttpContext.Current.Server.HtmlEncode(b.Title)) }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = TryNbsp(HttpContext.Current.Server.HtmlEncode(b.Author))<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        cell = New HtmlTableCell With { .InnerText = Format(b.Price, "c") }<br/>        row.Controls.Add(cell)<br/>        bookTable.Controls.Add(row)<br/>    Next<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>I guess it depends on how important speed is to you. For simplicity's sake I think I would go with the Repeater.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      SELECT OF SELECT OPTION WITHOUT DISABL THE FIELD
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>I know you mentioned that you don't want to, but I actually think that using the <code>disabled</code> attribute is a better solution:</p><br/><br/><pre><code>&lt;select multiple="multiple"&gt;<br/>    &lt;option value="volvo" selected="true" disabled="disabled"&gt;Volvo&lt;/option&gt;<br/>    &lt;option value="saab" disabled="disabled"&gt;Saab&lt;/option&gt;<br/>    &lt;option value="opel" disabled="disabled"&gt;Opel&lt;/option&gt;<br/>    &lt;option value="audi" disabled="disabled"&gt;Audi&lt;/option&gt;<br/>&lt;/select&gt;<br/></code></pre><br/><br/><p>If necessary, you can always give the <code>select</code> a <code>class</code> and style it with CSS. This solution will work in all browsers regardless of scripting capabilities.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>
      OF AD IN REGULARLI USE BLOCK OF CODE WHEN MARK UP IN TEXTMAT
    </pattern>
    <template>
<![CDATA[<p>You can do this very easily in TextMate using <a href="http://manual.macromates.com/en/snippets" rel="nofollow">Snippets</a>. Just add a new snippet in the bundle editor, and set up how you want to trigger it. You can set a key shortcut, or have it pop up when you hit <code>Tab</code> after a certain word/pattern.</p><br/><br/><p>There are many things you can do with them&mdash;in your case, it would probably be very useful to set so-called "placeholders" in your snippets, which are the parts that change every time (e.g. the names of the fields in the form). Then, as soon as you insert the snippet, you can hit <code>Tab</code> to move between these.</p><br/>]]>    </template>
  </category>
</aiml>
